In this video
we're gonna cover inversion of control.
So, inversion of control's the buzzword that you always hear
when you hear of the Spring framework.
So, what exactly is inversion of control?
Well, it's simply the design process
of externalizing, the construction and management
of your objects.
So, in a nutshell it basically says
that your application's gonna outsource the creation
and management of the objects,
and that outsourcing will be handled by a object factory,
and that's the big idea of inversion of control.
Now, to kind of help you out with getting a idea
of inversion of control,
I'll actually walk through some coding examples
and I will kind of start from scratch
with a very rough prototype
and we'll try and refine it
and refactor it over time
just so you can kinda see the real motivation
for inversion of control
and you know, why we need the Spring framework.
Alright, so let's go ahead and start
with this little coding scenario.
So, real simple example.
We're gonna have our app
that will make use of a coach like a baseball coach
and so our app will say hey, baseball coach,
give me a daily workout,
just so you find out what type of workout
you need to perform at practice.
So, that's the big idea of this application.
Now, one thing though is that the management teams says
oh yeah, by the way,
the app should be configurable,
so this app should easily work for a coach
in another sport,
so you should easily be able to plug in
a hockey coach, cricket coach, tennis, gymnastics, so on.
So, they want it to be configurable
and also work with any type of coach.
So, now you're like oh,
I thought the project was easy,
now it got a little bit difficult but don't worry,
we'll kind of walk through this
and we'll look at some possible solutions for this
and we'll kinda build out a little rough prototype.
So, this rough prototype will have four key players.
I'll first set off with MyApp.java.
It's simply the main program and it has a main method.
We'll use BaseballCoach.java.
It will be a simple implementation.
Then kind of in the version two,
once we kind of refactor it,
we'll introduce an interface called coach.java,
and then we'll also show another implementation
called TrackCoach.java.
Just the whole idea of switching in
a different coach and seeing if our application
continues to work.
So, those are the main players,
that's the big idea.
Let's go ahead and move into the next video
and let's get our hands dirty
and let's start writing some code.