Alright, let's dive into Eclipse
and let's write some code.
So what I wanna do is continue to use that
existing project that we created
in some of the previous videos.
And I'll start off by first creating a package.
So I'll just right click on the source directory.
I'll say new package.
And the name I'll give for the package here,
I'll call it com.luv2code.springdemo.
'Cause we love to code.
And once you're happy with that,
we'll go ahead and hit the finish button.
Alright so we have this basic package.
Now the first thing I wanna do is create the
baseball coach.
So it's a simple pojo, or plain old java object,
so I'll do a right click, I'll say new, class.
For the name, I'll call it BaseballCoach.
And I'll keep all the other defaults here.
And I'll hit the finish button.
Alright so here we go.
Our very basic class called BaseballCoach.
Let me go ahead and
zoom for a bit.
And I really wanna create just one method here.
This one method will be called getDailyWorkout.
And it's gonna return a string.
So here I'll say,
I dunno, makin' somethin' up here.
I'll spend 30 minutes in the batting cage.
Or spend 30 minutes on batting practice.
That's close enough.
So again, just a very simple implementation here
of this BaseballCoach for that method,
getDailyWorkout.
And then kinda just stepping back,
remember, we're building this little app
that's gonna talk to the baseball coach
and get daily workout
so we can kinda check the box there.
This baseball coach class is complete.
Alright, so let's move back over here
and let's go ahead and create another class here.
Let's go ahead and create the MyApp class.
So I just do a right click, and I say new, class.
The actual name I'll give for it is MyApp.
And then one thing I'll do here at the bottom
is that I'll check the box here to give us a main method.
This will be the main program for our application.
And then I'll hit finish.
Alright so here's our MyApp class,
has a main method.
Now I'll just go ahead and write some comments
as far as the type of work I wanna do.
So I say create the object
and then use the object.
Very simple, nothing fancy here.
So again, just putting in the little diagram,
so our app's gonna talk to the BaseballCoach.
So that means I need to create the Coach object.
So I need to say theCoach equals new BaseballCoach.
So at this point I have the object created
and that's theCoach that we created in a previous file.
Now I'll actually use it.
And I'll just do a print line here.
I'll make use of one of my sys out tricks.
I'll says sys out,
control space,
and that'll actually give me this system out print line.
Just a little Eclipse trick for you there.
And I'll say System out print line theCoach dot
getDailyWorkout,
'cause I wanna get the actual daily workout
that I need for practice.
And this kinda maps up with what we have here
with that little diagram.
So this looks good.
So we have theBaseballCoach taken care of.
And then we also have MyApp taken care of.
So then let's go ahead and run this application.
And we get the output,
Spend 30 minutes on batting practice.
And again, there's no rocket science here.
This is kinda Java 101.
We're creating objects and we're simply
calling methods on it.
So, hopefully you're okay with it so far.
Alrighty, so let's go ahead and get that idea
of the one requirement here that the app should work
with any type of coach.
So what we wanna do is make use of a software
engineering best practice
and that's to code to an interface.
So instead of coding directly to theBaseballCoach
implementation, we wanna make use of a well
defined interface that all coaches will support.
So, every coach is gonna have a method called
getDailyWorkout.
So let's go ahead and create this interface.
So we're kind of doing some code refactoring here.
I'll say right click, I'll say new,
and then I'll choose interface.
And the actual name of the interface I'll create,
I'll call it Coach.
And just a very simple interface
and I'll keep all the other defaults here
and I'll hit finish.
Alright, so, now we have this interface,
let's go ahead and add this one method,
getDailyWorkout and just a semicolon.
Now note here,
or recall,
an interface doesn't have any implementation code,
it's only a specification.
So they simply say, what is available
but not how it's implemented.
So the what portion of it is
a method called getDailyWorkout.
And then you'll have different coaches that'll implement
this method depending on the type of coach that they are.
Alright, so now let's go back to our BaseballCoach,
we need to do some refactoring here.
So, in our BaseballCoach we need to say
that our BaseballCoach implements Coach.
So that's that interface we just created.
And also add overrides,
meaning that this is the method that we override
from that coach interface.
So we're basically here just saying that our
BaseballCoach is compliant by implementing
a given Coach interface.
So I can access the BaseballCoach specifically,
or we can access it in a generic fashion
using the coach interface.
Alright, so let's make this small modification
here to MyApps.
So, I'm gonna change the variable on the left hand side,
so instead of BaseballCoach, the impletmentation,
I'm gonna say Coach, which is the interface.
Alright, so at this point,
we have theCoach which is just a generic interface
that has a method called getDailyWorkout.
So at this point
line eleven can work with any Coach implementation
that has the getDailyWorkout method.
Alright, so let's go ahead and run this application.
And wow!
Nothing really different here, right?
This is the same thing we saw before.
But again, the code's gonna run exactly the same,
however we've refactored the code
and we've refined it to make it a little bit better
to follow good software engineering practices.
And what we're gonna do in the next video,
is we're actually gonna add some more
implementations to follow that one requirement
that we had to make our app handle different
types of coaches or different type of coach
implementations.
And we'll cover that in the next video.
So, hang tight and I'll see you in the next video.