All right, so we have our app working
with the BaseballCoach.
Now, let's go ahead and add that new requirement
of working with a different type of coach.
So in my MainApp.java program,
I'm gonna change it on the right-hand side,
so instead of new BaseballCoach,
I'm gonna say new TrackCoach.
So, TrackCoach.
But now, we don't have a TrackCoach class yet,
that's why we have the little red, squiggly underneath that.
And also, if we move over to the left-hand side
and we click on this little red x,
then Eclipse will give us some suggestions
and, hmm, interesting.
It can actually create the class TrackCoach for me.
Mm, I like it.
That's pretty cool.
Let's try it, so let's go and select this option,
Create class TrackCoach,
and then, wow, this is great.
So it has a name of TrackCoach
and also, hmm, they're even gonna implement
the interface for us, Coach,
that we have from the previous slide.
So this is looking pretty good here. (laughs)
So let's go ahead and click Finish,
and let's see what it does and
boo-yah,
Eclipse wrote some code for us.
This is awesome.
So they have the class TrackCoach,
implements Coach,
and they did the override for that one method,
getDailyWorkout.
Man, you gotta love that (laughs).
Thanks, Eclipse.
All right, so let's go ahead
and get rid of that auto-generated stub
and let's get rid of the null
and let's return our workout as a TrackCoach.
So we're gonna say, "Run a hard 5k."
All right, so our track coach,
they're gonna run us really hard,
get us into shape for the next track meet.
So there we go.
So we have the implementation for this setup,
so this is our new coach that we just created, TrackCoach,
implements Coach,
and we gave our custom implementation here
for getDailyWorkout.
So now, let me move back over to MyApp.java
and now this works out just fine.
We're in good shape.
So we have a new TrackCoach, that class has been created.
On the left-hand side, the assignments of theCoach interface
because that TrackCoach implements theCoach interface,
and will print it out.
So let's go ahead and run it.
So I'll just do a right-click, Run As, Java Application,
and then woo-hoo, "Run a hard 5k,"
so that's our TrackCoach giving us our daily workout.
This is pretty cool, I like it.
And then the nice thing about it
is that on line 11, we can handle any type of coach
because we, again, were coding to the interface,
not the implementation.
So, we're almost there
but again, this is a rough prototype.
It's not 100% yet.
And the reason it's not 100%
is that one of those requirements that we had,
one was that this should work with any type of coach
and we kind of handled that part of it
but the other requirement
was that the actual coach implementation
should be configurable
and that right now, it's not really configurable
because it's hardcoded right here.
Ideally, it will be great
if we could maybe read the actual implementation name
from a config file, and then make use of it,
so then we could easily swap
by only changing a config file
instead of having to change the source code.
So in the next video, we'll look at Spring
and Spring was designed to address this exact problem.