In this video,
we're gonna cover Spring Inversion of Control.
Now in the previous videos,
we were working on our application.
However, we didn't get it to 100%
because we didn't have the support for the configuration.
And so, we need to make use of an object factory
to help us out with this solution.
And as I mentioned earlier,
this is exactly when Spring comes into play.
So Spring provides an object factory
so we can have our application talk to Spring say,
"Hey, give me an object
"based on a configuration file or annotation,"
Spring will give you the appropriate implementation
so then your app is configurable
and will have full support for that
based on our application requirements.
So this looks pretty good.
All right, so now we're into some real Spring stuff.
So the Spring container,
the primary functions of the Spring container is one,
create and manage objects, that's your inversion of control,
and then two, inject object's dependencies
and that's what they call dependency of injection.
Now, we'll actually cover all of this in the course.
I'll start off with inversion of control
and then the following videos,
we'll actually get into dependency injection.
There's three ways of configuring the Spring container.
One is by using an XML configuration file,
the other is using Java annotations,
and then finally you can make use of Java source code
and we'll actually cover all of these approaches
or all of these techniques in this course.
So let's talk about the XML configuration file.
It's the original configuration file that was used
when Spring was first released so it's a legacy,
but we'll still cover it
because most legacy apps still use this.
So if you're joining a Spring team
or you're joining a company
that has existing Spring applications,
it's a very high likelihood
that their applications still use XML config files
so we'll start off with that.
Also Java annotations is the latest fad,
the latest fashion, making annotations,
and also you can actually get rid of all config files
and you can configure the container
by using Java source code.
But again, we're gonna cover all of these techniques
so you'll understand how each one of them works
for your application.
All right, so here's the Spring development process.
And as you know, I love to do lists.
I love step-by-step approaches.
So the first step is configuring your Spring Beans.
The second step is creating a Spring container.
And then the third step
is retrieving the Beans from the container.
And we'll actually cover all of the step by step.
You'll see how everything works
and we'll do all of this from scratch.
All right, so let's start with step one,
configuring your Spring Beans.
So in this example,
I'm gonna make use of the XML configuration file.
So here in the XML config file
called applicationContext.xml,
I have a bean, I give the actual bean id myCoach
and I'll give the class
and that's the fully qualified name of the Java class.
So the id, that's simply the id
that your Java application will use
when they wanna retrieve a bean from the Spring container.
And again, class is the actual class or implementation
that you'll have for your application.
Okay, so let's move to step two.
So step two is creating a Spring container.
So in the Spring world,
a Spring container is generally known
as an ApplicationContext
so that's the term that you'll see a lot
in Spring documentation and in Spring apps.
So they have specialized implementations of it,
one for reading XML from the class path,
an annotation config, a web application context, and so on
and we'll take a look at all of these in this course.
All righty, so creating the Spring container,
so in this example,
I'm gonna read an XML file that's on my class path.
So I make use of this ClassPathXmlApplicationContext
and I construct this object
and I pass in the actual name of the configuration file
that I'm using for Spring.
So from step one,
we had a file called applicationContext.xml.
You can use any name that you want
as long as you're consistent between step one and step two
as far as reading that configuration file.
All right, so we have this container created.
Now the next step is retrieving the beans from the container
so your application is simply gonna talk
to the Spring container and say,
"Hey, give me a coach object,"
and based on information in the configuration file,
it'll give you an implementation of that given interface.
So here's step three as far as code.
So the previous line we already created our context.
Now we retrieve the bean from the container so here I say
context.getBean and here I say myCoach, Coach.class.
So myCoach relates to the actual bean id
defined in the configuration file,
you have to make sure those match up
with the exact same case,
and then Coach.class,
that's the name of the actual interface
that BaseballCoach implements.
So here, Coach.class is the interface,
BaseballCoach is the actual implementation
and then you assign it
and that's basically what you have to do
for retrieving a bean from a Spring container.
All righty, so that's the coding here.
In the next video, we're actually move into Eclipse.
We'll get our hands dirty
and we'll actually write this code and we'll run it
and we'll actually see it in action so woo hoo.