Alright, so moving into Eclipse
we're gonna go ahead and write some code,
so we'll make use of the existing project that we've had,
spring-demo-one and this is the same project
that we had in our previous videos
as far as making use of our coach,
baseball coach and track coach,
so again, the same project there.
And what we wanna do is make use of some code
that we've downloaded for this course,
so in previous videos we gave you the links
on how to download the course files.
So, once you download it you'll get
this spring-hibernate-source-code.zip,
you can extract it and then you'll get this folder,
so again, look at the previous videos in the course
as far as how to download the actual course zip file
but anyways, once you have it,
you've unzipped it,
there's this spring-hibernate-source-code
and we'll look in this directory here
called spring-core
because what we wanna do is actually copy a starter file
that'll help us out with the XML configurations.
So, I just move down into spring-demo-one starter file
and there's a file there called applicationContext.xml.
It's just a basic starter file, basic shell
but let's go ahead and copy this file,
just do a right click and choose copy,
and let's move back over to Eclipse
and we wanna place this in our source directory, alright?
So, highlight that source directory,
do a right click and then choose paste
because what this will actually do
it'll paste the file
and actually put it on our application's class path,
so we can make use of our class path applicationContext.
So, there's our file.
Now if we just double click this file,
our first step is configuring our Spring beans, alright?
So, this file has a lot of header information here
for the XML namespaces and that's what's required
for Spring to be able to process this file
using it's grammar, and XML schema,
and now let's go ahead and define our bean.
So, we have this bean,
and now I need to sep up two attributes.
The first attribute I need to set is ID equals
and this is basically our alias of what the app will use.
I'll just call it myCoach
and then I give class.
Now I give the fully qualified class name
of our implementation,
so in this case I want the BaseballCoach,
so I know that BaseballCoach is in com.Luv2code.springdemo.
Oh and actually this is TrackCoach, sorry.
So, com.Luv2code.springdemo.TrackCoach
and that's our bean definition there.
So, that pretty much covers step one
as far as configuring our Spring beans.
Alright, so now let's go ahead
and take a look at one other item,
and now what I'm gonna do is actually make use
of a Java class, so I'm gonna create a new class
called SpringHelloApp.
So, I'll select my package here, I'll do a right click
and I'll say new class.
And the actual name of the class here,
I'll actually call it HelloSpringApp.
And also I'll check the box here at the bottom,
public static void main,
just so it'll give us a main method for our application
and then I'll just hit the finish button.
Okay, great, so again, just like before,
this gives us a very basic Java class.
Now what I'd like to do is, you know,
always like to put in comments for us
before I start writing code.
So, the first thing I wanna do here
is load the Spring configuration file.
And then actually wanna go ahead and retrieve a bean
from the Spring container.
Now that I have the bean, then I call methods on the bean,
or a method on the bean
and then finally just to be nice,
I'll close the actual application context.
So, that's my basic game plan here
for building our HelloSpringApp.
Alright, so let me stretch out here at the bottom,
give myself some white space,
and now let's go ahead and cover step two
of creating a Spring container.
So, again here we're gonna use
this ClassPathXmlApplicationContext
and I say new and that's a really long name,
so I'm just gonna copy, paste that name.
I'm taking a shortcut, paste.
And then in the construct
I give the actual name of the config file,
so just like in the previous example here,
ApplicationContext.xml, that's the name
of our XML config file.
Now it'll give us error messages for us,
so we wanna import,
so we'll simply hover over that error message
and then we choose that first option of importing.
So, if you move up top,
Eclipse will help you out with importing
that class from the appropriate package,
so that's a nice little feature there.
Okay, so now let's retrieve the bean from the container.
So, here I say context.getBean
and I give myCoach, that's the ID,
comma Coach.class, that's the actual name
of the interface for our implementation.
So, now I'm simply gonna call methods on the bean,
so I simply use my system out print line trick,
sysout, control, space,
and then I'll say theCoach.getDailyWorkout.
And now I simply go through and close the context
by saying context.close,
just to be nice, just to clean up after ourselves.
Alright, so that's kind of the basic game plan here
with this HelloSpringApp.
So, the first thing we do
is we load the Spring configuration file,
then we go through and retrieve the bean
from the container.
Then I call methods on that bean,
and then finally I close the context
by doing my clean up,
and now that's the basic game plan.
And that's kinda your first Spring application right there.
Wohoo.
Now let's go ahead and try this out,
let's run it.
So, just do a right click, run as a Java application.
And there we go.
Booya, check the output.
So, here look at some of the info messages,
so it's loading XML bean definitions
from your class path resource,
that's our configuration file,
applicationContext.xml,
and then we called our sysout print line
on the getDailyWorkout,
and our TrackCoach said hey,
we need you to run a hard five K.
So, this looks really good.
Kinda excited about this.
I hope you are too.
This is our first real Spring application
and it actually works which is cool.
So again, there's the code up top
and then our messages being displayed there
at the bottom, reading a config file,
getting a bean from the container,
and then simply calling methods on that bean,
and that gives us the desired output in our console window.
Cool.
So, let me kind of switch back to our slides here
for a second because now we've kind of come
full circle here.
So, now we have an app that meets the requirements.
Our app is configurable
based on that configuration file
we just worked on
and also we can easily change the coach
for another sport by simply putting in
a different coach implementation.
So, I like to say mission accomplished,
and I'd like to say that we've met all of those requirements
from our manager.
So, hey boss, we got it all covered here.
We're all done for the day
and thanks to Spring our life is much easier.
So, good job here.
Our first Spring app,
it's up, it's running and it's working.
A lot of great Spring stuff coming on later
but hey, this is a good start,
so give yourself a pat on the back.
Job well done.