Alright, so we met the requirements
but our boss said I'd like to see you test that out,
let's change the configuration file
and let's put in a different implementation.
They just wanna make sure
that the code actually works as advertised.
Alright, no problem.
So, here let me open up my Spring config file,
I'll move in here.
Right now it has a TrackCoach that it's using
and I want to change this over to use BaseballCoach, right?
So, I'll replace TrackCoach with BaseballCoach.
It's all configurable
and then once I have that set up
as BaseballCoach, I simply save this file.
And so, once the file is saved,
I move over to my app again
and I simply run it.
No need to change the source code here
because it's reading everything from the configuration file.
So, I just say right click, choose run as
and run it as a job application.
And boo yaka, boo yaka.
(instructor laughs)
So, now our BaseballCoach implementation is running.
Based on information from the config file,
our BaseballCoach says hey,
spend 30 minutes on batting practice.
So, this is really good, so we've met the requirements here.
Our app's configurable,
simply change the config file,
run it without modifying any source code
and it'll pick up the new implementation.
So, again job well done, drop the mic
and you can go ahead and head home for the day
'cause you accomplished a lot of great stuff here.
Alright, good job.