Hey, real quick in this video
we're gonna discuss constructor injection
and what happens behind the scenes.
So, we have our screen configuration file
that's been created but you may wonder well,
what really happens behind the scenes
when Spring runs through or processes this file?
So, behind the scenes the Spring framework
will actually perform some operations for you
based on information you have in the config file
and I just want to kind of show you this code wise
so you get a better feel for what happens.
So, over on the left is our config file,
over on the right is kind of the work
that Spring will do for you behind the scenes.
Alright, so when you create that first bean,
myFortuneService of HappyFortuneService,
behind the scenes Spring will actually construct
that object for you,
so they'll actually call the default constructor
or the nor or constructor and they'll create
a HappyFortuneService,
and they'll give it the variable name of myFortuneService.
Alright, so that covers that first piece of it,
the first bean.
Now moving forward there's also a second bean, myCoach,
so here they'll actually create a new BaseballCoach
and based on the information from your config file,
they'll pass in a constructor argument
and that's the same myFortuneService
that we just created,
so they'll create that BaseballCoach
with that myFortuneService,
and again, make this bean available.
So, the key here is that Spring will do this work for you
in the background and Spring's object factory
when they kind of create your objects
and they inject the dependencies,
this is really what's going on behind the scenes
when Spring processes your file.
So, I hope this helps out a little bit.
I wanted to kind of just cover that real quickly
before we jumped into the actual coding.
Alright, so I'll see you in the next video.