All right, so let's go ahead
and move into Eclipse.
Let's get our hands dirty and write some code.
So we'll use the previous project from before.
Our development process, the first thing we need to do
is define the dependency interface and class.
So we'll go ahead and start off with the first step here.
The first thing we need to do is define an interface,
so I'll say New, Interface.
I'll give the name of this interface as FortuneService.
Once you're happy, click the Finish button.
So we have this very empty interface right here.
I'll simply define one method called getFortune,
and this method returns a string.
And since this is an interface,
there's no actual implementation code.
We simply have just a semicolon, no curly brace or anything,
just the method signature.
Okay, great, so that's our interface.
Now we actually need to create a class
to implement this interface.
So I'll do a right-click, I'll say New, Class.
What we'll do is we'll make use of that HappyFortuneService
that we saw on the slides.
And what we wanna do here
is move down to this Interfaces section that's empty,
but I wanna click this Add button
and actually add an interface to implement.
So up top, I'll type in fortune
and it will find FortuneService.
We'll go ahead and select that one.
That's the one that we just created in the previous section.
And I will hit OK.
And so we should have our interface listed here
in the Interfaces section.
Once you're happy with that,
move down to hit the Finish button.
Cool, so we have this HappyFortuneService.
Woo-hoo, I like it, getting excited here.
Let me expand the window.
So our HappyFortuneService
implements that interface FortuneService.
With that implementation,
they gave us an auto-generated stub here
for that method getFortune.
But here, I'll just go ahead
and I'll put in my own little fortune here.
I'll just hardcode something for now.
I'll say, "Today is your lucky day!"
Yay, yeah (giggles).
And again, just a very simple implementation
that somebody can call this method
and they can get their actual fortune.
All right, so this looks pretty good so far.
Now, what I'd like to do is actually
move back over to my Coach interface
because in my Coach interface,
I actually wanna add a new method to this Coach interface.
Because our coach already gives daily workouts,
but now, we want our coach to also give daily fortunes.
So here, I'll say, getDailyFortune.
And again, just the method signature, no implementation.
So that's our Coach interface.
And then our class that implement this,
well then, they'll have to provide
some implementation support.
All right, so I'm going to save this Coach interface and,
ooh, I see some red exes here.
Oh, I broke some of the classes that implement Coach.
And the reason they broke, because those classes,
they don't implement all the methods (giggles).
So here we can just hover over that red squiggly
and then we can choose that little fix here
that Eclipse is suggesting.
We can add unimplemented methods.
Ooh, cool, I like it.
So Eclipse is helping us out here.
Eclipse said, "Hey, you need this new method
that the Coach interface has, and you don't have."
So they went ahead and gave it to us, so thank you, Eclipse.
And similar thing here for TrackCoach,
they don't have it either,
so we'll choose Add unimplemented methods.
So we're basically just fixing the code that we just broke.
And we'll leave it right now for return though.
We'll come back to that stuff later.
But at least we just have the method in there.
We have the placeholder in place
just to make it pass the compiler.