All right, so we're making
some good progress now.
So we just completed step one of defining
the dependency interface and the class.
Now let's go ahead and focus in on step two,
creating a constructor in our class for the injections.
All right, so back into Eclipse.
I need to actually create a constructor in my class
for injections.
So in my BaseballCoach class,
I need to do two things actually.
One is define a private field,
and then, two, define a constructor.
So let's go ahead and just write
some quick comments here in the file.
So here I'm gonna set up a
private field for FortuneService.
I'm also gonna give the variable name fortuneService
with a lowercase f.
Okay, so the capital F is the actual interface name.
The lowercase f version is our variable or field.
And then I define a constructor
for the dependency injection.
All these fancy buzz words here.
We're actually doing it, which is pretty cool.
So, creating a constructor, right?
Nothing fancy, the same name as the class,
BaseballCoach.
And now for the argument,
you simple set up the actual interface name here.
So FortuneService, I'll call it theFortuneService,
and then I simply make an assignment here
inside of this constructor.
So I say FortuneService, our field equals theFortuneService,
the actual parameter being passed in.
So Spring will actually construct our object,
they'll pass in a dependency,
and then we accept it,
and then we simply assign it.
And that's basically dependency injection.
So our class is ready to accept dependency injection
from the spring framework.
So we're in good shape right now.
All right, so we're making progress here
with this dependency injection.
Now let's go ahead and use this new FortuneService.
So down in that getDailyFortune method,
let me remove all of that auto generated stuff,
and I'll write a quick comment here to myself.
Actually, give me some white space.
I need to stretch out.
Okay, now here's my comment.
I'm gonna use my fortuneService to give the fortune, right?
So the coach can do daily workouts on his own.
But for fortunes, he actually needs a helper.
We're gonna use that dependency that was passed in.
So you all say fortuneService.getFortune
and that's what I return.
So I'm basically helping out the coach
by making use of this little helper class
or like an assistant to help the coach out.
We always wanna help the coach, right?
Helping well.
So that's basically it.
So we're making use of our dependency
in our actual application.
So this is cool.
We're doing some good dependency injection stuff here.
Getting excited.
We can probably go brag to our friends now that
we're doing some dependency injection.
We're doing some DI.
We can now one up our friends at the water cooler
when we talk again.
Yeah, man, I'm doing some screen dependency injection.
All right, so there we go, looking good.
So now the next step here is configuring
the dependency injection in our spring configuration file.
So we need to set this up in our spring config file
that application context.xml.
So I'm going to just get some white space here.
So I need to first define a bean here for that dependency.
And that dependency of course is our fortune teller,
our little helper, our assistant coach or whatever.
So here I'll set up this bean.
I give the id equals myFortune,
and then class.
I'll just set some double quotes here.
I'll make it empty for right now.
And what I need to do for classes,
I need to get the fully qualified class name.
So I'm gonna show you this really cool Eclipse trick
on how to do this.
So you can go back over to your HappyFortuneService,
that's the one that we want.
And you can simply click on the class name,
HappyFortuneService,
then you can right click and you can choose
Copy Qualified Name.
So what this will do is it'll give you
the fully qualified name,
meaning the package name dot the class name.
So I can move back over to my application context.xml.
I can right click on class=, and I can hit paste.
And then booyah!
All right, good.
So we have the fully qualified class name,
the package and the actual classes up.
This is very useful if you have a very long,
a very verbose package structure.
This is an easy way to get it in there
without having any typos or whatever,
because we always make mistakes when we hand type stuff.
All right, so that's a dependency.
Now let's go ahead and
set up the constructor injection.
Ooh fancy term.
I tell you, you'll really be able
to brag to your friends here.
So constructor injection.
Now, to use constructor injection,
you make use of constructor-arg,
and it gave me an end element.
Tell you what, I'm gonna just say space /&gt;.
Yeah, because I don't that extra thing there.
All right, and then I say ref=.
And now for ref=, I give the actual ID
of the bean that I'm gonna inject, the ID.
So that myFortune up there,
copy that bean name,
and then I'm gonna move it down here
and choose Paste.
You can hand pick it if you want,
but I like to kind of copy paste,
'cos I save some typing errors.
So that's it.
So they're going to...
What they're gonna do here is they're going to...
When I say they, meaning spring,
the spring framework or factory,
they're gonna create our coach object,
call the constructor,
and they're gonna pass in that fortune reference,
myFortune, which is effectively HappyFortuneService.
So again, this car factory,
they're actually gonna build a car for you.
So spring,
they're actually gonna construct the object for you,
and inject the appropriate dependencies.