Wow, we did some great stuff
in that last video so we're pretty much taken care of.
We've covered steps one, steps two and step three,
so we're ready to go.
So, what we're gonna do now
is actually move into our main application class.
We'll make use of the beans from Spring
and then call some methods on it.
So, let's go ahead and dive in.
Alright, so let's go ahead
and move back to our main application class,
our HelloSpringApp,
and this is basically everything from before,
so we go through it and retrieve the bean
from the container myCoach
but now this bean actually has some dependencies, right?
The dependency meaning the FortuneService,
so it actually injects that FortuneService
onto that bean, so when we get the bean,
we actually get the bean fully assembled.
Remember, the Spring factory, they're actually gonna create
all the appropriate beans and dependencies
and inject those dependencies
so you can make use of them,
so you'll get a object that's fully assembled,
ready to go, so your car has already been built,
you simply drive it off the showroom floor.
Now that that's taken care of,
we simply call methods on the bean
and let's go ahead and call the new methods
that we actually have for our FortuneService.
So, here I just simply do system out print line,
and I say theCoach.getDailyFortune.
Fortune, nice, I like that.
And that's really it.
We simply added a new method to support
the new functionality that we just added
to this application.
So, that's cool.
Everything else in this app stays the same.
There's no major changes here.
Alright, let's go ahead and run it.
Right click, run as Java application.
And voila, this looks great.
So, we got our daily workout
but now note this item here,
today is your lucky day.
This is awesome because you're lucky today
because you have a Spring app
that's actually running using dependency injection
and IoC and all those other fancy buzzwords,
so you're ready to hang out with your buddies and brag.
But anyway, this is cool.
I'm having so much fun here.
So, we got this working, it's running
and we went through all of the whole process
step by step, so I'm pretty excited right now.
Now let's go back in here
and let's make some changes.
Let's go ahead and drop in our TrackCoach,
so our TrackCoach can also make use of the FortuneService
'cause hey, we don't wanna leave anyone out, right?
So, we're gonna give equal preference
to all of the sports at our university.
So, here we have our private FortuneService,
service, FortuneService here,
so that's for TrackCoach.
Our TrackCoach also needs a constructor
to support constructor injection.
I'm gonna show you a nice little trick.
So, right click, go to source, K, one more time,
right click, source and choose
generate constructor using fields, whoa.
So, with that.
So, Eclipse will actually look at the fields
that you have in your class
and it'll actually create a constructor
using those fields,
so here we have this one field called FortuneService
and we can keep all the other defaults
and then we can actually move down
and hit the OK button
and Eclipse will actually generate some code for us.
Boo, booya.
So, what we see right here on lines seven through nine,
this is a constructor that Eclipse created
and it created it based on the fields
that we have this class.
Really cool, I like this feature.
And it's very flexible,
you can turn it on and off if you have multiple fields,
but anyway, that covers it for right now.
So, we have our constructor set up for injection,
now in the bottom here
we're actually gonna use this service,
so again, getDailyFortune,
we'll say fortuneService.getFortune
and for this TrackCoach
they're gonna use something a little fancy here.
They're gonna add
their own little message on the beginning.
Just do it.
Famous commercial,
just do it and then they'll drop in a fortuneService,
just a little custom implementation
just so that we know the TrackCoach
is really doing something differently
than you know, the BaseballCoach.
Alright, so we have that saved.
Now in our config file we just swap out BaseballCoach
and we'll drop in TrackCoach.
And we'll save that, hit OK.
Alright, so let's go ahead and right click and run it,
so right click, run as Java application,
and oh my gosh, an error exists in the project.
Yikes, what happened?
MyApp, what's up with that?
Oh, got you.
This is our old rough prototype from earlier.
For know let's comment it out.
I'll come back and fix it later
but just for now I don't wanna deal with it for right now,
so I just hit some comments there,
save it and now I'll go back and run it.
I'll fix that later, so,
and I'll actually fix it in this video,
so right click, run as, Java application.
Don't want to steal my thunder here
because I'm on a role, run a hard 5 K from the TrackCoach
and boom, just do it, today is your lucky day.
Cool, so our TrackCoach is also serving up fortunes
which is really cool, so.
I'm happy.
And I'm speechless.
Yikes.
Alright, so let's go back and fix that issue
that we had before, set up MyApp.
So, we just comment it out with some code
but you know, how should we really,
what's the real solution here?
And the real solution is that over on the left-hand side
they're trying to create a TrackCoach
but we don't have a no-arg constructor
or we don't have a default constructor,
so we need to add that to the class.
So, I can simply just hover over
or actually I can just go ahead and type it in myself,
I'll go ahead and do it the long way.
So, I can go back to my TrackCoach class
and I simply need to create a no argument constructor.
So, public TrackCoach,
open param and close param,
and then there we go.
So, this is kinda of a hack,
not totally ideal
but anyway, this will help us out
when we get to the setter injection stuff.
So anyway, I'll kind of leave it for now.
There are minor issue here or there
but we'll worry about that later.
So anyway, that takes care of the actual compile issue
and we're good to go.
so, I think we're in good shape here.
I mean, we covered on all
of the basic constructor injection stuff
with dependency injection.
Good job, whoa.