In this video,
we're going to cover setter injection.
So we've already covered constructor injection
in the previous videos.
And this video will focus on making use of setter injection.
So with setter injection,
this is where the spring framework will inject
your dependencies by calling setter methods on your class.
So looking at the development process,
and again, I love to do things step-by-step.
The first thing we'll have to do,
or the first step we'll have is
creating the setter methods in our class for injections.
Then the second step is configuring the dependency
in the Spring configuration file.
Okay, so let's take a look at step one,
creating the setter method.
So we'll have this new class called CricketCoach.
We're going to explore a new sport here.
So CricketCoach, they'll have a private field,
they'll have a no-argument constructor,
and then we'll have a setter method
for setFortuneService.
This is the method that will be called by Spring
when they inject the dependency
using setter injection.
So in step two, we have to configure
the dependency injection
in our Spring config file.
So up top, we have our FortuneService,
like from the previous videos.
And now here, on the bottom,
we'll have this myCricketCoach.
We inject the dependency using setter injection.
So here we say property.
We give the name of the property, fortuneService,
and then the ref myFortuneService.
And the ref refers to the bean
that was defined a little earlier in this example.
Now we have property name="fortuneService".
What Spring will actually do is
it'll take that property name,
and call the setter method on your class
for that given property.
So they'll look for a public method
called setFortuneService.
So Spring will actually call the setFortuneService,
and they'll pass in that value for that call.
So, in general, any property name you have,
Spring will attempt to make a call to the setter method
for that given property.
So if I had a property name BestAthlete,
Spring will look for a method called
public void setBestAthlete.
So, it takes that property name,
the first letter of that property,
and makes it a capital,
and then it makes a method call on the fly.
So this is how Spring will process your config file.
So up top, we have the bean ID of myFortuneService.
And like we've seen before,
Spring simply creates an instance
of your FortuneService by using
the new keyword for the no-argument constructor.
Then for our CricketCoach,
Spring will create a new CricketCoach
using its no-argument constructor,
and then it'll inject that dependency
by calling the setter method.
So whatever the property name is,
in this case the property name is FortuneService,
Spring will call setFortuneService,
and they'll pass in a reference to that given bean.
And that's what happens behind the scenes
when Spring processes your configuration file.