Alright, so let's go ahead
and move into Eclipse and let's write some code.
With our development process, the first thing
we need to do is create a setter
method in our class for injections.
But, actually, what we need to do
really is create a new class first.
Let's go ahead and create our CricketCoach class
and the name of this class, we'll call it, CricketCoach,
pretty simple and for the interfaces here,
I actually need to make use of the coach interface,
I need to add the coach interface,
I'll click on add, I'll type in coach at the top
and this will give me my coach interface.
Hit okay.
Alright, so now we have this coach interface listed
and we'll keep all the other
defaults and then we'll hit finish.
Okay great, so we have our very basic cricket coach class
and what I wanna do is, go ahead
and just do some of the basic work for these
methods that we need, get daily work out
and get daily fortune, so let me just kinda
clean this up a bit, let me add the
daily work out here for cricket
and so, here we're gonna practice fast bowling
for 15 minutes a day and cricket's a great sport.
Also, we're gonna get the daily fortune
and remember with this one, we need a helper
so we need to make use of our dependency here,
so private fortune service, and I'll just say,
fortune service, it hasn't been assigned yet
but we'll take care of that in a second.
But let's just go ahead and use it down here
in this get daily fortune method,
so here we'll say, return fortuneService.getFortune
and there we go.
Alright, so this kinda covers just the basic
infrastructure work that we needed
for a new coach that we're bringing online,
returning the daily work and
also returning the daily fortune.
Alright, so that takes care of that part of it.
Now, the next thing I need to do here,
is actually create a no argument constructor
because spring's gonna actually call this constructor
when they make a reference to our bean.
So again, constructor simply has the same name as the class,
public cricket coach and what I'll do
inside of this method here, or this constructor,
is I'll actually make use of a sys out print line,
I just wanna put a little diagnostic messaging here,
just so I know that, hey, we're actually inside
of our constructor because, when I run the program,
I like to see, kinda what's going on
behind the scenes by spring, so spring is gonna call this
method, or call this constructor
and I just wanna get some diagnostics
just so I know that, hey, things are happening for us.
Okay now, we can get to our real step one,
we have to do some preliminary work,
but we're ready to go now, so here,
this is why we actually create the
setter method in our class for the injections
and I'll make use of this Eclipse trick,
I'll just do a right click, I'll choose, source
and I'll go down to generate getters and setters.
In this scenario, I really only need a setter,
so I'll simply expand this list here
and I'll just check the box for, setFortuneService,
that's the only method that I need,
I don't really need the getter method,
only the setter method.
You can add the getter if you'd like, but it's not required.
Alright, so I'll go ahead and hit okay
and that should create a new method for me
and it's down there, let me just clear up some white space,
more white space and here it is,
in lines 12 through 14, that's that new setter method
that was just created for us by Eclipse
and this is the actual setter method
that'll be called by spring when they
actually inject the dependency.
Alright, so this looks pretty good so far,
I'll just copy paste this print line
onto a similar thing here in the setter method,
so another, just a diagnostic method
to say, "hey, I'm inside of this setter method."
when I give the actual method name.
Again, mainly just for us when we test the program out,
just to see what's going on.
Alright, so we can kinda step back a bit
and this is basically all the real stuff here,
we created that no argument constructor
and we also created our setter method.
So, we're in pretty good shape so far.
I'll see you in the next video.