Alright, so we're moving right along here.
So, the next step in our dev process
is to configure the dependency
in our Spring configuration file.
So, let's go ahead and open up our applicationContext.xml
and we'll set up our dependency injection.
So, I'll kinda expand the window here for this file
and I'll move down to the bottom
and we'll add a new bean entry here for our CricketCoach,
So, bean ID, myCricketCoach and for the class, equals,
I'll just kinda leave it empty for right now
and then I'll come back and use that same technique
that I used before,
because I need the fully qualified class name
of my cricket coach.
So again, what I'll do is I'll just kinda
move back to that class CricketCoach
and I will select it and right click
and choose, copy qualified name.
So, that will give me the fully qualified name,
which the package name dot the class name
and then I'll move back over to my configuration file,
and I'll just do a right click and choose paste.
So there we go.
So, that's our fully qualified class name for this example.
Alright, so we're doing pretty good here.
Now let's go through and actually set up
our setter injection.
Set up our setter injection
and what I'll do here is I'll set up property,
I'll say name equals and then I'll set ref equals
and I'll go ahead and fill in some other values here.
So the name, this is the actual property name here,
so the property name is fortuneService
and the ref is gonna be
the name of myFortuneService
and again, the ref of myFortuneService,
that's the bean that was defined a little bit earlier
in this configuration file,
I'll kind of scroll up a bit
so you can see it.
So, up on line 13 that bean ID of myFortuneService,
that's the actual same reference
that we'll use when we inject it into our CricketCoach.
Okay, great, and then also as a reminder here
with that property, name equals fortuneService,
the Spring framework
will actually call setFortuneService,
so again, they'll take that property name,
the first character, they'll make it a cap
and then they'll call setFortuneService.
Alright, so we're pretty good here.
Another thing I wanna do
is create a new app class for this demo.
So, just to kinda start from scratch
just so we have a separate area to work in
and you know, makes it a little bit simpler
for us to work through it.
So, I'll create a new class,
and I'll call it SetterDemoApp
and again, just a class that's gonna have a main method
to read the Spring config
and perform some operations.
So, I'll check the box there
for the main method
and then I'll keep all the other defaults
and I'll hit finish.
Alright, so here's our SetterDemoApp.
I'll go ahead and clear out this auto-generated stuff
and I'll just quickly just write some comments here
as far as what we need to do in this app.
So again, we're kinda starting from scratch here.
So, the first thing we'll do is load
the Spring configuration file.
We will retrieve the bean from the Spring container.
Then we'll call methods on the bean of course,
and then finally we'll be nice
and we'll close the context.
So, that's the basic game plan here
for this demo app,
and we've seen this before in some previous videos
but we're just gonna kind of do it again from scratch
just for this setter example.
Alrighty here.
So, loading the Spring configuration file,
so ClassPathXmlApplicationContext,
context equals new
and I use that big long class name,
I'm just gonna do a copy, paste on that.
And then I just pass in the actual name of the file
that I'm reading in, applicationContext.xml,
so there's my context
and you can fix the imports here
by hovering over the red arrow or the red line
and say import and that'll take care of the imports for you.
Alright, we're good there.
Now let's retrieve the bean again
on the white space at the bottom.
I'll retrieve the bean by saying CricketCoach, theCoach,
equals context.getBean
and I give the name of the bean, myCricketCoach
comma and then CricketCoach.class.
Alright, so now when we retrieve this bean,
they'll actually do all the setter injection work
behind the scenes for us.
And then actually this is kinda cool,
let's do this real quick.
So, let's do this context.close
and that line here for calling methods on the bean,
let's just say that we'll come back and do this later
because what I wanna do is just check
the basic operations here,
what Spring is doing behind the scenes
because we put some print line methods in there
as far as the constructor and the setter
and Spring should call those methods automatically
and so we should see something
when we actually run this program.
So, let's go ahead and save this
and let's do a right click
and choose run as Java application
and we beam up the console
and oh yeah, looks really good.
Look at that.
So, we're loading that config file,
so it reads the configs,
and then here it says we're inside the no-arg constructor
and we're inside the setter method
and those are those little print line methods
that we personally added,
so we know that Spring is actually calling
these methods for us behind the scenes
when they're processing that config file,
so this all kinda works out
with everything that we've been learning here
in the video,
so this looks really good.
I'm confident now going forward
with how this part works out.
Alright, so now we can move back into our SetterDemoApp
and then we can go ahead and actually write some code
for doing this stuff.
So, let's go ahead and call the methods now.
So, I'm just gonna do a print line on the workout
and the fortune.
So, sysout print line.
Here I'll say theCoach.getDailyFortune,
I'm sorry, actually getDailyWorkout
and then a similar thing here for theCoach.getDailyFortune.
There we go, that's my fortune, alright.
Alright, good stuff.
So, these are the methods here
that we're calling on our coach
and we should see again, some information being displayed
to the screen when we run it.
Alright, so again, we save it,
right click, run as Java application
and we look at the console window here
and oh yeah, looking good.
So, those are our diagnostic messages up top
and then that's our daily workout,
practice fast bowling,
and then the item here is our fortune,
today is your lucky day.
So, this is great,
so everything kind of works out as desired.
Spring is making use of setter injection,
they're injecting that fortune service
and then we can use our coach
and call methods just like we could do before
with all the other coaches like baseball coach
and track coach, so again,
really good example here.
We're just making use of another technique in Spring
as far doing setter injection.
So again, great job, pat yourself on the back
and we're moving.