Hey, in this video we're gonna learn
how to inject literal values into our Spring objects.
So, currently we have our CricketCoach.
We've learned how to inject a FortuneService
to our CricketCoach.
But now we'd like to inject some literal values
like some string values.
So I'd like to inject
the actual email address for the coach,
and the actual team name for the coach,
like the Sunrisers.
Alright, so let's go ahead
and check out our development process for this.
So again, I love to do things step by step.
The first thing we're gonna do here
is create setter methods in our class for injections.
And then we'll also configure the injection
in our Spring configuration file.
Alright, so let's go ahead and take a look at step one.
Create setter methods in your class.
So here's our class CricketCoach.
Actually the first thing we wanna do
is create some private fields to hold these values.
So I'll have a private String for emailAddress,
and then a private String for team.
Once I have that set up,
then I need to set up public setter methods
for these fields here.
So I have a public void setEmailAddress,
public void setTeam.
And we'll cover the coding piece in the video.
Alright, so now that's taken care of, now we do step two.
Configure the injection in the Spring config file.
So again, here's myCricketCoach,
then I have these two new entries here
for property name equals emailAddress,
and then value, and then I give the actual value
of the email address.
Thebestcoach@luv2code.com.
And note here the attribute name is value equals,
as opposed to ref.
So value is used for literal values,
ref is used to refer to other objects or dependencies.
And then I just repeat the process here
for this next property, team.
So I give the actual value,
and I give the actual literal value here for the team.
Alright, so that's the basic process there
for injecting literal values into your Spring application.
In the next video, we'll dive into Eclipse,
and we'll actually write the code to make this happen.
Okay, I'll see ya there, in the next video.