All right, so let's dive into Eclipse.
Let's go ahead and write some code.
Again, looking at our development process,
the first step we need to do is create the setter methods
in the class for injections.
All right, so let's go ahead and open up the file here
for our Cricket Coach.
Expand the window here.
Again, remember the first thing we really need to do is
set up these private fields here
for emailAddress and team.
I'll just write a quick comment here for myself,
and then I'll go ahead and answer these private fields here,
so I have this private String emailAddress,
and then I have a private String team.
These are just the fields that we're gonna use
to actually assign the data
once it's injected to our application,
but that's basically what we have here.
This looks pretty good so far.
Now, the next thing I need to do is actually generate
or create the setter methods here in our class
for injections
so I'll actually make use of Eclipse
to generate this for me.
Here I'll do a right-click,
I choose Source,
and I choose Generate Getters and Setters.
Here in this dialogue,
you tell Eclipse what you want,
so we'll check the box here for emailAddress and for team.
Then we can expand it,
and we can see that Eclipse will create
the getter and setter methods for each one of these fields.
Now, you don't really need the getter methods.
You only need the setters,
but I'll go ahead and use both of them
because we'll actually wanna print out the values
in our little test program.
All right, so here we go. We have this all set up.
We have our methods here
for getEmailAddress and setEmailAddress,
and getTeam and setTeam.
These are of course generated by Eclipse,
so thank you Eclipse!
All righty, now what I'd like to do is add
some little diagnostic methods here,
or diagnostic messages here in our setters,
so I'm just gonna copy line 36
that we had from our setFortuneService method.
I'll just copy that line.
Right-click, choose Copy
or you can use the keyboard if you'd like.
Then I'll just move up to this setter for emailAddress,
and I'll just paste it in there.
All right, and I need to simply just update the description,
so I just copy emailAddress and then put it there.
I just wanna make sure that this message is correct,
so it says, "CricketCoach:
"inside setter method for setEmailAddress".
Okay, good. So this is good.
Now, let's just go ahead and copy/paste this line
and do a similar thing here for when we set the team
because again, I'm adding these little messages here
just so I can see how Spring is working behind the scenes
when they call these appropriate methods.
I just added a setter method here, or a message,
for setTeam.
Mainly just diagnostics for us,
you know, mainly a training purpose here.
All right, so I just highlighted.
These are the methods that we have here.
Primarily, Spring's, they would call the setter methods
when they inject those values into your class.
We have the getter methods just so we can display them later
in one of our test programs.
All right, so this looks good.
Now, let's go ahead and move over to step two.
In step two, basically we need to configure the injection
in our Spring configuration file.
Again, I'm moving down here to this myCricketCoach
that we already have from the previous videos
where we injected the fortuneService.
Now, I'm gonna inject those other two values here
for the property emailAddress
and also the property team.
All right, so here I give a property name=,
and I give the actual property, so it's "emailAddress".
Make sure you spell it correct and use the correct case.
Then value=,
and note here we give value,
so that's the actual value that we're placing here.
Not ref, but it's a value.
It's a literal value.
We'll say, "thebestcoach@luv2code.com",
so that takes care of emailAddress.
Now, let's repeat the process here for property of team,
so name="team".
The value="Sunrisers".
That looks pretty good.
Now, remember here when we make use of these properties,
they're gonna call the appropriate setter method,
so since we have property name emailAddress,
Spring's gonna call setEmailAddress
and also property name="team",
Spring will call setTeam
and it'll pass in those values,
or inject those values.
All right, so this looks pretty good.
Let's go ahead and update our demo application,
so I'm gonna open up SetterDemoApp.java.
Then I'll just move down to the bottom.
This is what we had from before
in some of the previous videos.
What I wanna do now is call
some of those new methods that we have
just to see those new values
that we injected into the item cell here.
We'll just simply do a System.out.println,
and we'll print out the coach's email address,
so we say getEmailAddress.
Then we do a similar thing here for team
so we can print out the actual team name.
Sysout.out.println(theCoach
.getTeam). There we go, cool.
All right, so this is it.
That's basically our demo app.
It's making a call to those methods
and all of these values were injected already
by Spring behind the scenes,
so everything should just work out as desired.
Let's go ahead and save this.
Let's just do a right-click and choose Run As
Job Application.
It's gonna bean and up in the Console, and oh, wow!
A lot of good stuff here, let's check this out.
It's reading information from the config file,
it's calling that no-arg constructor,
and then it goes through and it's
making calls to those setter methods.
These are the little
diagnostic messages that we added to our code.
We're confirming that, hey,
Spring is actually calling those methods there.
This is some of our previous stuff of fast bowling and so on
but now, the new part here is
the actual coach's email address
and their actual team name, the Sunrisers.
This looks really good,
so this kinda works out as desired.
We're injecting literal values here into our coach object,
so good job.