In this video
we're gonna learn how to inject values
from a properties file.
Alright, so in the previous videos
we learnt how to inject literal values,
so we could inject an email address in the team.
The only problem is that those values
were hard coded in the config file
and what we'd like to do is be able to read
this information from our properties file.
So, we'll have an external properties file,
we'll have our values there
and then we'll be able to read the email address
and team name from this properties file.
Alright, again, you know how I love
my step-by-step process,
so the first thing we're gonna have to do here
is create the properties file,
then we'll load the properties file
into the Spring config file
and then finally in step three
we'll reference those values from the properties file.
Alright, so let's go ahead and look at step one,
creating a properties file, right.
Very simple.
Simply open a text editor,
create a file, in this case, sport.properties
and you simply give the name value pairs.
So, the name of the property is foo.email
and the value is myeasycoach.
The actual property names,
you can give any name that you want.
There's no direct relation
to your actual bean.
You can call them foo bar, test, funny, bozo, anything.
The only thing is that you simply have to be consistent
between referring to the property name
in this config file and also referring to the property name
in your Spring setup.
Alright, so those are our properties.
Now step two is loading the properties file
in the Spring config,
so in your application context.xml
you simply make use of this context:property-placeholder,
you give the location for it,
so in this case the file will be on our classpath,
and then you give the actual file name,
so in this example
our properties file's called sport.properties
and so I'll actually load that properties file
into memory and then you can use it
within this Spring config file.
So, now this brings us to step three,
referencing the values from the properties file.
So, the general syntax is you simply use
the dollar sign, curly brace
and you give whatever the property name is
and then Spring will actually substitute
that property value directly there.
So, in this case for email address,
I simply give value
equals dollar sign, curly brace, foo.email,
so foo.email's the actual property name
from that prop's file
and that will include the value of myeasycoach@luv2code.
And then here I do a similar thing here for the team.
So, I reference that property name foo.team,
and again, based on information
from the properties file
it will actually put in the value
of Royal Challengers Bangalore.
So, that's basically it
and you can add additional props in there as you like
and simply reference them.
So, the key item here is that you reference
those values using the dollar sign, curly brace,
and then whatever that property name is.
Alright, so good stuff here.
In the next video we're gonna dive into Eclipse
and we'll actually write this code.
Alright, so I'll see you then.