Alright so just moving into Eclipse here
and looking at the Development Process.
The first thing we are going to do is create
the Properties File.
So what I will do here is I will click
on my source directory.
I will do a right click and I'll say New File.
And for the actual name of the file I will call it
sport.properties.
And once you're happy with that go ahead and click
on the Finish button.
Now we simply add the values here for our Properties file.
So our first Property name is called foo.email
and then I simply just enter a value here for the
email address.
Then I do a similar thing here for the actual team name.
So foo.team= and I simply give the team name.
So again you can give any property name that you want,
you simply have to be consistent with the actual value
in this Props file and which you use in the
Spring config file.
Alright so this looks pretty good here for the basic
Properties file for right now.
Alright so let's go ahead and move over to Step 2.
So Step 2 is loading the Properties File in our
Spring config file.
So I am going to actually open up my application
context.xml file.
Expand the window here.
And what I want to do, right near the top here,
like around,
let's see here,
yes, like on line 10.
What I want to do here is actually add a reference
for that context property placeholder.
This is what we use to actually load the Props
file into the Spring environment.
So I make use of context:property-placeholder
and then I give the actual location.
So this file is going to be on our classpath:
So I say classpath: and then I give the name of our
actual Properties file, so sport.properties.
and that is file that we just created.
And, oh my, I normally put my comments first
but I will put the comments last. (chuckles)
So here I will just make comments for myself.
Load the Properties file
sport.properties.
It's just a way to kind of jog my memory when I go
back in and look at this file at a later time.
So good job.
Alright, so then the next step here is Step 3.
Reference the values from the Property file.
So again this is our CricketCoach here that we have
been working on so far, and on Lines 34 and 35 we have
values hard-coded.
And what I would like to do is instead, is make use
of that information from the Properties file.
So again I make use of that syntax right.
${ and the actual property name.
So here, that foo.email, that is the Property name.
And then I will just kind of move back over here
and use that ${ and then I give
the actual property name, foo.email.
Make sure that it's the same name that you have from
the config file.
Alright so that covers us for the email.
Let's do a similar thing here for foo.team.
Then I will just move back over to my configuration file.
And here I will say ${foo.team.
Alright.
Excellent. Looks very good so far.
So that is it. So instead of hard-coded values,
now I am going to read those values from the actual
Properties file.
So this is great. I like this.
The app is kind of very flexible at this point
and also very configurable.
So, in fact we actually have a config file
for the config file right. (chuckles)
We have this Sport.properties that is used in the
configure spring config. Anyways we are all good.
So what we can do now is actually run our demo app.
Set our demo app.java so once we open up this file
here there is really no changes that we have to do.
We are simply changing how the screen is reading
information from the configs.
So all this stuff we can keep the same, no changes,
and we can just simply run it.
So I just do a right click Run As Java Application.
And then we can take a look at the results here.
And, yeah, looking really good here.
Looking really good.
So at the bottom we have our coach's email address
and also the team, so it is actually reading that
information from that file Sport.properties and then
plugging those values in there.
So this is great. I love it. I love it.
Things work as planned. How about that.
Now let's test it out though.
Let's go back and change our Properties file.
Just to verify that it really really is working. (chuckles)
And I am going to change the email address here to
silly. And I am going to change the team name to
a really really awesome team here.
I am going to put in this special super team.
And it's called the Mighty Java Coders. Yeah.
And it's composed of all of us right because
we are all super heroes and we are all
super athletes.
And we can beat any other cricket team out there.
Right. (chuckles)
Alright. So let's try this. So we saved it.
Again, since it is a Properties file no need to
change the application, simply run the application again.
And it should pick up those new properties.
And let's take a look at it.
Yeah! Alright! Good Stuff!
So, there's our team name, Mighty Java Coders,
and our email address silly@luv2code.
So this is great. Woohoo!
We are rocking and rolling.
So we have accomplished that item of actually reading
information from the Properties file
so it is not hard-coded in our spring configs.
So I would like to say Good Job! and Congratulations!