In this video, we're gonna learn about
Spring MVC Validation for number ranges,
using @Min and @Max.
So what we'll do here is we will actually add a new field
to our HTML form for free passes.
So this Free Passes field, the user will be able to
enter a value between zero and 10.
And that's our number range.
Anything outside of that range then, we should have
a validation error displayed on the screen.
So let's look at the development process, and we've
kinda seen this before.
But with step one we'll add the validation rule
the the Customer class, and then from there we'll
display the error message on the HTML form.
Then next we'll actually perform the validation in
the Controller class, and then finally, we'll update
our confirmation page with the appropriate information.
Alrighty so let's dive in and take a look at step one,
adding the validation rule to the Customer class.
So basically what we're gonna do here is have this
new field in our Customer class called Free Passes.
So I'll define it as private int freePasses.
And now, what I'd like to do is actually make use of
two new annotations to set up our validation rules.
I'll make use of an @Min and an @Max.
Very self-explanatory, right?
So @Min, value equals zero, that's the minimum value
that we'll expect, or accept, and then the
message equals, that's the actual error message
that's generated if this validation fails.
So that's for @Min.
Then we'll also add one for @Max.
So the maximum value is 10, and then the appropriate
error message in case this validation fails.
So we've actually placed two annotations here,
on this given field, for a given range.
Now, we go through an do our normal work of adding the
getter and setter methods, so we can actually retrieve
the value for the free passes and also set the
value for the free passes.
But that's basically it as far as the coding here,
for the Customer class.
Alrighty so just a recap on the development process.
The first thing is adding the validation rule
to the Customer class, we just covered that.
Now steps two through four, I won't go through these
in the slides.
I'll actually save these, and we'll actually cover this
in the actual video because, steps two through four,
they're really similar to what we've already done before,
so there's really nothing new to cover in the slides.
We'll simply code this in Eclipse as we
go through the video.
So I'll see ya in the next video.