All right, so let's go ahead
and move into Eclipse.
What we'll do here is we'll start with the first step here,
adding the validation rule to the customer class.
So let me go ahead and move into my source directory,
and let me find the Customer.java file,
and let's go ahead and double-click this one and open it up.
All right, now I'll go ahead and expand the window.
So, for this customer class, we need to add a new field,
and that field name is called freePasses,
and it's an integer.
So I'll say private int freePasses.
All-righty, so this looks good so far.
Now the next thing I need to do is actually generate
the getters and setters for this field.
So what I'll do here is I'll simply just move to the bottom
of the file, and I'll just do right-click
and I'll choose Source, and here,
Generate Getters and Setters.
Yep.
Then I'll select the one item here for freePasses,
I check the box, and then hit okay.
All right, great.
So on lines 32 through 38, those are the new methods
that Eclipse has generated for us,
those getters and setters.
All right, so this is good stuff.
Let's go ahead and move back to the top of this file,
and let's add some validation rules.
All right, so we have our field on line 15 right now,
private int freePasses.
I'm gonna add the validation rules for @Min,
and also @Max.
So starting with @Min, I'll say the minimum value
for this field is zero, and then I get
the actual error message that'll be thrown or generated
in case this validation fails.
And for the error message, you can give anything you want.
Here, I'm just kinda keeping it simple for right now.
So, that's @Min right now.
I'll just copy-paste that,
and I'll do a similar thing for @Max.
So the maximum value, just based on these rules we're
setting up, the maximum value is 10, and again, you can give
any values you want here, but just to kinda follow
with the example I've created so far.
So here the value must be less than or equal to 10.
All-righty, that looks good.
So let's go ahead and fix the imports here, so fix
the import for @Min, and also fix the import for @Max.
All-righty, that looks good, and let's see.
I have a little typo here on this line.
I don't need semicolons there.
I don't know why I did that.
That was bad.
So I'll get rid of that semicolon and that semicolon.
Okay, good.
So, good stuff here.
So now we have this field created,
and we have our validation rules for @Min and @Max.
This is very simple, very straightforward.
Okay, so now, what we need to do next
is actually move to step two, and that's displaying
the error message on the HTML form.
So I'll go into my view directory,
and I'll go to customer-form.jsp,
and I'll open that file.
And I'll expand the window here for a second.
So again, basically I'm just gonna define a form field
and also the form errors.
So, I'll just copy-paste the line breaks there,
and I'm just gonna add a new entry here for Free passes,
and then actually give a form, colon, input,
and I map that to freePasses.
That's the field that we just created in our customer class.
And on line 29, I'll also give information here
for form:errors, so path="freePasses,"
then also specify the cssClass.
Just in the event that, hey, the validation fails, then the
error message for this field will appear just next to it.
And now that's basically it.
So this is really just a repeat of what we've done so far
for Last name.
A similar thing here for freePasses.
All-righty.
Now the next step in our process
is actually performing the validation in the controller.
So that's step three,
perform validation in the controller.
Now, one little caveat here is that there is nothing
that we really have to do here.
The code that we already have in our
CustomerController.java, we can use the exact same code.
There's no changes, no modifications needed here,
because we have the @Valid attribute on line 25,
and that's already working for Last name.
So there's nothing new we need to do.
I'm simply showing you this file here and then showing you
this step just out of completeness, but again,
no changes, no code needed for our controller.
We can kinda leave that as is.
So, next, what we'll do here is we'll cover step four,
and that's updating our confirmation page.
So what we'll do here is move back into our view,
and then we'll go to customer-confirmation.jsp.
And basically what we wanna do here is just give an output,
just echo whatever they entered
for the value for the free passes.
So here, I'll just put in a little &lt;br&gt; there,
and then I'll just say Free passes,
and I'll just drop in the value of Free passes.
So again, using my JSP extression language,
I'll say customer.freePasses, and whatever the user entered,
it'll be echoed here on the screen.
Very simple, very straightforward.
There's no rocket science here.
We've seen all this stuff before.
All-righty, so we're at a point when we can actually run
our application, so let's just move back over to our app,
just do a right-click, Run As, and Run on Server.
Okay, great, our app is up and running.
We hit Customer form.
And then we'll just enter the fields here
for First name, Last name, and then for Free passes,
let's add some bad data.
Right, we're trying to break the system.
So, a large value of 555,
it says must be less than or equal to 10.
Okay, great.
Let's try a negative value.
Hit submit.
Again, must be greater than or equal to zero,
and then we can hit a value of four,
which is in that range, so it's good.
So, as we can see, our validation rules
are working as expected.
It only accepts values between the range of zero and 10.
So I'd say good job with adding validation ranges
with spring and receive.
Woohoo!