In this video, we're gonna learn
about Spring MVC Validation, with Regular Expressions.
So a regular expression is just a sequence
of characters that define a search pattern.
You can use this pattern of find or match strings
but you can also use it for validation.
Now, Regular Expressions it's like its own language.
This is really an advanced topic,
so I'm gonna assume you already know about
Regular Expressions and I'll simply
show you how to apply it with Spring MVC.
Now, if you don't have any experience
with Regular Expressions there's plenty
of free tutorials available.
Check the link here, available on this line.
So what we'll do is we'll actually
use Regular Expressions to validate a postal code.
So our form will have a new field for postal code.
And the user can only enter five characters or digits
in order to pass validation.
And again, we'll actually apply
a pattern for Regular Expressions for this validation.
Now let's look at the development process very similar.
We'll simply add a validation rule
to the customer class.
Then we'll display the error messages
on the HTML form.
And finally, we'll update the confirmation page.
So this is all very similar to what
we've seen before, in some of the previous videos.
All righty, so adding the validation rule
to the customer class.
So basically what we do is make use of a pattern.
And then we have regex, that's Regular Expression.
And we simply, drop in that regular expression.
So what you see there in blue
that's the actual regular expression
that will only match on five characters and digits.
Now, I know the expression looks a little bit scary,
a little bit cryptic, but that's kind of
the language of Regular Expressions.
So once you know Regular Expressions.
You can simply drop in your appropriate expression
and you're ready to go.
So, again, here we have the Regular Expression
and then we have the actual error message.
We simply apply this pattern, to a field,
for a postal code.
And that's it, and we create our normal
getters and setters, and then we're up and running.
And we're ready to go.
And that's it for step one.
We'll cover steps two and three in the next video,
once we move into Eclipse.
So I'll see ya in the next video.