Okay, so let's dive into clips.
We'll start our first step of adding the validation rule
to the customer class.
So I'll move down here to my Java Source directory
and I'll open up the class Customer.java.
And we'll follow a similar pattern as we did before.
So what we'll do is we'll move down here
and I will first add in our new field for postal code
and it'll be a string.
So here I'll say private String postalCode.
And so there's our field here for postal code.
I'll also go through and actually generate
the getters and setters for this field.
So again, my standard practice is to use a right click,
choose Source, and then say Generate Getters and Setters.
And I'll choose our option here for postalCode,
check the box, and then I'll just go ahead
and click the OK button.
And there we go, right there on lines 25 through 31.
Those are the new getter and setter methods for postalCode.
Looks good.
So I'm gonna go ahead and clean up some of the white space
that I have here, just to kind of tighten things up a bit.
Okay great, so now I can actually start getting
my hands dirty, and that's by adding my validation rule.
In fact, we're gonna add a regular expression.
So I give the regex.
So basically this regular expression
is cryptic regular expression.
Basically it's gonna accept only five characters or digits
as the actual postal code.
And again, like I mentioned earlier,
I'm not a regex expert, I know enough to get me by.
There's plenty of regex tutorials online
if you wanted to get into all of the gnarly details
of how the regular expressions work.
But here I'll assume that you already know
how to use regular expressions.
We're simply gonna apply them here on the seal
for springing the seed validation.
Alright, good job.
So that's taken care of, let's go ahead and take a look
at step two, and that's actually displaying
the error message on the HTML form.
So again, go back to my view,
go to my customer-form.jsp and open this one up.
And basically what I'll do first is I'll just do
a little copy/paste here of my existing field.
So that Free passes, I'll just go ahead and copy that
information and then I'll just move down a bit
and actually paste it here on my screen.
Because basically Postal Code is gonna be an input field.
We're simply just gonna change the actual label
and the path form.
So that's just Postal Code.
The path will be postalCode, which maps at that actual field
that we just defined in our customer.java class.
And a similar thing here for the error messages.
So really just some copy/paste programming here.
And hey, please don't judge me.
I like to keep things simple.
So here we go, our new postal code that's entered,
along with the appropriate field here for error messages,
if the validation fails.
So this is great, so again let me clean up
some of the white space here at the bottom.
And this looks pretty good, pretty good.
Great, so now our final step here is just
updating our confirmation page.
So assuming that validation passes,
they would at least like to display
the actual postal code that the user entered.
So I'll go ahead and move into my view,
open up customer-confirmation.jsp
and again here, just some copy/paste programming,
I'll drop in some line breaks and then I'll say
Postal Code and I'll use that JSP expression language again
and say customer.postalCode.
And there we go, looks pretty good to me, I like it.
I hope you're happy too, woohoo!
Alright, well it's time to go ahead
and run this application.
So we'll simply do our right-click Run As
and choose Run on Server.
This'll bring up our main menu.
We'll go ahead and select the link there for Customer form.
And now I'll go ahead and enter some data.
So the last name is required, so I have to enter that data.
So I'll enter a last name.
A postal code is not required, so I can do a Submit.
So that works out a-okay.
Now I want you to actually enter some bad data
for postal code, so I'll just enter a whole lot of gibberish
here on my keyboard and I'll hit Submit.
And it'll say hey, you can only have
five characters or digits.
So I'll go ahead and clear that out.
I'll enter a whole lot of digits.
It's gonna yell at me again.
I'll enter only three characters or only three digits.
It's still complaining.
I'll say, okay you got me.
I'm gonna enter five characters.
So abcde.
Not that, abcde.
I hate autocorrect.
X, there we go.
And now I hit Submit and boom it works out just fine.
So they entered a postal code of five characters.
And I can enter five numbers and it works out just fine.
That's all based on the regular expression
that I'm using in the application.
Now note here, postal code is optional,
so it's not required that you enter a postal code.
So that's how you can enter nothing and it'll still pass.
But if you do enter values, then it's actually going
to apply it with that given regular expression.
Alright, so this is good, we're successful.
We have our regular expressions working.
Our validation's working.
And we're doing all this cool stuff with Spring MVC.
So I'd like to say congrats, good job, and woohoo!