In this video, we're going to learn how to make an integer field required.
So far we've created this nice form, we've added some validation rules already.
We have last name that's required, we have our free passes, we've also added pattern
matching to our postal code.
What I'd like to do is actually make this free passes field required such that, if the
user doesn't provide a value, then we'll actually give them a error message saying, "Hey, this
given field is required."
All righty, let's go ahead and move into our coda, shouldn't be too hard right, 'cause
we've added required fields before.
Let's go ahead and move into our source directory, and let's open up customer.java, all right,
expand the window here.
Let's take a look, so yeah, so we've already added our required fields for last name, so
hopefully we can do something similar here for free passes.
For free passes here, we have our min, and our max value, and this is the field that
I want to make required.
Basically, I simply do a copy paste exercise, I'll copy the @NotNull from last name, and
I'll simply move down to my free passes field and paste it.
All right, so there we go, so we have this @NotNull that we've added here for our free
passes field.
This will basically make sure that's this given field is required.
If they didn't provide a value, then we'll actually display the error message, is required.
That's the game plan, we've kind of seen this before.
All righty let's go ahead and test this out.
I'll save my file, move over here, and run my application, run as an run on server.
I'll through and choose this link for customer form, and I'll test the field free passes
is required.
I'll give something for last name, for free passes, I'll empty this field out, make it
empty, make it blank.
I'll go ahead and hit on the submit button here, and ugh, okay, what the what?
I get this long message here, it says, oh gosh, this is crazy, just double checking
something real quick here, let's empty out last name, and I hit submit.
Okay, so last name is required, that part worked, but what's up with this guy?
Says, "Failed to convert property of string to required type."
Okay, so the root cause is it's a type conversion error.
Couldn't convert a string to the primitive type of int.
Ah, gosh.
A lot of stuff here.
All right, let's go ahead and try and fix this, or resolve it.
We can actually resolve this by refactoring our field.
Instead of using the primitive type, we can use the Integer type.
That's with a capital I, this is basically a wrapper class.
Why won't this work?
Because, if our field is blank, or has spaces, then they'll actually trim it to null, using
that string trimmer editor that we've added before, and then this'll handle the appropriate
issue.
Again, we're going from int to Integer, and Integer's a special wrapper class in java.
That's our field on line 22.
We also have to update our getter and setter methods in this class.
Let's go ahead and scroll down to the bottom.
For get free passes, we get the return type of Integer, with a capital I, and then we
have to do a similar thing here for our setter method, Integer with a capital I.
Again, we're basically using classes here, instead of the primitives here, and hopefully,
this should help us out with that validation as far as the type conversions from strings
to ints.
All right, let's go ahead and save all this stuff, move back over here, and let's run
our application one more time, and let's cross our fingers, hope it works.
We move in here to customer form.
Free passes, we'll leave it blank, we won't put any information in there, and we'll hit
submit, and boo-yah, oh yeah, just the way I wanted it.
Is required, so they can handle the nulls and all that stuff, and that's working out
just fine.
Let's just check it with last name.
We give a last name, we hit submit, and great, so is required is being applied to our free
passes field, so that's kind of working out as desired.
Give real values, it goes through, and the validation passes.
Oh boy, woo.
The key here was simply converting from an int to an Integer type, or refactoring from
int to Integer, and that helped us resolve this issue.
Great job, but we're not really, really done.
There is some other issues with this form, you may have discovered them, if not, we'll
actually talk about them in the next video.
Stay tuned.