In this video, we're going to learn how to handle string input for integer fields.
So we have our form that we've created.
In the previous video we added supports to make sure that the free passes field is required,
but I hinted that we have a little problem.
So let me show you here real quick.
So I'll go ahead and enter something for last name, and then for free passes, let's go ahead
and oo, let's break it by entering some text.
And then hit the submit button.
And come on, really?
So this thing's failing again.
We've entered some text, and it just blows up.
All right?
Failed to convert property value.
Number format exception.
Blah blah blah.
Ah, boy.
Okay, but don't worry, we can actually work this out.
We have a development process that we can use to resolve this issue.
And here it is, step by step.
So, what we'll do is we'll first create a custom error message, so we won't see that
big, long, ugly error message.
We'll simply give them a simple message of, "Hey, invalid number."
And then in step two, we'll actually load that custom resource into the Spring configuration
file, and then that information will be displayed and used on our screen during spring validation.
So in effect, we're simply going to add our own custom error message for that scenario.
All right, so let's go ahead and move back in to Eclipse.
Let's take a look at our code.
So let's go ahead and do step one, creating the custom error message.
Now the key is that we have to place this inside of a new folder inside of a new file.
So the first thing I'll do here is on the src directory, I'll go New, and Other.
Because I'm basically going to create a new folder.
And here in the wizards here I'll simply do a filter for folder, find folder, because
we're going to create a new folder.
Go ahead and click on next, and then I give the actual name of the folder.
So this folder's going to be under the src directory, so make sure you have source there.
And then the folder name is resources.
And then click on finish.
Okay great, so now we should have this resources directory here underneath src directory.
So I'll go ahead and choose resources, and now I'll create a new file in this resources
directory or folder here.
So I'll go new, and I'll choose other, and here I'm going to create a new file.
So new, other, and then in the list here I simply select file.
Alrighty, so I have the file selected.
Go ahead and click on next.
And what I'll do here is create a new file called messages.properties.
And make sure you use the exact same name that I have here on the screen.
messages.properties.
And then go ahead and hit the finish button.
All right, great.
So we have this blank file here called messages.properties.
What we're going to do here is actually add our own custom error message for that scenario.
So here I'll give typeMismatch.customer.freePasses equals, and then I give the actual custom
error message that we're going to use for this scenario.
So, "Invalid number."
All right, so there's a lot of stuff here.
Let me kind of break this down for you and explain it.
So the first item here is the actual error type, type Mismatch.
Then we have the actual attribute name.
Next we give the actual field name, and then finally we specify our own custom error message.