All righty, so we have the file saved.
This is our custom error message for the Spring
validation, but we need to tell Spring about
this file.
One thing that's really important that I want
to point out here is that the location is
very important.
This file has to be under src/resources and
then the file name is messages.properties.
That's very, very important.
Now, let's go ahead and tell Spring about
this in step two, so load the custom messages
resources in our Spring config file.
I'll simply open up my spring-mvc-demo-servlet.xml
file.
Go ahead and expand the window here so I can
see more of the file.
Let's go ahead and scroll down to the bottom.
What I'll do here is I'll actually load the
custom message resource, so that actual file
that we created previously, we're going to
tell Spring about it so Spring can load it
and then use it for our validation error messages.
I'm going to kind of stretch out here at the
bottom, give myself some white space, some
room to work with.
I'll create this special bean with a bean
ID of messageSource, and then I give the actual
class name for the resource bundle loader.
This is going to be a really long class name,
so kind of hang in there with me as we type
it.
This is going to be organization.springframework.context.support.ResourceBundleMessageSource.
The class name has to be exactly the same
and also the bean ID has to be exactly the
same.
Make sure you have the exact code that I have
here on lines 28 and 29.
Now, I need to also specify where to find
the file, and I set this up by making use
of a property here for basenames.
I have basenames and I give value as resources/Messages.
What this configuration will do is it'll actually
load the file under resources/messages.properties
and Spring will automatically append the .properties
on there for you, you don't have to specify
it on line 31.
Spring will do that for you in the background.
It's very important that you have this exactly
like I have here on the screen.
All right, so we're in good shape here.
Let's go ahead and test this out and see if
it works.
I go over to my application and I'll get it
up and running on my server.
Go ahead and click on the link for customer.
For last name, I'll just give Smith.
Now, I'll add a lot of text.
Ooh, let's try and break it.
Boom.
Oh, yeah.
There's our custom error message, "Invalid
number."
That's great, so it's actually reading our
custom message from the file and displaying
it to the user, so no more of that long-winded
Java stuff.
We get a simple message that we can show to
the user.
Again, that was defined in our messages.properties
file, so you can simply change that to anything
you want, reload the app, and it will have
that new error message being displayed there
on the screen.
Good job.
Now, you may notice that there was a lot of
stuff that we put there, in that messages.properties.
In the following video, I'll actually break
it down even further.
I'll go in depth and I'll decipher how we
came up with that big, long piece of text
that we added in at messages.properties.
Stay tuned and we'll do a deep dive in the
next video.
Yo, yo.