All right.
So we have this working, as far as, giving
our own custom message, but there's a lot
of things that we didn't add messages resource
file and I kind of want to break it down,
kind of decipher it and figure out exactly
what those different components were, and
also how you could use this on your own project
if you had a totally different object module
and a totally different form set.
All right.
So let's go ahead and what we'll do is we'll
actually add some logging or debug messages
here in our Customer Controller.
So in our Customer Controller, I'm going to
actually inspect the Binding Result object,
because this object has a wealth of information,
a lot of good data that we can use to kind
of decipher what's going on during the validation
process.
So what I'll do is I'll simply add a System
out print line and I'll print out the Binding
Result.
So I'll say, "Binding Result and then the
Binding Result," and again the Binding result's
a parameter that's being passed in to this
method when we process the form.
Then also, just to kind of help out with showing
you this stuff on the video, I'm going to
add some line breaks or some line spaces or
new lines, just to kind of move things up
on the console window, but this is not really
required.
Line 48's kind of just for me to help you
show stuff on the video.
All right.
So let's go ahead and save this.
Let's go back and get it up and running and
we can check out some of our logs here in
the console window.
So I just go to the customer form here.
And I'll just enter some data here for Smith,
I'll enter some bad data here for freePasses,
and then I'll go ahead and hit on the submit
button.
Okay, great.
So now we should have some good data in our
console when it runs.
So let me go ahead and double click console,
bring it up.
Okay, good stuff.
Really good stuff.
See these last two lines here are very important
for us.
All right.
So this line here, the Binding Result, basically
says, "Hey, this Binding Result had one error,"
okay and we know about that, it's on the freePasses,
of course.
And the second line will actually give you
more details as far as where it occurred so
it'll say that, "Hey there's a field error
on object customer," and that's the actual
Spring MVC attribute name, and then on the
field freePasses of that customer object.
Okay, cool.
Good stuff, good stuff.
And then it says the rejected value, so whatever
the data that the user entered.
So you can grab that, if you want to say,
I don't know, play around with that or do
something with it.
Here comes the really good part.
All of the error codes that Spring MVC will
use when it displays a custom message, so
it'll go out and look for these.
So they have, one of their error codes, its
type Mismatch customer freePasses.
So what we'll do is we're simply overriding
their default error code and we're simply
providing our own custom message.
So here in the config file we say, "Hey for
that type Mismatch customer.freePasses, use
our custom message."
And that's how that piece works out there.
Then they also have other error codes here.
You can simply have a type Mismatch on any
freePasses not related to customer in any
field that has freePasses or you can have
a type Mismatch on any field that has an integer
or you can have just a more generic type Mismatch.
So basically it goes from very specific starting
at the left, to very generic all the way over
to the right, but we wanted to make use of
that first one there because we want it to
be specific only for that given specific field.
So you can use this same approach on your
own project.
You simply just do a print line on the Binding
Result and that'll give you all the codes
that Spring's using or looking for and you
can simply override it accordingly.
So just a nice little debugging trick there
for you where you can override the error code
and give your own custom message.
So you can apply this same technique on your
own project.
And then there you go.
So you have it up and running.
I do the print line on Binding Result.
Just a real simple one liner there.
You can inspect the console logs and then
figure out which error codes that you need.
You simply find those codes, drop them into
your messages.properties file, get it all
configured up in your Spring configuration
file, like I showed you a little earlier,
and run it in your application.
And then booyah, your own custom error message.
So there you go.
All righty.
Good stuff.
I'll see you in the next video.