In this video, we're gonna develop
Spring controllers and views.
So we've seen the big picture of Spring, right?
The MVC, you have the front controller,
you have a controller object, and a view template.
What we're gonna do here is actually
set up a request mapping for a given path,
and then we'll have a home controller
that's gonna handle the request,
then it's gonna forward it over to a view template,
which we'll call main-menu.jsp.
And it's very simple, very straightforward,
but I just wanna make sure we get
all the mechanics down for building this out.
All right, so again, I love this
step-by-step process, right?
The first thing we're gonna do is
create the controller class,
then we'll define the controller method.
Next we'll add request mappings
to the controller method,
and then we'll return the view name,
and then finally we'll develop the view page.
Woo, seems like a lot of stuff, right?
But don't worry, we'll go through all of this step-by-step,
and we'll do it all from scratch.
All right, so let's go ahead and start with step one,
creating the controller class.
Basically, you define a class,
and then you annotate it with @Controller.
Now, @Controller basically says that
this is a Spring MVC controller,
and also, one thing that's really cool is that
@Controller inherits from @Component,
so it's really just a specialized component
that supports web MVC.
The nice thing about this is that,
when Spring does its component scanning,
then it'll also pick up @Controllers
because they inherit or extend from @Component.
So this is the basic process here
of defining a controller class.
All right, so let's go ahead and take a look at
step two, defining a controller method.
So, here I have a method, public String showMyPage.
Now, this is a very simple method.
The actual method name is flexible.
You can give any method name that you want.
Here I called it showMyPage,
but I could've easily called it fubar.
The return type here is String.
I'm simply gonna return the actual view name
that I want them to show.
But again, this method here is actually very flexible.
So, in Spring, when you define your controller method,
you can actually pass in any number of parameters,
like request parameters, session objects,
and so on, or model objects.
And you can also return different variations here.
What I'll do is I'll keep it simple for right now,
but in the later videos,
I'll show you some other combinations,
some other forms of how we can define our controller method.
But this is a basic controller method for right now.
All right, so now that we have this method defined,
in step three we need to add the request mapping,
so we basically need to map some type of web request
to this given method, and we do this
with an annotation, @RequestMapping.
So you get the @RequestMapping
and you get the actual path that you wanna map.
So, in my example, I simply wanna map on the route,
so if they simply go to this website,
then they'll show this page here,
or they'll actually call this method here.
I'll show other examples of request mappings
in the following videos,
but this is just the basic one for right now.
And this request mapping will handle
all types of requests, get, post, and so on and so forth.
All right, so now, inside of the method,
with step four, we actually need to return the view name.
So, in this example I'm gonna return "main-menu."
That's the name of the view.
Now, remember here, there is some magic
that's gonna happen in the background.
Spring's actually gonna use information
from its configuration file,
and it'll actually find the view page.
So, based on the configs, it'll look
in a given prefix directory,
and it'll use the view name,
and then it'll pin the suffix ".jsp."
So, in this example here, it's gonna look for
/WEB-INf/view/main-menu.jsp.
So then step five is that
we actually have to create this page,
/WEB-INF/view/main-menu.jsp.
And again, it's any regular html page or jsp page.
You simply put in your html tags,
your markup, and so on.
So that's kinda the basic step here
for building a Spring MVC, I guess, page flow.
And here's just a quick recap of the steps.
Creating a controller, defining a controller method,
adding request mappings, the view,
and then the view page.
So what we'll do in the next video
is that we'll actually move into Eclipse,
and we'll actually build this out from scratch,
and then we'll run all the code,
and we'll get it up and running
on our local computer.
So I'll see you in the next video.