Alright. So let's go ahead
and move into Eclipse.
What we're gonna do is walk through our development process
of creating a controller class,
the method, adding the mapping,
returning view name, and developing the view page.
And again, we'll go through all of this step by step
and we'll do it all from scratch right here.
So there's some prep work that we have to do first
and that is actually creating a new package.
So I'll move into my Java Resources directory,
into the source package, I'll do a right click
and I'll say new package.
And the actual name for the package
that I'm gonna use here is com.luv2code.springdemo.mvc
'cause we're doing some Spring mvc baby.
Alright, that looks good.
Go ahead and hit the finish button.
Alright, so we have our new package,
so now we can start with step one,
creating the controller class.
So I'll simply right click on our new package,
and I'll say new and I'll say class.
And the actual class name that we're gonna give here is
HomeController.
And I'll keep all the other defaults
and I'll hit finish.
Alright, great. So here's a very basic class.
It's empty, nothing's there.
Let me expand the window here for a second.
And the first thing we want to do here
is add the @Controller annotation.
So this basically tells Spring that,
hey this is an mvc controller and to make use of it.
So I'll simply fix the imports here
and I get the Spring stereotype controller, great.
So again remember that @Controller
extends off of @Component,
so they get picked up during component scanning.
Alright, so the next thing here is step two,
defining a controller method.
So just like in the slides,
I'll have a public String showPage.
For right now I'll just say return null
and remember it can be any method name.
Here I just called it a showPage,
but we could easily call it something totally different,
if you'd like.
And what I'll do now is in step three,
is I'll add the request mapping to the controller method.
So I'm basically gonna map a URL request
to this actual method.
So that's why the method name can be anything,
'cause we're gonna simply set up this
annotation mapping to attach this path to the given method.
And again, I go through and just fix my imports
here on @RequestMapping
and choose the first one there,
so I should get the web bind request mapping.
Alright, so this is cool.
So this method here, showPage, it'll handle
all types of http requests for getting posts for
this slash and all the other http methods.
Alright, so this looks good so far.
Now let's go ahead in step four
and let's actually return the view names.
This is gonna be the name of the page that we wanna return.
Again remember, it's not the complete name of the page
because we make use of information from the config file
while they'll actually add a prefix
and they'll actually add the suffix.
So it'll be WEB-INF/view/main-menu.jsp
So Spring will do this automatically for you
in the background, some of Spring's little magic.
Alright, so this looks good.
So let's go ahead and create that view page.
So I'll move back over into my project,
under WebContent, WEB-INF
and then view folder.
I'll simply just do a right click
and I'll say new file.
And the name for the file, we'll call it main-menu.jsp.
And once you're happy with that,
go ahead and click on the finish button.
Alright, great. So at this point,
this is just a regular jsp file.
We can write any HTML markup here that we'd like.
So I'll just go ahead and start off with the DOCTYPE,
I'll say html,
do the basic header stuff, the body stuff,
and here I'll just put a title here,
Spring MVC Demo - Home Page.
And this'll kinda be like our starting point
or our main menu for some of the following examples
that we'll build here in this course.
Alright, so this looks good so far.
You can save it
and um, I don't know, it looks good.
I think we're in good shape right now.