All right, so let's go ahead
and run the application.
So what I'll do is I'll move to my project folder
at the root and I'll simply go right click
and choose run as, and I'll choose run on server.
So here I'll just choose the default server here
and click on finish.
So it's gonna start at the server.
And wow, there's our output.
This looks really, really good.
So this is our main menu JSP, Spring MVC Demo- Home Page.
Ooh, that's awesome, this works.
So basically our controller in the background
forwarded the request over to this view page.
Awesome, awesome.
So let's go dig into the logs here in the console window
and just take a look at some of the output.
Looking at the logs here it says that it's making use
of the spring dispatcher servlet and the initialization
has started.
So it's starting the process of initializing itself
and reading data.
A couple lines down you can see where it's loading
the XML beam definitions from that servlet context file.
That spring MVC demo servlet, dot xml from one
of the previous videos, so that's good.
That basically just has component scanning in there.
Thanks to component scanning then we'll see
that it's gonna actually make, it's gonna actually find
our controller, our home controller and map the slash
onto a method in our home controller class.
So this is great.
It says that it's mapping that onto this method,
show page.
Awesome so just like our code laid out.
This is great, good stuff.
Finally down near the bottom this is where we have
that framework servlet dispatcher initialization complete.
So this is basically your success message that hey
spring started up successfully.
It read all of its controllers, did all the mappings.
There were no issues and the server's up and running
and ready to go.
So this is good.
Successful so far in getting our first example running.
Give yourselves a pat on the back.
In some of the following videos we're gonna dive
into more details here with Spring MVC.
But hey, this is a good first start.
So take a break and get yourself a coffee.
I'll see you in a bit.