In this video,
we're going to learn how to read form data with Spring MVC.
So at a high level, we're going to have a form,
we're going to prompt the user for their name,
they'll hit Submit Query,
it'll go through our Spring MVC application,
and then will show a confirmation page.
Hello World of Spring!
Student name, and we simply plug in the student name
that they entered.
So here's the application flow.
So in the browser, they'll go to our website
and they'll enter /showForm.
This will go to our HelloWorld Controller,
and the main purpose of this is
to simply show the JSP form.
Then, once we have a form displayed,
once they enter their information and hit Submit,
then they're going to pass it over to this
/processForm request mapping.
So again, it's going to go into our HelloWorld Controller,
and for that mapping, we'll simply pass back
a confirmation page, so we'll say Hello World of Spring!
Student name, and we simply plug in the student name.
So the key here is that we're going to use one
HelloWorld Controller that's going to have
two request mappings.
Now let's go ahead and look at
some of the source code here for the controller.
So again, with the Spring controller,
we always annotate with @Controller, up top.
Then I'll set up a method, to show the initial form.
So I'll define a request mapping /showForm,
I give a method name, pubic String showForm,
and then return "helloworld-form".
And then remember in the background,
Spring will add on that
WEB-INF/view/helloworld-form.jsp,
based on information from our configuration file.
Now we'll also need to add a second method here
to process the form.
So we'll have request mapping for /processForm,
and we have a method public String proccessForm,
and we simply return "helloworld".
That'll be the actual confirmation page
that will say Hello World of Spring,
and we simply display the student name.
Now again, remember the method names can be anything.
We simply map the paths to the actual method.
But again, you can use any method name you want,
show form, process form, do the work, FUBAR, whatever.
Alright so let's kind of step back
and look at the development process.
And again, everything's step-by-step.
So, first thing is creating a controller class,
and for showing the HTML form,
we'll have a controller method
to show the form, we saw that
in the previous slide, and we'll also need to
create the View Page for the HTML form.
And then for processing the form,
again we need to create the controller method
for processing the form, and also developing the View Page
to show the actual results.
Okay, so that's our development process.
In the next video, we're going to move into Eclipse,
and we're going to start writing some code.
So I'll see you there.