All right, so let's go ahead
and move into clips and let's start writing some code
to process form data.
So, the first thing we're going to need to do here
is to actually create our HelloWorldController.
So, we'll move into the package here, springdemo.mvc
and I'll do a right click, and I'll say New, Class.
And the name of this class will be HelloWorldController.
And once you're happy with the name,
we'll keep all the other defaults and then we'll hit Finish.
All right, great, so here's our basic class.
I'll expand the window here.
And the first thing I'll always do here
is add the @Controller annotation,
because this is a springmvc controller.
I slide down here and I fix the imports.
All right, that looks good.
And now what I'll do is I'll actually write
some comments to myself,
just to kind of keep myself on track
as far as what I need to do.
(chuckles)
So, I know I'm going to need a controller method
to show the initial form.
And then once I have the form displayed,
I'm going to need a controller method
to actually process the form.
All right, so those are the basic two things
that I'll need to do here in this HelloWorldController,
so I know I'll need to have at least two methods
for building this out.
All right, so let's go ahead
and take this one step at a time.
So, the first thing I need to do is set up my method here.
I'll call it showForm.
And it's going to basically return helloworld-form.
And we know in the background,
springmvc will add all the magic onto it.
I'll set up this @RequestMapping
and I'll have it set up for /showForm.
And I'll also fix the imports here for RequestMapping
choose the first option.
All right, that looks good.
Okay, so stepping back, this looks really good so far.
So this is basically our controller method
to show the initial form.
So they're going to go to /showForm,
in the background we'll simply say, helloworld-form,
springmvc will add the WEB-INF/view,
and I'll append the .jsp.
So we're in good shape with
this layout so far for this method.
All right.
So now, we need to actually go through
and create that view page
or create the actual form.
So, in my WEB-INF "view" folder,
I'll say New, File.
And the actual name of the file is helloworld-form.jsp.
And I'll go ahead and hit the Finish button, here.
All right, so let me go ahead and expand the window here,
and let me go ahead and add
just my very basic HTML header information.
So &lt;html&gt;, and then I'll set up a &lt;head&gt; section,
and I'll also set up the &lt;title&gt;.
All right, so let's go ahead and define our form element.
And then we'll set the action="processForm".
And we'll set the method="GET".
So basically we're going to send something
over to the path /processForm,
and then the actual method type will be GET.
So it's going to pass it as a GET request,
as opposed to a POST request.
And we'll talk about GET and POST a little bit later.
So the input type="text",
and then name, we give
="studentName".
So that's the actual form field name.
And now I'll just set a placeholder here.
That will be the actual prompt text that you'll see
when the form is actually displayed.
So this is the prompt,
hey, "What's your name?" type stuff.
All right, so that looks good.
And now we'll just simply set up
an input type for the Submit button.
So type="submit".
And then I'll just take the default label
that they'll give me there.
And that's pretty much it for our form.
Just taking a look, stepping back.
Making sure I didn't miss anything.
So yeah, basic form field with a Submit button.
All right, so this looks really good so far.