All right, so now we have
our HTML form taken care of.
Let's go back and just take a look at our controller
one more time, so they basically go through
and say /showForm, and they're gonna return,
helloworld-form.JSP.
All right, let's go ahead and run it real quick.
I'm gettin' anxious.
So we'll do a right click on our project,
and we'll choose run on server.
All right, so our project is up and running.
There's our home page.
Now, let's enter showForm, and make sure you use
the exact same case because it's case sensitive,
and oh, good job.
This looks good.
So our form displayed, but we're only halfway there.
We're not fully there yet.
So we can display the form, but we haven't really done
any work for handling the submit or handling the process.
So if I were to actually hit submit here and boom.
It'll break, okay.
(laughs)
Because it's a 404 because they can't find
anything to handle processForm.
So that's what the form's trying to do.
It's trying to send data to this path processForm,
but we haven't done that yet.
Oh, okay, but don't worry.
It's on our to do list, right.
So in line 18, we have this all kind of, you know,
listed out as a item to do, or line 17, 16 right now.
Anyway, so we have an item there to add a method
to process the HTML form.
So let's go ahead and do that now.
All right, so let's go ahead
and write our method for processForm.
So here I call it public String processForm.
And again, remember, you can use any method name.
We simply map it with the appropriate mapping here.
And then I'll say return.
And we're actually gonna return helloworld as a string.
And again, they're actually going to pass it over
to helloworld.jsp in the background.
So let's go ahead and copy this request mapping
and drop it in here.
So for request mapping, it's gonna be a /processForm,
so that's where the HTML is going to send it over
to this request mapping that I have listed on line 17.
And this is again, annotating this map we have
on line 18, processForm.
All right, so that's the real key.
That's the real glue here for pulling it all together.
And that's basically it so far, so this method's in place.
It can handle that web request.
But now, we need to actually write the code here
for our view template for helloworld.
And we'll go ahead and do that now.
So in our view folder, we'll just do a right click,
and we'll say new, file.
And the actual name of the file
we'll call it helloworld.jsp.
And then we'll move down,
and we'll hit the finish button.
And I'll go ahead and just knock out my very basic HTML
header information real quick.
Body.
And now, I'll just print out some text here.
Hello world of spring.
Give some line breaks here.
And now I'll simply read the form data,
so I'll say student name, colon, and I'll read it
by using a JSP expression language.
I use the dollar sign, param.studentName,
so studentName's the actual name of the HTML form field.
We can read form field data in JSP
by using dollar sign, param, dot, whatever that exact
form field name is.
And I have a little typo here.
Hell, world of spring.
That's bad.
I meant to say, hello world of spring.
'Cause everything is great with spring.
No such thing, okay.
All right, so that looks good.
So that's our actual HTML form.
So let's go ahead and save this file.
Let's get ready to run it.