Alrighty, so let's go ahead
and run our application, I think we're ready
to test this thing out!
So we'll right-click on our project
and we'll choose Run As and run on the server!
Alright, so here's our page.
Now let's go ahead and enter /showForm
in the URL up top and hit enter.
Okay, great, there's our page.
So let's go ahead and enter a student name.
So I'll enter the student name of John
and I'll hit the submit button
and whoo-hoo, there we go.
Hello World of Spring, and student name
John, and John's the actual form data that we entered
so we're able to read
form data with Spring MVC, ya-hoo!
Alright, I'm having too much fun over here.
But one thing I wanna do is actually kinda
clean this up a bit, so that I don't have to enter
the show form every time.
I liked to be able to just have a link
that they will simply click and go to this form
just to kinda clean it up, make it a bit more professional.
So what I'm gonna do is actually move over
to this main-menu.jsp.
So this is the first page that's shown
whenever we run our project.
And I'm gonna set up an html link.
So here I'll set up
a little label here saying hello world form,
and then I will put an actual link for it here,
so a href equals
and then this will simply go to show form.
And then we'll put the end anchor tag at the end
and that's it, so now we'll have this Hello World form
show up as a hyperlink, and when they click it,
it'll go to show form.
It's the actual request mapping in our
Spring MVC code.
So here, let me just remove that show form at the beginning
of the URL, and hit enter.
And great, so that's our home page
and note the new link here, whoo-hoo!
Looking good, looking good.
And then let's click this link and
magic (chuckle) shows the form.
Nothing really fancy, this is very basic html 101.
But anyway, we've kinda cleaned up our example a bit
so that we don't have to manually enter information
in the URL.
Enter the student name Billy, hit submit,
and everything works out as desired.
So anyway, just wanna kinda go full circle
building out that example, reading form data,
and then finally here at the end,
we just added a hyperlink to actually
automatically show the form
and end process on it, so
good example, I'm happy.
I hope you're happy.
We made some very good progress here.
So I'll see you in the next video.