In this video, we're gonna learn
about adding data to the spring model.
So the main focus here is on the model.
So far, we've covered the controller code.
We've covered view templates.
But we didn't really talk about the model,
and so that's where we're gonna kind of zoom in here,
and see how we can use it, how we can add data to it,
and also how we can read data from the model.
It's all about the model right now.
So the spring model is really just a container
for your application data.
So in your controller code, you can put
anything in the model.
You can put in strings, objects, information
that you get from the database, et cetera.
And you can load it up.
And then your actual view page, or your JSP,
can actually access data from the model.
So what I'll do here is I'll actually walk
through a code example.
So I'm gonna create a new method to process form data.
I'm gonna read the form data.
And then I want to convert the form data to all upper case.
And then I'll add this upper case version of the data
to the model, and then we'll display it in the page.
When we make use of our spring controller,
we can actually pass the model to our controller,
and we can also read form data in our controller.
So what I'm gonna do here is create this new method
called letsShoutDude 'cause I'm gonna shout
and use everything in all caps.
That's just my little joke here.
And we're gonna set up a request mapping up top,
so the name of this request will be processFormVersionTwo.
All right so our method letsShoutDude
we're gonna pass in two parameters.
So in spring and receive, when you create your controller
methods, they're actually very flexible on the parameters
you can pass in, so if you need to read form data
in your controller code, then you pass
in the HttpServletRequest.
And it's working like the normal servlet request
that you've learned already.
And also, you can pass in the model.
So again, the model is just a container
that can hold your form data.
When the model comes in initially, it's empty,
and you can add data to it.
So let's kind of walk through this code here step by step.
So the first thing we want to do is read the request
parameter from the HTML form.
The form has a field name called studentName.
I simply say request.getParameter, studentName.
That allows me to read that form data,
and I simply assign it to a variable here called theName.
Now, in my little example, I want to convert the name
to all upper case, so I simply say theName.toUpperCase,
and assign it to itself.
So now I have an all caps version of the name,
kind of the way of shouting.
In the online world we always say
if you type in all caps, it's shouting.
So that's why we have this whole little shouting thing
going on here. (laughs)
Then, we're gonna create a message.
So our message is gonna be simply, yo,
and then whatever the person's name is.
Like, yo, Pauly.
Yo, Andrian.
Okay.
And that'll give us the message or the result.
So now that I have the result, I want to add
this message to the model.
So to add something to the model, I say model.addAttribute,
and the attribute I give the actual name
of the attribute, comma, the value.
So the name here is message, and the actual value is result.
So result is the object that we just created
on the previous line.
Now, the actual name of the attribute message,
you can give any name you want for the attribute.
You can call it fubar, funny, silly.
It's totally up to you as long as you're consistent
in other parts of your application.
And that's it for actually adding data to the model.
And then finally, I say return helloworld.
It'll go off to that helloworld.jsp page.
So that's the basic coding there for passing the model
to your controller and also adding data to the model.
All right, now in my actual view page, or my JSP,
I can access data from the model.
In order to access data from the model,
I simply make use of the dollar sign curly brace,
and I give the actual model attribute name.
So in the previous example, we set something
with the attribute name of message.
I can access it using that same name, message,
and whatever data was placed there,
it'll be displayed right here on the screen.
So that's the key there.
So in your controller, you add an attribute
with the given name.
In your JSP page, you can display it
using that same attribute name.
And then finally you may have the question, well,
what if I need to add more data?
What if it's more than just one item?
Well, you can add as much data here
as you'd like to the model.
All you do is you simply call addAttribute
X number of times.
So in this example, I have, up top I get data.
I have three variables:
results, theStudentList, theShoppingCart.
Then, I can add that data to the model.
I simply say model, addAttribute, message,
attribute, student, addAttribute, ShopingCart.
So that's it.
So you simply give your name, value pair
that you're adding for a given attribute,
and you can continue doing that X number of times.
So that's the basic process.
All right, so this is good stuff here.
Let's go ahead and move into Eclipse,
and let's get our hands dirty.
Let's go bang out some code.
So I'll see you there.