Alrighty,
so let's go ahead and move into Eclipse here
and we are actually going to add some
methods to our HelloWorldController to handle that new
example code that we want to set up.
So let's go ahead and move into HelloWorldController
and let's expand the window here
and clear out some white space
and again I always like to write a little comment
to kind of keep myself on track as far as what I need to do.
So we're going to add a new controller method
to read form data
and also add data to the model.
So that's kinda our game plan as far as what we need to do.
So let's go ahead and define that method here letsShoutDude.
We're going to shout in all caps.
So we passing those two parameters the httpServerRequest
and also the Model.
We're going to return, "helloworld".
So that'll go back over to our helloworld.jsp.
So that's the basic stub here, for this method.
Let me slide over here and fix some of these imports.
So I'll fix the import httpServerRequest
and also fix the import for Model,
that's from the Spring Framework.
Alright, so let's just copy that @RequestMapping
from line 21
and let's move down
and let's paste it in right above our
letsShoutDude method.
Alright, clean up that extra white space there.
Okay, cool.
So we're going to change the RequestMapping path
to processFormVersionTwo.
So a unique path, where,
and we'll actually update our form
to point to this path also.
Alright so that's kinda the basic layout here
for this controller method,
but we still need to kind of fill in the blanks
and do some stuff inside.
So before I start writing code, as far as what I need to do,
I'll actually write some comments (laughs).
Again, I love to keep myself on track here.
So the first thing we need to do is
read the request parameter from the HTML form,
then I need to basically convert that data to all uppercase
because I want to shout.
Then we'll actually create our message.
So I'll say like, "Yo, dude.",
and finally I'm gonna add that message to the model.
So that's kind of the basic game plan of what I want to here
in this code
and it's very similar to what we had in the slides.
So again to read the form data
we simply say request.getParameter
and we give the actually form filled name of studentName
and then we actually go through
and convert this data to all caps.
I say theName.toUpperCase
and then next go through and I create the message.
So I'll say result equals
and I'll say "Yo!"
and I'll concatenate it with thename
and then the important thing here
is adding this to the model.
So I'll say model.addAttribute
and I give the actual name comma value.
The name of the attribute is "message"
and the value is result.
So that's the information from the previous line
that we just set up.
So that's kind of the main piece here,
adding data to the model.
So that's it for our method.
So we have this new RequestMapping processFormVersionTwo
we take in some parameters, we read the form data,
convert the names to uppercase, create a new message,
and add that to the model.
So this looks good so far.