Alright, so our controller's
pretty much taken care of.
Now let's go ahead and update our view page,
so we can access information from the model.
So I'll move back over to my web (mumbles) view,
and I'll look at the file here, helloworld.
So, that's helloworld.jsp.
And, I will add
some line breaks here.
Then I wanna read data from the model.
So, we can expand the window here for a second.
Give myself some white space here at the bottom.
And, I'll say the message.
And, now to actually access the message,
or read that model data,
I use dollar sign, curly brace, message.
So again,
I wanna use dollar sign, curly brace, in this case message,
it's actually gonna access
a attribute from the model.
So, whatever we place in there,
under the name of message,
or the key of message,
it's gonna actually retrieve that information
and display it right here on the page.
And, now one other thing
we need to do is modify our form,
or update our form
to now point to this new version of our process.
Because in our controller,
if we flip back over here, for a second,
that new code we just added,
this is for processFormVersionTwo.
Okay, that's a request mapping.
Also, if you copy that request mapping,
and I'll move back over to my form
and I'll paste that information in.
I like to do a copy paste
to make sure I don't have
any typo problems or errors,
'cause it's very case sensitive.
Alright, so there we go.
So, that's our form that's updated.
processFormVersionTwo.
Alright, so I'll save everything.
Let's go ahead and run this real quick.
So right click, choose run as,
and run on server.
Alrighty, so I can go ahead
and make use of the hypertext link
that we set up in the previous video,
which is cool.
And, I can go ahead and enter my student name.
My student name of Larry, hit submit.
And, there we go.
Hello World of Spring,
student, Larry.
And, now the message, this is our new stuff.
Yo Larry, okay.
So, we're shouting at Larry.
We took his name and converted it to all caps,
and we put yo on the front,
but actually I notice
I have little typo here
in my message, itself.
Yo, Larry.
There's no white space
between the words.
So, I'll show you this lil feature here.
So, if I need to make a modification
to my spring code,
I can make the change...
So, I'll enter a space here.
So, yo, space, the name,
then I can save this file,
and if you watch the console,
spring has a little...
Actually this is Tomcat.
Tomcat will basically check your code
to see if there were any modifications.
And, it'll run like every five or ten seconds.
But, note here, it just fired up,
so it noticed some changes
on the file system.
It's gonna reload your new version
of your controller,
and then you're ready to go.
So, the reload has been completed.
And, now there's no need
for us to stop the server
and start it again.
Tomcat automatically reloaded our new code
by simply saving
our controller code.
So, now if I go back to my browser,
I click on the back button
and I can keep the same name, I guess,
hit submit,
then it says yo, space, Larry. (chuckles)
So, notice here we made a modification
to our controller source code.
We saved it.
Tomcat is smart enough to notice
that we made a change to that file.
Tomcat automatically reloaded our application,
and we had our latest code ready to go.
So, this is cool.
So anyways,
we did some good stuff here.
We added data to the spring model.
So, I wanna say congrats.
Give yourself a pat on the back.
And, good job, so far.
You are rocking and rolling, dude.
Yo. (laughing)
Alright, I'm having too much fun again.
I'll see you in the next video.