In this video,
we're gonna discuss Spring MVC form tags.
So we all know about html forms, right?
Basically if you have to log into a system,
you have to enter your information via a form,
or if you use like a travel site
to travel from a given city to a destination,
you make use of a form.
So we'll learn how to use forms with Spring.
And in particular,
Spring has support for form tags,
and these are form tags that are configurable,
and you can reuse them on a webpage.
Now you may wonder,
"Well we've already created forms using Spring."
Well these Spring MVC form tags,
they give you an extra support.
They support data binding,
so this allows you to automatically set data
and retrieve data from Java objects and beans.
All right, so let's take a look at the Spring MVC form tags.
These form tags will actually generate html for you,
so they'll do a lot of the heavy lifting behind the scenes.
There's also some other special features that they'll add.
I'll talk about that in a second.
But basically here's a list of the tags.
So you have the main form tag,
and you also have the input tag for text fields.
There's a text area for multi-line text fields,
check box, radio buttons,
and there's also the select tag for doing a drop down list.
And there's many more.
So in this video series,
I'll cover the most commonly used form tags,
and you'll see it all in operation
and we'll write all the code from scratch
and we'll do it all step by step.
If you'd like to get more documentation on these tags,
you can simply go to my website here,
luv2code.com/spring-mvc-form-tags,
and I'll redirect you to the official documentation
for the Spring MVC form tags.
All right, now how's the web page structure set up?
Well you basically make use of a normal JSP page
and then you simply drop in the Spring MVC form tags.
So you have your regular html stuff,
Spring MVC form tags,
and then more html.
So you can easily mix 'em in
to your existing web page content.
Now how do you reference these tags in the JSP file?
Well basically at the beginning of your file,
you make use of this tag lib reference.
You have prefix equals form,
and then you give the uri
and solicit here on the slide.
And once you have that set up,
then you can make use of those tags on the JSP page.
All right, so that's an overview
of the Spring MVC form tags.
In the following videos,
we'll start to drill down into some of the tags,
then we'll set 'em up and see how they work
and just test 'em out.
So I'll see you in the next video.