In this video,
we're gonna use the Spring MVC form tag for text fields.
So here's the big picture.
We're gonna have a form that's gonna have two text fields
for first name and last name.
The user will enter that information, they'll hit submit,
it'll pass it over to our controller,
and then our controller will send the user to
a confirmation page.
So in our Spring controller, before we show the form,
we must add a model attribute.
So this is basically a bean
that's gonna be used to hold the form data,
and this will give us support for data binding.
So we'll actually bind form data to our bean.
All right, so here's the code snippet from our controller
for actually showing the form.
So when we show the form, we need to add a model attribute.
So here I have showForm.
This method takes a new parameter here
called Model, theModel.
And remember, theModel is an object that we can use to
kind of pass data around between controllers and views.
So here what I'll do is I'll say,
theModel.addAttribute.
I give the model name of student
and then the actual value of new Student.
So, think with me, I'm creating a new Student object,
I'm creating an empty Student object
that I'll pass to the form
for the form to make use of with data binding.
Now, the important thing here is that,
when I give the addAttribute,
the attribute name of student,
that's the same name that our form will use
to reference this model attribute.
So that part of it is really important,
and we'll see this on the next slide
when we look at the coding for our form.
All right, so here's our form.
So we're making use of the Spring MVC form tag.
So I say form:form, I give the action,
and then the modelAttribute= student.
Again, that's the same attribute name
that I used on the previous slide
for writing the code for showing this form,
and then I go ahead and just list out
my two text fields here.
First name, I give form:input,
that will generate a text field.
I'll set the path to firstName.
Last name, form:input, path= lastName,
and finally, a submit button.
Now, you're probably wondering,
what's up with the path= firstName
and the path= lastName, kind of how does that map out?
Well, this actually binds this form field
to a property on the bean.
When the form is first loaded,
what Spring MVC will do behind the scenes is that
they'll actually use this to populate the form field.
When they have path= firstName,
Spring MVC will call student.getFirstName,
and they use that model attribute from up top to
retrieve that data.
If it's null, then that form field will simply be empty.
So in our case of creating a new student from scratch,
then it'll be empty,
but you can easily prepopulate that
accordingly if you'd like.
We'll do a similar thing here for last name,
form:input path= lastName.
Behind the scenes, Spring MVC will call student.getLastName.
Now, when the form is submitted,
Spring will actually call the setter methods.
All right, so they're real simple.
When they submit, they call setter methods.
So here for first name, form:input path= firstName,
Spring will call student.setFirstName
and only use whatever data the user
entered there in the form field.
A similar thing for last name, student.setLastName.
Again, Spring will call the setter methods
when they actually submit the form.
All right, so the form data's been submitted.
Now, how do we actually read the data in our controller?
Well, in our controller,
we can simply make use of a new Spring annotation called
@ModelAttribute, and we give the name of the attribute.
So again, we're using student, in all lower case.
They'll actually bind that object
to this parameter being passed in theStudent.
Some work behind the scenes,
Spring will actually take that model attribute
and bind it to this variable here, theStudent,
and we can use it in our controller.
So here, I simply log the input data, I simply say,
theStudent, I say, theStudent.getLastName and
whatever else I wanted to do.
And here I simply return to student-confirmation page.
But the key here is that Spring will actually
take all that form data,
bind it automatically to your object,
and then pass it into your controller
so you can make use of it.
So there's no need for you to do the manual
request.get parameter for each one of the fields.
Spring will handle all of that work for you,
and that's the real benefit
of using the Spring MVC form tags,
is they have actual data binding,
and that's the part that I just love, I love it.
All right, good stuff.
All right, so at the bottom here,
we return the confirmation page.
So let's go look at the confirmation page real quick.
So here we simply say the student is confirmed,
and then we simply use our dollar sign, curly brace,
student.firstName, student.lastName.
So again we're using the model attribute name
and then we actually access those properties accordingly
by calling get.firstName, get.lastName.
All right, and that's it.
That's our confirmation page and we're good to go.
So we covered a lot of stuff there.
I kind of want to step back for a second and
pull it all together.
So we had our form up front.
They would submit data to our controller,
our controller will take that data, process it,
and then pass it off to the confirmation page.
All right, so that was a lot of work there.
What we're gonna do in the next video,
is that we'll actually go through our development process
and we'll walk through it step-by-step.
So the first thing we'll do is we'll create a Student class,
then we'll create a Student controller class,
next we'll create an HTML form,
then we'll build a form processing code,
and finally, we'll create the confirmation page.
So we'll take care of all of this in the next video.
So I'll see you over there.