Let's go ahead and move into Eclipse.
We're gonna work through our development process
and we're gonna do everything step by step
and we'll build it all from scratch.
The first thing we're gonna work on
is step one, creating the Student class.
What I'll do here is I'll move down
to my Java Resources directory,
to my source directory, to my package
and I'll do a right click and I'll say, New, Class.
The actual name that I'll give for this class,
I'll call it Student.
Real simple.
I'll keep all the other defaults and I'll hit Finish.
We have our basic class here.
I'll expand the window.
This Student is gonna have two fields.
It's gonna have a firstName and a lastName.
I've also set up a no argument constructor for our Student.
Now what I need to do is actually generate
some getter and setter methods for this Student.
Again, I'll make use of that Eclipse trick
where I'll simply just do a right click
and I'll go to Source, Generate Getters and Setters.
Eclipse will bring up the dialog.
I'll go ahead and check the box here
for firstName and lastName and that'll generate
getters and setters for both of those.
I'll go ahead and keep all the other defaults
and I'll hit OK.
Again, Eclipse does a lot of great work for us.
It generates all this great code for us.
So there you have it.
We have getFirstName, setFirstName
and getLastName, setLastName.
All right, we're good to go.
That's basically it for this Student class.
I can save this, move out.
Moving over to step two is creating
a Student controller class.
So that's our spring-mvc controller.
Again, I'll go to my package,
I'll do a right click, I'll say New, Class.
And again, as you'd expect,
the name here will be StudentController.
And then again, we'll keep all the other defaults
and then we'll hit the Finish button.
So here's our controller and this is where
we have to actually do our work.
Up top we set up some annotations.
We basically say it's @Controller.
And we also set up the RequestMapping for this one.
Everything's gonna be based off of /student.
Swing over here and fix the imports real quick.
The first thing we need to do is
actually create a method for actually showing our form.
So I'll go ahead and give the method name ShowForm.
It's gonna take the parameter from Mode, theModel.
And I'll just go ahead and do a
quick return to say return student-form.
That'll actually return it back to the student-form.jsp.
I'll fix the imports here for Model.
So we took care of all the dotting the I's
and crossing the T type stuff.
I'll also set up the annotation up top for Request Mapping.
So this'll be /showForm.
On the inside of my Method I'll just write
some quick comments here to kind of keep myself on track
as far as what I actually need to do in this item.
Again, remember we're using forms here,
so we're gonna make use of a Model attribute.
The first thing I need to do here
is create a new student object.
And then I need to actually add that student object
as a Model attribute.
So I basically add it to the model.
So those are the comments there.
I have a good feel for what I need to do.
Let's go ahead and start cutting some code.
Creating the Student, we simply say
theStudent = new Student.
Again, very simple Java coding there.
Now we need to add this to the model,
so I'll say theModel.addAtrribute.
I'll give the actual name of the attribute
and the actual value for the attribute.
So we create the Student object
and then we add it as an attribute,
giving the name of Student and the value of theStudent.
That's the object that we created on line 15.
That's basically it here for this showForm
that we simply create our object,
add it to the model and then we simply
do a return over to student-form
and that'll pass it over to student-form.jsp.
This looks good so far.