Alrighty, so our next step
is that we actually need to create the HTML form.
That's gonna have our input fields and our submit button,
and all that good stuff.
So, let's go ahead and swing back over
to our project structure here.
And let's go move into
yeah so we're gonna click this file,
called student form.
So, let's go into WebContent,
WEB-INF view.
Let's do a right click here and say New File.
Alrighty, so the name of the file
is student-form.jsp.
And then, we'll go ahead and click on the Finish button.
Okay, great so our very empty file right now.
Let's go ahead and take care of some of the,
actually, the important thing here is
taking care of taglib reference up top,
so make sure you end the taglib reference
like I have here on the screen.
Make sure you get the uri exactly
like I have here on the screen
'cause that'll help resolve any problems that you may have.
So, once that's in place,
I always like to do a copy-paste on it,
but you can go ahead and type it in,
but make sure it matches here on the screen.
Now, let's go ahead and take care of some of our
HTML
infrastructure or basic stuff we have to do.
I'll set up the head and the title,
Student Registration Form.
I'll set up the body,
and that's kind of just the basic structure here
for our HTML page.
I'll stretch out here at the bottom.
Give me some white space just so I can kind of stretch out
and move around a bit.
Then, basically, what I'm gonna do here is actually
go through and start creating the form.
Alright, so use form:form.
Again, we're using the Spring MVC form tags,
the actual action of processForm.
And then, I'll get the modelAttribute=student.
Now, remember this modelAttribute is very important
because it must match what the actual code we used
in our controller.
So, in our controller, we gave the attribute name of student
in all lower case.
Same thing here for the form.
Those have to match up.
Okay, great.
So, now, let's go ahead and start cutting out the form,
basically just setting up
an input field here for first name.
I will say form:input,
and then, we'll give the path=firstName.
And again, first name's a property of the student class
because we have Getter Setter methods for first name.
I'll just do a little copy paste here.
I'll just kinda copy line 15
and I'll move down and I'll paste it.
Actually, I'll copy 15 through 17.
I'll paste it right here,
and I'll change this to Last name,
as the label,
and also, I'll change the input path to LastName.
And again, that's the actual property of the student class
for Getter Setter methods.
Alrighty, so this looks good so far.
Let's go ahead and add our input type for our submit button.
So, that's the actual button the user will click
to send the data over.
And now, that's in place.
So, this looks pretty good so far,
and it's some simple editing there,
as far as alignment,
but the important thing here is that when we load the form,
Spring MVC will call the Getter method,
so they'll call getFirstName, getLastName.
And a similar thing, when we submit the data,
Spring will call student.setFirstName, setLastName.
So, when they load, they call Gets.
When you submit, they call Sets.
Just remember that, remember that.
Alrighty, now let's go ahead and take care of step four,
creating the form processing code.
So, that's code that's back in our controller,
so I'll move back over to our StudentController.java.
And I need to go through
and actually define a new method here.
So, I'll first start off with the RequestMapping,
here the actual path, and that's the same thing
that we had on the form.
So, /processForm,
and then actually go through
and actually define my method here.
So, I'll call it processForm.
Again, our method name can be anything.
The important thing is the annotation.
Now, I set up the process form.
I set up ModelAttribute, Student, theStudent,
and remember they're actually gonna bind that ModelAttribute
to the parameter being passed in.
Now, I still have to do a return on student-confirmation,
so remember this will actually send it over
to studentconfirmation.jsp.
And we saw all of this on the slides.
We're just kinda cutting it,
cutting the code ourselves,
just to make sure that we can get everything working.
I'll go ahead and fix the import here on ModelAttribute.
And also, just as a reminder here on that
@ModelAttribute, so when they send it over,
that form data is gonna populate this student object
and then we can access it.
So, on the form, they have the modelAttribute of student.
Here, on our code, we use the same name with the same case.
And Spring does all the work behind the scenes
of populating that student object with all the data.
So, there's no need for us to manually do a request
on Get parameters.
Spring will just push everything in there.
I love it.
That's the nice feature of using Spring MVC.
Alright, so we can go ahead and do my System.out.println.
I'm just gonna print out some of the data
that came in, just to make sure
that Spring actually did populate it.
(chuckles)
Make sure that it's doing its work, as it's advertised.
So, here, I'll say theStudent.getFirstName,
and then, I'll just drop down a line here.
Give myself a white space,
and then, I say, theStudent.getLastName.
So, again, I just want to prop the information
to the console,
just to make sure that the controller gets the data,
and they can make use of it accordingly.
Alright, so that's basically the code there
for processing the form data.
Looks really good so far.
Good job.