Alrighty, so we're making some really good progress here.
So, our final step here was creating the confirmation page,
so we simply want to display the information
on the webpage as far as what the user entered.
So we'll create this file here called student confirmation.
So let me swing back over to the directories here
on the web view and I'll just do
a right click on this folder and I'll say
new file.
An actual name of the file,
I'll call it studentconfirmation.jsp.
I'll hit finish, and actually what I want to do is
copy some of the basic html stuff
from our other student form,
I don't want to type it all again.
I'm getting a little lazy here,
so I'll just copy all the doctype header body stuff.
Just do a copy on that
and I'll just swing over to my confirmation page
and just do a paste
and then I'll just do a /body/html there.
Cool. Alright, good.
So, that's the basics there and instead of
student registration form,
I'll say student confirmation.
Cool.
So it takes care of all the regular stuff.
Now, I simply want to give the
confirmation message here.
So I'll say, "The student is confirmed."
And basically I need to give the student's
first name and last name.
So I use the dollar sign curly brace
student.firstName then a space with
dollar sign curly brace student.lastName.
So again, remember here, they'll simply
call student.getFirstName
and likewise they'll call student.getLastName.
That will give us the output here
for this confirmation page,
which you've seen all this before,
this is really simple for you now.
You're an expert now.
This is easy. Easy, easy.
Alright good, so this looks really good.
We're in good shape.
I think we're at the point where
we can actually go through and
test out the application.
Actually, there's one thing I wanna do.
I wanna go back and actually change our main menu.
I wanna add a link there to the main menu
to point to this new form that we just created,
so let's go ahead and open up main-menu.jsp
and update our links.
So here it is.
So we currently have a link for the Hello World form,
I'll add some BRs, some line breaks here.
I'll copy this href from line 10.
I'll paste it on line 14
and now instead of Hello, this will be
student/showForm and I'll call it student form.
So on our main menu, we simply have
a link that will take us directly to our student form.
Alright, so this is really shaping up
to be a nice little app.
I'm happy.
I'm happy I'm getting excited.
I think I can start running it now, yeah.
Alright, let's go ahead and move to our app.
Let's bring the MDC demo, right click,
choose run as, and then run on server.
Alright, so the app is up.
There's our new link for our student form.
Let's go ahead and click that link.
Shows our form, so we just enter
our first name and our last name, John Doe.
And let's hit the submit button.
Cool, so there's our confirmation page,
the student is confirmed.
Now we've done a lot of this stuff earlier in the class,
but now we're actually making use of
Spring MVC Form Tags and we're also making use of
@ModelAttribute to bind form data to java objects.
And that's really cool.
We're making use of this data binding here in Spring.
Oh and also let's take a peek here
at our output for our controller.
So, when we log that information,
it's showing up right here in the console window
for that controller output,
so this is cool also.
I'm happy, I'm excited.
So we kind of walked through this whole
developmental process and we did it step by step.
So we created our student class, controller,
form, processing code, and finally,
our confirmation page.
So, good job with everything.
Woohoo.