In this video,
we'll cover the Spring MVC form tag for drop Down list.
So here's just a quick review
of the original HTML &lt;select&gt; tag.
You can have a form that has a dropdown list.
A user can go through and select their favorite country
and then hit submit.
So I have India selected here.
In the bottom right, that's the original HTML text
that you would use for displaying this dropdown list,
simply a &lt;select&gt; tag with multiple options.
Now in the Spring MVC world,
the dropdown list is represented by the tag &lt;form:select&gt;.
So let's take a look at how to use the &lt;form:select&gt;.
Basically, you specify the path that this binds to.
In this case, &lt;form:select path="country"&gt;,
and then you give your options,
and you give the value labels.
The label is what the user will actually see on the screen.
The value is the actual code that you'll pass over
when they submit it.
In this case, my values and labels are the same,
but your value can easily be a code,
like the three letter country code for a given country.
But that's basically how you use the dropdown list
in Spring MVC.
Alright, so let's go ahead and pull it all together.
We'll have a student form.
We'll basically add a dropdown list to that form.
We're gonna send it over to our student controller,
which will in turn pass it across to the confirmation page,
and once we're on the confirmation page,
we'll simply display the value
that the user selected from that dropdown list.
Okay, so we'll move into the clips,
and we'll do all this from scratch,
and we'll get our hands dirty.
So I will see you in the next video.