All right, so let's go ahead
and move into Eclipse, three steps here:
updating our HTML form, updating our student class
and also updating our confirmation page.
So, let's go ahead and start with Step One,
updating the HTML form.
So, I'll go into our View
and I'll find our student-form.jsp,
I'll double-click that file and open it up,
stretch it out and I'll move down here,
right below Last name,
I'm gonna add a new entry here for country
because I want to have a little drop-down list for country.
So, I'll just copy the br's there for a second
and I'll just zoom in.
I'll go ahead and enter the label here, Country,
and then I'll set up my form:select
and I'll set the path equals="country"
and then I'll do a /form:select.
All right, so that looks good, so far.
So, now, I need to give 'em some options
for the drop-down list, so I'll say form:option
and then I give value= and then I give label=
and for right now, I'll just make it an empty string.
I'm just gonna copy paste this x number of times,
'cause I, you know, I have a lot of coding here to do,
so, again, I'm being lazy.
So, I'll just copy paste that
and now I'll just go ahead and enter the values here
for the different countries.
So, I'll start with value for Brazil,
copy paste that for label and then I'll go ahead
and kind of speed the video up here for a second.
I'll do a similar thing for France, Germany and India.
All right, so there we go,
so we have this drop-down list set up
and the important thing here is
that when we actually do a submit,
Spring MVC is gonna call,
it's gonna call student.setCountry,
so we'll have to make sure
that our java object has support for that.
So, that's actually our next step here, Step Two.
We're going to add the property to the Student class.
So, I'll move over to,
over here to my Java source code, under Resources,
student.java, beam it up.
All right, so let's move into student.java.
We're going to add a new field,
so this is gonna be a field for Country, which is a String,
so I'll say private String country;
so that's the new field that we've added,
but now we need to expose it as a property
by using those getter setter methods.
So, let me kind of move down to the bottom of this file
and I make use of my right-click.
Then, I'll go to Source
and I'll say Generate Getters and Setters.
And, I'll kind of zoom in, here, and I'll chose country,
so that's the field
that we want to generate getters and setters for
and I'll kind of zoom out and hit OK.
All right, so there we go,
so we have our new methods here, getCountry, setCountry.
So, again, when they submit the data,
they're gonna call student.setCountry.
Okay, we're in good shape, here.
Now, Step Three is updating the confirmation page,
so, basically, once they've submitted their data,
we at least want to tell the user, "Hey, you selected X."
All right, so I'm gonna go ahead
and add a little linebreak here
and also I want to display the actual student.
So, stretch out a bit
and I'll say, Country,
and I'll say, :student.country
and, again, remember it's gonna call student.getCountry
'cause were using the jsp expression language
and that'll basically display
whatever the user selected on that form.
Alrighty, so this looks pretty good, so far.
Let's go ahead and test it out.
Let's run it, run it.
So, I'll just right-click, Run As, Run on Server
and there's our link to our form, select the link
and, now, we have our drop-down list.
Woo hoo, looks pretty, looks fancy, let's check it out.
Let's check it out.
So, I'll go ahead and enter the name John Doe
and then my drop-down list, Brazil, France, Germany, India.
Whew, I like it.
It looks good.
I'll choose Germany and I'll do a submit
and then there's our confirmation page.
Country, Germany, whatever the user selected on the form,
so this looks really good.
So, again, we made use of the Spring MVC form tag
for creating drop-down lists
and we read the data and put it on our confirmation page.