Alrighty so that was a good example
but what if we wanted to read the list of countries
from a Java class?
So instead of hard coding it,
let's read it from a Java class.
So basically, the first thing that we wanna do
is define country options in the class.
So, for the country options we'll simply
set up a linked hash map which is effectively
a collection of named value pairs in an ordered fashion.
So we'll have the country options so we'll
have the value and an actual label.
So, here this is a linked hash map.
In my constructor what I can do is go ahead
and construct or create that country options
and then I'll populate it with data.
So, when our spring embassy application runs
they'll actually read information from this class
as for a list of options as opposed to using it
hardcoded in the actual JSP page.
Now this is a simple example.
I'm simply placing it here in this file.
But, we could easily integrate this with reading
it from a file system, reading it from a database
or from a web service.
But here we're just gonna keep it simple for right now.
So, here's our country options.
Linked hash map and just the normal constructor there.
And now I'm gonna populate the country options.
So, I'm gonna make use of the ISO country code
and the actual country itself.
So, BR that's the actual code or value
and then Brazil is the actual label,
what the user will see, alright?
So, let me kind of copy/paste this x number of times
and I'll do this for the other countries here in my demo.
So, I'll have FR for France.
And then I'll--
Ya know the ISO country code for Germany
which is DE for Germany.
And then the country code for India, IN
and then the actual country itself, India.
So again, when you make use of the hash map
the first value is the actual code or key
and the second value is the actual value or label
that the user will see.
So those aren't country options.
Now, all we need to do here is really just create
just a getter method such that
Spring mvc can read that information.
So I'll simply do a right click here.
I'll say source and I'll say generate getters and setters.
But in this example, we only need the getter method
so I'll simply expand country options
and choose get country options.
And then I'll hit okay.
So, right here on line 50 through 52 is get country options
so when we show the forms, spring mvc will actually
call this method to use this to actually populate
or generate the drop down list.
Alright so let's go back over to our form now.
We're gonna actually use this.
So, we're gonna update our form.
So, instead of hard coding the values
here on the JSP page, we're gonna change this up a bit.
So here I'll say form:options.
Note the S there, plural.
And then I give items.
And so this is actually gonna be the actual method call
here for our country options.
So, here I'll say student.countryoptions.
That's the items and what they're
gonna use for populating it.
And so notice here, it's simply one in three
that country option's gonna return a list--
Sorry, a linked hash map of values
and it'll use it accordingly.
So that's basically it.
So when we have student.countryoptions,
it's actually gonna call student.getcountryoptions.
It's actually gonna use that getter method
that we just defined previously.
Alright so that's it there.
So, we can go ahead and save this file.
Just double check things look okay over here.
Yeah, let me get rid of the--
No, that's fine I'll keep that there.
So, that's good.
So, we're good to go here.
That looks fine.
I'm gonna add one more country here
just to make sure that we're getting new data.
Cause we have the same items here in the previous video.
Make sure that this is new data that we're retrieving here.
So, the U.S.
Alright, so that should be the last entry
that you see there in our drop down list.
Alrighty so let's go ahead and save that.
Let's go ahead and run this application again.
And go through our student form.
And I always like to hit the refresh button
here at the top just to make sure
we're getting the latest and greatest.
And hit my drop down list and boom.
I like it.
You see that?
United States as our last entry there.
So, we're reading all of our data from the Java class
and we're not hardcoding it in the JSP page.
Again, that Java class, we have the data listed there.
But again, that Java class could read it
from a database or a properties file
or some external service.
But, the key here now is that the JSP page
simply tells the class hey give me the options
and the class handles retrieving that data
and passing it back.
So, good job.
I hope this example was useful for you
and I hope you like it.
Alright, I'll see you in the next video.