In this video, we're gonna cover
Spring MVC Form Tags for radio buttons.
So here's a quick demo of radio buttons.
We'll enter the user's information.
And then they can choose their
favorite programming language.
So radio button, they can only choose one option.
They choose their one favorite language,
such as PHP in this example.
And then they can hit submit and then it will actually
show them the results on the confirmation page.
So their selected language there,
PHP, from that radio button.
Now, in the Spring MVC world, they have support
for radio buttons, and it's really simple here.
It's called form:radiobutton.
So let's look at a quick code example.
This is really simple.
So here, I'm gonna have radio buttons
for the four languages: Java, C#, PHP and Ruby.
We simply say, form:radiobutton,
path="favoriteLanguage", value="Java".
And the path="favoriteLanguage",
that's basically the property that we're binding
this radio button to, and that's basically it.
So they get to choose one of these options
and then we submit and then during the submission,
they'll call student.setFavoriteLanguage.
So we'll need to have a setter method there
to hold or handle this submission.
All righty, so that's basically it.
So what we'll do is we'll move into the clips,
we'll kind of pull it all together,
we'll add radio buttons to our form,
and then we'll display the results on our confirmation page.
So I'll see ya in the next video.