Alright let's move into Eclipse.
With our development process we're gonna update the form.
Update the Student class and our confirmation page.
So the first thing here is updating the form.
We've kind of gone through this drill before so it's
going to be very familiar to you so far.
So I'll just open up student-form.jsp.
So basically what I'm going to do here
is add a new entry here for our radio buttons
So I'll add another &lt;br&gt; here.
I'll just copy-paste line 31 and paste it on line 34.
Alright so what we'll do here is we'll set up
for our favorite language.
And then we'll set up our &lt;form:radiobutton&gt;.
And I'll set the path="favoritLanguage".
That's a property that we're gonna bind to our Java class
with getters and setters.
And then I'll set the value="Java".
Alright that's the basics there.
So again, remember when we submit on this form
they'll call student.setFavoriteLanguage and then I'll
pass in the selected item.
Alright cool, so let me just copy-paste line 35
x number of times.
I'm just copying that Java line and I'll just paste it
x number of times for the other languages here.
For C#, PHP and Ruby.
Just give me one quick second here I'll speed the video up
while I update the values here for C#, PHP and Ruby.
So we're kinda in good shape here.
So that's our radio button for favorite language.
Again remember, when they submit the data they're gonna call
student.setFavoriteLanguage.
I'm kind of happy here.
This looks good so far for our HTML form.
Alright so I'll save everything.
And now we need to move over to step two.
That's actually creating a property in our Student Class.
So we're gonna create a property here
for this favorite language.
We'll actually provide getter and setter methods
for that property.
So here I'll say private String favoriteLanguage.
So that's our actual field.
Then I'll scroll down a bit.
And right click here generate getters and setters.
So right click -&gt; Source -&gt; Generate Getters and Setters.
You know how to do all this stuff by now.
I don't even have to say anything.
You know what to do already.
You're an expert at this.
Alright so I'll just select both the options here.
Actually select the one option for favoriteLanguage.
And that'll generate the getter and setters
for favoriteLanguage.
Then I'll just hit ok.
Alright, so there we go.
Lines 57 through 63 getter/setter methods
for favoriteLanguage.
Alright so this looks good so far.
So let's go ahead and move up to our next step.
That's simply updating the confirmation page.
And again we're simply just gonna echo whatever the user
selected from the form.
So on my confirmation page I just need to add one more
little line break so I'll copy line 13.
Paste it here on line 17 and then I'll say Favorite Language
and again use the $.
And again you probably beat me typing that.
You already knew the answer.
So again, when here Spring will actually call
student.getFavoriteLanguage() cause we're simply displaying
the data here.
So this looks good, I'm happy so far.
So let's go ahead and run this application.
So I'll simply right click -&gt; Run As -&gt; Run on Server.
Zoom in a bit.
Click on the link for Student Form.
And we have our languages listed here at the bottom.
Radio buttons can only choose one.
Which language will I pick?
I'll fill in my other information here for the student.
And I'll hit submit.
And so there we go.
So student is confirmed, John Doe.
Favorite language of C#.
So this looks great.
Everything works kinda as desired.
So we can read radio buttons with Spring MVC.
Using those form tags and the data binding.