In this video, we're gonna cover
Spring MVC form tags for check boxes.
So, let's imagine the scenario
where we're gonna ask the student
"Hey, which Operating Systems do you have experience with?"
So, in this case they may not select only one,
they may have experience with multiple Operating Systems.
So, with check boxes you can check multiple items,
Linux, Mac or Windows, all three, one or two of 'em.
Very easy.
So, how do we do this with Spring MVC?
Well, a check box is represented using
the form:checkbox tag.
Very simple, very straightforward.
And you kind of get in the groove here.
Once you've seen one of the Spring form tags
you can kind of pick up how the others work.
So, here's an example here using check boxes.
You say, form:checkbox, you give the path
that we're gonna bind to, in this example operatingSystems,
and then the value equals Linux.
And you can repeat that process for the other fields here
for Mac OS and for Microsoft Windows.
So, the only difference here is
that for check boxes, they can choose more than one option.
So, in your Java class,
you're gonna have more than just a single field.
You'll have a field that's actually a collection
so it can hold multiple input items from the user
and in the following videos we'll dive into Eclipse
and I'll show you how to actually write the code for that.