Alrighty, so let's go ahead dive into Eclipse
and we'll follow that same process.
We'll update the form, we'll update our class, and then
finally update the confirmation page so again
you guys kind of see the development process
that we're using here.
And you're getting used to it by now.
So let's go ahead and open up our form.
On our form what we're going to do is actually
add checkboxes here for the
different operating systems.
And then we'll make use of that form:checkbox.
So let me just move it down to line 40.
I'll just copy that BR there
and I'll paste it here.
Now what I want to do is basically just give a
label here saying operating systems.
And then I'll just add some entries here
for the different OSs.
Like Linux, I'll say form:checkbox.
I'll give path equal.
This is going to bind to operating systems.
And the value equals Linux.
What I'll do is I'll actually copy this line
X number of times.
And again remember, they're going to call
student.setOperatingSystems.
So I'll just copy that line and I'll paste it.
Then I'll just make some quick updates here for Mac
and also a quick update here for Microsoft Windows.
There we go, so that's all lined up.
This looks pretty good so far.
So I need to create a field here for operating systems
and the appropriate getter setter methods.
And I'll go into Student.java.
I'll scroll down here and just add a new field
for operating systems, so private String,
operating systems.
Now, the important thing here is that,
again like I mentioned earlier,
they can select multiple operating systems,
so we need a collection.
In this case, we need to have an array of strings.
And then at the bottom here,
I'll generate my getter setter methods here
for that property or that field.
So, generate getters and setters.
Then I'll choose operating systems and I'll click OK.
Alright, so there we go, lines 67 through 73,
we have those getter and setter methods.
The setter methods is what Spring MVC will call
when they actually do a form submission.
Alrighty, so let's go ahead save that file.
Now, the one last thing we have to do is
just move over to our confirmation page and simply
display the operating systems that the user selected.
But it's going to be a little bit different now, right?
Because with the operating systems, they can have multiple.
So actually what we need to do is loop over
that array and print out the information.
So the first thing I need to do is
make use of the JSTL tags, the core tags,
that will give me that for each tag
for looping over a collection.
So I'll click that at the top.
And now down here, I'll just copy line 19 of the Rs,
paste them here, and I'm basically going to
loop over that array and then print out each item.
So I'll just make use of a bullet list
to display those different operating systems.
So the bullet list, I'll make use of UL, unordered list.
And then I'll give a collection of list items here
that you'll actually have for the given name.
So that's the basic layout there for doing a bullet list,
but I need to kind of add some code here
such that it will actually loop over it.
So I can add code by making use of JSTL,
so I use the c:forEach,
I give the variable equals temp,
so that's the variable name, and then the items.
So I'll say student.operatingSystems.
So that will basically call the getter method.
It'll say student.getOperatingSystems
and it will loop over that, get those values,
and we can kind of display them here.
So let me clean this up a bit.
Let's see, line 30, I actually want to use that
temporary variable that was passed in right there.
So, inside of here I want to say dollar sign temp,
so that will give me the temp variable.
It'll give me that element in the array
that I'm looping over right now.
So that's the basic coding there for kind of
looping over that array and displaying
the information on our confirmation page.
And here we're making use of the JSTL
to help us out with the looping.