Alrighty, so let's go ahead and run this.
This looks pretty good right now.
So I'll simply right click.
Choose run as, run on server.
All right, and so my app's up and running.
Go ahead and select the item there for student form.
I can enter some basic information there
for first name, last name.
Now, for operating systems, I'm gonna choose Linux and Mac,
so I'm choosing multiple operating systems here.
And I'll go ahead and hit submit.
And boom.
Oh, my gosh.
What the, happened here?
Oh, this is terrible.
This is awful.
What happened?
Ah.
It said operationSystems.
Ew.
Typo, young man.
Typo.
You know why, right?
You already, you saw this earlier.
And you caught it earlier.
And your code is fixed.
And your code is working, but mine's broken.
It's not working.
Ah.
So it's not operationSystems.
It's actually operatingSystems.
All right, that's my problem.
I didn't use the right property name.
So operationSystems.
That's bad.
That's wrong, very wrong.
'Cause if we look at our student.Java,
they're gonna call set operatingSystems,
but you know, there's a getter and a setter,
and there's no such thing as operationSystems.
It's operating.
I can't spell, blah.
All right.
So as developers, right, we waste most of our time
not on logic errors.
We waste most of our time on configuration errors and typos.
(laughs)
All right, so let's go ahead and fix that, operatingSystems.
So spring will call student.getOperatingSystems
to actually retrieve that data.
So that's what was going on there.
Ah.
Well, at least we fixed it.
That's the good thing.
I hate errors, but at least I like to solve 'em,
so I can continue moving on with my development.
All right, so I've saved that.
Now, if I simply go on back, and I'll just,
forms are already set up ready to go.
Let's just cross our fingers, and hit submit.
And boom, yeah, success baby.
Linux, Mac OS, that's great.
So it's working.
So we're looping over those operating systems.
That's like an array, and we're using
that JSTL for each tag.
And we're displaying our output.
I love it.
I'm happy.