In this video,
we're gonna learn how to perform custom validation
with Spring MVC.
So let me give you a quick demo here
of the custom validation.
So we're gonna have a form that has three fields
for first name, last name, and course code.
So I can go in and enter the first name, last name,
and a course code.
The course code is simply an identifier for a course.
Now we're gonna attach a custom business rule here
to this course code.
So if I hit Submit, notice it gives a validation error.
It says, "The course code must start with LUV,"
because we love to code.
So that's the custom business rule
that we're adding here for this course identifier.
So you'd have to go back
and add a course code that starts with LUV,
and then everything will work out just fine
when we hit the Submit button.
So this is great.
So notice our course code, and it starts with LUV.
That's our custom business rule that we just made up.
So I'll actually show you
how to write the code behind the scenes
that will allow Spring to perform the validation
using your own custom validation rule
or your own custom business logic.
So, with the custom validation,
as I mentioned, we're gonna create
our own custom business rule here.
So in our example,
the course code must start with LUV for Luv2Code.
And what we're gonna do,
Spring will actually call our custom validation rule,
and if there's an error,
then it will actually display it on the page.
So this custom validation is gonna return
a Boolean value of true or false
based on the code that the user entered on the form.
Alrighty.
So we'll actually do something really fun here.
We're gonna create a custom Java annotation from scratch.
So far, you've used some of the predefined validation rules
like @Min, @Max, but what we're gonna do here is
we're actually gonna create our own custom Java annotation,
and our custom annotation is gonna be called CourseCode.
So this is really some advanced Spring MVC work,
so you're in for a real treat in this video.
And as you can tell, I'm really excited
'cause this is some great stuff here.
So @CourseCode, this is a validation rule
that will actually apply to a given field.
So we'll have this field in our entity.
We'll call this field courseCode lowercase,
and then we'll add this annotation, @CourseCode
That's the custom annotation that we're gonna create.
This annotation, we can give it any name.
We can call it @FooBar, @Luv2Code, @CrazyStuff.
Any name you can give to this annotation.
This annotation is gonna take in two parameters here.
It's gonna take in
the actual value that I'm gonna start with
and then the actual error message
that's displayed on the HTML form.
And it's kind of parameterized right now,
but I'll show you how to write
all of the code for this annotation from scratch.
So again, a custom annotation
that we're gonna create ourselves,
some good, advanced material.
Now, we always have our step by step process for it.
So the first thing is creating the custom validation rule.
The second step is adding that rule to the customer class.
Then we display the messages to the HTML form.
And then we update our confirmation page.
So steps two through four,
you've done that many times before.
We're simply gonna focus on step number one,
creating that custom validation rule.
So I'll go ahead and drill down here
step by step on number one, creating the rule.
So step 1A is we have to create that CourseCode annotation,
creating it from scratch.
And then we need to create the CourseCodeConstraintValidator
This is where we'll actually place our own validation logic
or our own business rules to determine true or false
if the value passed in passes our validation.
So that's where we'll put our own custom logic.