Okay, so let's go ahead and look at step one,
creating the @CourseCode annotation.
Now first, I just wanna show you the usage example
of how we're gonna use our annotation.
So in your Entity class, you'll have a field
and then we'll make use of the @CourseCode annotation.
So we're gonna attach this validation rule
to this given field.
Then I'll pass in two parameters for it,
the value and the message.
So value's the actual value I'm gonna start with.
And then the message is the actual error message
that you can use on the HTML page.
All righty, so Step 1a: Creating the @CourseCode annotation.
So the first thing to notice here's that we're creating
this annotation.
Now, when you create an annotation, you make use
of some special syntax.
So here we have public @interface CourseCode.
Okay, so this is new.
So it's a special type of interface.
So use the @interface.
In effect, this is how you define a custom annotation
for anything in Java.
But here we're gonna use it for our Spring MVC.
So you use the @interface, so that's not a typo,
@interface, and then you give the name
of your annotation, CourseCode.
All right, so that's kinda the basic structure.
Then up top, we add some additional annotations
to describe this annotation.
So up top we have Constraint.
It's gonna be validatedBy and you give the actual class
that has the business rules for validating this process.
So CourseCodeConstraintValidator.class.
We'll cover that in Step 1b, that's coming up.
Then we have @Target.
So this basically says hey, where can you apply
this annotation or where can you list this annotation?
So here we're gonna say you can use this annotation
on a method or on a field, all right?
So either way, a method or a field.
Then for @Retention, it says all right,
this annotation that's here, how long should we retain it?
So there's different types here.
Here we're gonna say RetentionPolicy.RUNTIME
meaning keep this annotation in the compiled Java bytecode
so we can use it, and introspect on it, and instrument on it
during runtime.
All right, so that's the basics there with setting this up.
Now just taking a look at some other items here.
We actually have to setup parameters here
for this annotation.
And this annotation's gonna have to parameters:
value and message.
All righty, so now we'll actually add some
method declarations here.
So we have public String value.
That basically says this annotation has a parameter
called value.
Now if the user doesn't provide a value,
then we'll use the default value of LUV.
And then we'll also add another method here for message.
So public String message.
And if they don't give an actual message,
we'll default to must start with LUV to code.
Now you're probably wondering, well, hey,
why are you using these defaults in your passing
and values here?
Well, I wanna keep this annotation customizable.
I could've hardcoded those values in there,
but I wanna keep it customizable so we could actually
apply @CourseCode and give a different prefix.
I'll actually show you how we can customize the usage
of this annotation in the following video demos.
So I'm just kinda doin' a little work up front
just to make it easier for you a little bit down the ways,
which you'll see it all come together.
But that's the basics here on actually defining
the @CourseCode annotation.
So you have those annotations up top,
public @interface CourseCode,
and then the method list.
Now we're moving ahead here and we look at
the actual ConstraintValidator.
So this is the guy who actually has the business rules
that'll give you true, false if the actual value passes.
All righty, so CourseCodeConstraintValidator
implements ConstraintValidator, has generics
so they'll pass in the actual CourseCode annotation
and the actual type of data that we're validating against.
Then I setup my field here, private String coursePrefix.
And then I have public void initialize
so when they create this validator,
they actually initialize it so I get a handle
to the actual annotation that was passed in
and I say theCourseCode.value.
So that would give me the actual prefix that we're gonna use
to validate data against.
So this basically just sets everything up.
So our validator's up and running, it's ready.
Now someone can actually use it.
Someone can actually say hey, is the given value valid?
That takes us to this next method here, isValid.
So this is what Spring MVC will call at runtime
when they actually say hey, the user just submitted a form,
here's the data, is this data valid?
And then we apply our business rules to it.
So they'll call isValid
passing string to the code.
So the code is data from the form.
They'll also pass in a ConstraintValidatorContext.
That's just a helper class we can use to add additional data
or messages to later.
And then I go through and write my code.
So here I say if theCode is not equal to null,
then I check to see if theCode.startswith coursePrefix.
So whatever code the user entered on their HTML form,
I'm gonna see if it starts with our given prefix.
So say our prefix is LUV, L-U-V, I'll check to see
if their code starts with LUV.
I'll return true or false based on that.
And that's basically it how that works out.
The else block here says result equals true,
meaning that if the code passed in was empty,
then we simply just return true.
So that's the basic layout here for
the CourseCodeConstraintValidator.
Now I know it looks really scary, but don't worry.
We'll actually move into Eclipse and we'll actually break
this down piece by piece and we'll write it out
line by line so you'll understand how this all works out
for you, okay?
So I'll see ya in the next video.