All right, so let's go ahead
and dive into Eclipse here.
The first thing we're gonna do is our step 1A,
creating the @CourseCode annotation.
So I move over here to my project,
and I move down to the Java Resources directory,
on the source, and I'm actually gonna create
a package first.
So I'll simply right-click over here
and I'll say new package.
Because I want to kind of group
all my validation code in the same package here.
And I'll pretty much keep the same package structure.
I'll just say .validation.
So the full name here, .validation.
And once you're happy with that,
go ahead and click on the finish button.
Okay, great, now I have my validation package set up.
Now I need to add something to it, right?
So the first thing we're gonna do is add a new annotation.
Ooh, this is new, haven't done this before.
New Annotation.
So this will bring up the annotation dialog here
and you basically give the name of the annotation.
So our annotation is called CourseCode.
And that's the value that we'll enter there.
We'll keep all the other defaults here
and we will click the finish button.
Great, so notice here, Eclipse helped us out
by setting up our annotation note on line three
to have public @interface, right, that special notation,
@interface CourseCode.
All right, so this is the basics here.
So we need to set up some annotations
at the top of this annotation.
Somewhat recursive, huh?
All right, so we'll say @Constraint(validatedBy
and then we give the actually class
that's gonna be our constraint validator.
So we'll have a CourseCodeConstraintValidator
that we'll create in some later videos,
part of our step 1B.
And we give the .class for it.
And then we'll kind of scroll over here to the left
and we'll fix the import here for @Constraint.
That's out of the JavaX.validation package.
And we'll continue to have that little issue
on line five, just kind of leave it there for now.
We'll cover that in the following video, so don't worry,
don't fret right now.
Then we'll also say @Target.
Basically we're saying, hey, where can you apply
this new annotation that we're creating?
So here we'll say you can apply this annotation
on methods or you could also
apply this annotation on fields.
And so in our case, we basically want to apply it
to the field on our instance class
for doing our validation or a method.
So there it goes, that's the basics there,
and you can always go into the Java doc
and find all the other options available here.
But we'll just keep it simple for now.
So that's target, we'll do an import on target.
And then we'll do a similar thing for @Retention.
So this basically says, how long will the marked annotation
be stored or used?
So here we'll say the RetentionPolicy.RUNTIME.
So basically we say retain this annotation
in the byte code and also use it at RUNTIME by the JVL.
So we say at RetentionPolicy.RUNTIME.
All right, so that's kinda the basics here
for our annotation, so we have our imports up top,
we have everything taken care of.
Except for our validator class,
and we'll actually take care of that in the next video.