All right, so we have the basic stub
for our annotation setup.
Now what I need to do is actually define the attributes
that we can pass into our annotation.
So we've already saw the usage example
where we're gonna have two attributes, one for value,
and one for the actual error message.
We'll actually define these attributes here,
and we'll also set up some default values for them.
And then we'll also make use of two other entries here
for this annotation for groups and also for payloads,
so groups is where you can actually group validation
constraints together, and then payload is where you can
give additional information about the validation error.
All right, so that's kinda like the basic layout here
of things that we need to do
and things that we need to fill in.
So let's start typing.
So, we're gonna have this one attribute called value
that the user can pass in, and if they don't
pass in a value, then we'll say the default is LUV.
So that's the actual prefix that we'll validate against.
Then also for message, they can pass in their own
custom message, but if not, then we'll give
this default error message of "must start with LUV."
This is primarily for people
who are using the actual annotation.
Then we set up our default groups, and so here,
we're not gonna use any grouping of grouping constraints,
so we'll simply just give the basic boilerplate here of
groups, and we'll simply just give an empty collection.
And then for payloads, we're not gonna use any payloads,
so we'll simply just give the default here for payload.
And again, payload can basically give you additional details
about the error message that has occurred.
So again, just anything will do.
All right, so that's the basic layout here.
Let me go through and, let's see,
I have a small little typo here.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah, I'm missing the parens here.
I'm missing parens.
There we go, there we go.
Let me go ahead and put the open paren,
close paren right there.
All-righty.
And then a similar thing here for the word payload,
lowercase, open paren, close paren.
All right, good.
Took care of that.
Let me go through and fix some of these imports here
for payload, just to import.
Make sure you perform the correct import here.
All right, so this looks pretty good.
We got all of the big items here,
a javax.validation.Payload, we got that importing correctly,
and we went through and we listed the attributes
that the user can call or pass in
to this given annotation.
So we're in good shape.
So we went through and defined the default course code,
error message, and then also groups and payloads,
and so the two key things that we're gonna use
in this demo is that we're gonna make use of the actual
value for course code and a message for error messages.