All right,
so we have our annotation taken care of.
We still need to fix this CourseCodeConstraintValidator.
That red squiggly line is really starting to annoy me,
it's really starting to bug me.
Let's go ahead and resolve this issue.
That's step 1B, creating our CourseCodeConstraintValidator.
I'll go ahead and just highlight the actual string here
for that class name,
and I'll use that to create a new class.
Now, let me swing over and create a new class.
In my validation package, I'll create a new class.
The actual name of the class, I'll just drop in
that actual name that I just copied,
a little copy/paste exercise, CourseCodeConstraintValidator.
Go ahead and keep all the other defaults here,
and go ahead and click on Finish.
All right, so here we go.
We have the basic layout here for our class.
Now, I know this class has to implement
the ConstraintValidator interface,
so I'll say implements ConstraintValidator.
Then I'll pass in CourseCode and the string.
ConstraintValidator is actually an interface
from the javax validation package.
Make sure we do the import and get the correct one here.
Okay, so this is good so far.
All right, so now we can go ahead
and click on the little red X here on the left hand side,
and we'll tell Eclipse to Add the unimplemented methods,
just to make sure that we implement all the methods
that are required here.
Nice little stub code it'll generate for us.
Let me zoom out for a second.
Eclipse dropped in two methods here.
There's an initialize method
that we have to implement or override,
and also there's a is valid method,
and that's where we'll put our actual business logic
to return true or false if the given string validates.
All right, so what I want to do is define a coursePrefix
that we can validate against,
so this is the actual prefix that they've set up
with the annotation to say,
hey, we validate it against a given prefix.
I need to actually assign this
when this annotation or ConstraintValidator is initialized,
so here I'll say coursePrefix equals theCourseCode.value.
That .value actually accesses the attribute value
for that given annotation.
Here, it'll actually be LUV,
but we could easily customize that
to be something different,
and we'll do that in some of the following videos.
All right, so we have the basic set up,
now let's go ahead and get down and dirty
and let's write our real business rule here,
check and see if something is valid.
That first parameter coming in, arg0,
that's theCode, that's the actual text
that the user entered on their HTML form,
and then the second argument
is the ConstraintValidatorContext,
that's just an actual parameter that we can use
to give additional error messages if we need it
for this given validation routine.
All right, so I'll add some nice descriptive arguments here.
Now, let's go ahead and do some of our work
inside of this method,
so basically we want to check to see
if something's true or false and give a result,
so I'll set the boolean result equals
theCode.startsWith course prefix.
I want to see, whatever the user entered on their HTML form,
does it start with our desired course prefix?
If so, we just basically assign it
so that result will be equal to the result
of theCode.startsWith that'll return
the value of true or false.
That's basically our business rule or our business logic.
Now, again, this is very simple,
if you're writing your own custom validation rule
you can really do anything you want in this invalid method.
You can talk to a database, call a web service,
do some special number crunching, whatever you need to do,
you can do inside that is valid method,
it's totally up to you,
you simply return a true or false
based on your own custom business logic.
All right, so this looks good so far,
so I'll go ahead and save this
and we can go ahead and move onto our next step.