Alrighty, so just a quick recap.
So we've covered step one
of creating a custom validation
where that includes our annotation
and our constraint validators.
So that was all the real heavy lifting here.
The remaining steps we've kinda seen a lot of this before,
so step two will simply add
the validation rules to the class.
Step three is displaying the error message on the form
and then step four is simply updating the confirmation page.
These steps go really quickly
and we'll take care of all of these in this video.
So with step two,
adding a validation rule to the customer class.
So at this point,
we simply need to open up our customer class,
our entity,
and actually place the rule there.
So go down into to my customer.java file,
open it up.
And this is where we have all of our other validation rules
for like first name, last name, and so on.
Well first need to create a
(laughs)
I need to create a field here for course code.
So I'll just create a field,
private string course code,
and this field we can give any name, right,
which is course code.
And then we'll also generate some getters
and setters here for this field.
But again, this field could be called anything,
food bar or whatever you would like to have here.
So I'll just generate the getters and setters
using our normal technique.
Select everything there for course code
and then click okay.
Okay, great, so there we go.
So we have those
getters and setters here for course code.
Okay, good stuff so far.
Alright, so now let's go ahead and do the real work.
Let's drop in our custom annotation, woohoo!
So @CourseCode,
and remember, Java's case sensitive, right?
So this is a capital c,
so it's different from the other stuff
and this is our custom annotation
and wow!
The clips found our annotation.
So we can do an import on course code, yeah.
All right, so that's my annotation
that I just did an import on
and just verify and there it is for my validation package.
Course code, yeah baby,
using my custom validation over here.
And there you go and that's our @CourseCode annotation
We're not not gonna pass any attribute values here,
we're simply gonna use the defaults right
'cause we've already coded it accordingly
to handle the appropriate defaults.
So we're in good shape with this so far.
All right.
Now I need to display the error messages on the HTML form.
That's step three.
So I need to go into my customer-form.jsp
and again,
just follow the same process I've done before
for displaying the error messages.
So I actually need to add a new field
here for course code,
So I'm just gonna copy postal code
and I'll just do a little copy paste exercise
and drop postal code here,
but I'll go through and rename this to course code.
So, course code.
Path, course code.
All right, there we go.
So we have our new form field
and we also have on line 39 an entry
so we can actually display the error message
in case the validation fails for this field.
Now moving ahead to step four,
updating our confirmation page,
we simply wanna echo whatever the value user entered.
So, real simple right?
So again, I'll just do another little copy paste here.
And I will say
course code
and a dollar sign customer
dot course code.
Go and save that and there we go.
So we'll just echo whatever the you user
entered on their HTML form.
Okay, good job.