Okay so I'm getting really anxious here.
I'm eager to run this application,
so let's go ahead and run it and test it out.
Go ahead and click my link here for customer form.
And I'll just go ahead and enter some data here,
for a last name.
Also, go and submit and whoa!
What the what?
I was not expecting this.
500 error, let's dig in here.
So this was unplanned, unscripted,
but here, root cause, Null Pointer Exception.
Oh, I like it.
So this is some good debugging tips for you.
And Course Code Constraint Validator line 20.
Okay, all right.
We're getting some evidence here.
Let's get on the trail.
So, course code constraint validator line 20.
Well I didn't follow my own code.
So I actually need to check for null.
So what happens is that if the user
doesn't enter anything, it comes in
as a null value for the code.
And, boom, blows up right here.
Oh boy, okay.
So we can fix it, right?
We know how to fix it.
We just need to check for null
before we do any real checks.
This is all fun.
So, here I can say, if the code is not equal to null,
then I can do my regular work,
like I planned on doing, silly.
So I'll say, result equals this thing
and I put the curly brace.
And then else, I'll actually return the value of true.
Because, hey, you didn't pass anything
there's nothing for me to validate.
And we'll let you go on.
Because this field is not required.
So, all righty, I think I feel a little bit better.
And again, it's all my fault.
I should have followed my own code from my own slides.
But hey, we're human, things happen.
All righty, so we're having too much fun here.
So anyway, we fix our code.
We've saved it.
Now let's go back and actually run this
and try it again.
So get it up and running.
We click on our form.
And now we enter some data here for last name.
And then hit the submit.
Okay, it goes through, good!
Okay, so no Null Pointer Exception, that's a good thing.
Now let's actually enter a code.
Let's enter a bad code, like, A-B-C one two three
and this should fail.
And yeah, all right!
So it says that it must start with L-U-V.
Good job.
So now here I'll say, "Okay, great.
"I'll start it with L-U-V."
and hit enter, and booya!
There we go.
Course Code LUV one two three.
So that's great.
So we're in really, really good shape here.
Now, what I wanna do is actually customize this.
Such that it's not using L-U-V
but instead, using something different.
A different code.
So here I'll customize it by saying,
"must start with TOPS."
Again, just making this up.
We could say, "must start with Foobar."
Or, "must start with funny."
Whatever, but I'm just getting a customized
version of this annotation and making use of it.
So I'll let my container go through,
in the background, and reload.
And notice here at the bottom, it will say,
"Hey, the reload is completed."
Okay, good.
So now I should be able to go back to my form.
All righty, so for my course code here
I'll just enter some bad data, like A-B-C one two three,
hit submit, right?
Okay, and up at the top it's asking
about names, Smith.
All right, or whatever.
And here, let me just give a bad code again,
L-U-V one two three.
I'm gonna try and hit submit.
Notice here it's saying it must start with TOPS.
Because we've changed our source code now
to actually validate against this new prefix.
Okay, good, so I'll go ahead and hit
TOPS one two three, hit submit.
And, boom, it passed.
So that's cool.
So we have our annotation up and running.
We can even customize our annotation
as far as what code or prefix to use.
And it all works out fine with the
Spring MVC Validation.
Good job, congrats!
Whooo!