In this video, we're gonna discuss
the bean scopes available in Spring.
So what exactly are scopes?
Well, a scope refers to the lifecycle of a bean,
for example, it tells you how long the bean will live,
how many instances will be created
and also how is the bean shared in the Spring environment?
So the default scope for a bean is singleton,
so here's an example here of just some bean code,
that we had earlier and we didn't explicitly give a scope,
so by default, the scope is singleton.
But now you're probably wondering,
well, what exactly is a singleton? (laughs)
we know it's a default scope, but what is it?
Well, for a singleton, the Spring Container
creates only one instance of the bean, it's cached in memory
and then all requests for that bean
will return a shared reference to the same bean,
so the end result is that there is only one bean
and everyone will share it.
Here's a nice diagram to kind of show you this example.
In this example, we have theCoach
equals context.getBean myCoach
and it'll give you a reference to like a TrackCoach,
that you have defined and then later on in the code,
if you would also do a similar thing,
saying context.getBean myCoach, the same bean id,
then it'll basically give you a reference to the same bean.
We have these two object references here
and they point to the same area of memory
or they point to the same bean,
so again, Spring makes use of a singleton,
it'll create only one bean and then share it
for everyone who requests that bean,
so the singleton scope is default
and the best use case for this is for a stateless bean,
where you don't need to maintain any state.
You can explicitly specify the bean scope,
I mean, by now you know that by default,
you have the singleton scope,
but if you want to explicitly specify,
then you make use of the scope attribute,
so you say scope equals singleton
and that'll make it a singleton bean
and that's kind of the preferred approach
to minimize the number of beans, that are created.
But now, there are additional Spring bean scopes,
that you can make use of.
We've already covered singleton,
there's also the prototype scope,
which creates a new bean instance for each container request
and we'll see examples of that coming up
and we'll also use that as a demo in the video coming up,
then the next three items here,
request, session and global-session,
these scopes are only used in a web environment,
so request is for a given web request,
session is for a HTTP web session, for like session tracking
for like maybe a shopping cart or something
and then global-session is scope application-wide,
but we'll talk more about these later,
when we get into the Spring MVC section,
but for now, we'll simply focus on singleton and prototype.
So here's an example of using prototype scope,
so again, remember, prototype scope,
a new object is created for each request,
so in this example here, I have my bean id of myCoach
and I have scope equals prototype,
so that means that every time
I make a request for this myCoach,
they'll create a new instance each time.
So, a nice little diagram here.
So the line of code at the top,
theCoach equals context.getBean myCoach,
it'll create a new instance of that bean,
I'll get a reference to it and then a similar thing here,
when I say alphaCoach equals context.getBean myCoach,
it'll create a new object for you
and you'll have your own reference.
So the prototype scope is good for keeping track
of stateful data, so again, whenever you see prototype,
just think of the new keyword, it's gonna create a new bean
for each request for that component or that object.
Alright, so this is some really good stuff.
Let's go ahead and move forward,
in the next videos, we're gonna dive into Eclipse
and we'll actually write some code,
that'll make use of the singleton scope
and the prototype scope,
so you can see everything in action.
Alrighty, I'll see you in the next video.