Alright, so let's go ahead
and dive in to Eclipse and we're gonna run
some demos here on Bean Scopes.
We'll take a look at those singleton scope
and a prototype scope and we'll see
all of this code running in action
and I don't know, just get a good feel for it.
The first thing we wanna do is,
copy our application context file.
We're actually going to create a new version of it,
so we'll take this existing application context,
we'll just do a right click and choose copy
and then, we'll simply paste it,
so we just do a right click and we choose paste
and this new version, we'll give it a new name here.
I'll call it, beanScope-applicationContext.xml
and so, with these spring config files,
you can really give them any name that you want.
Your project can actually have multiple config files
and here you simply reference the one that you want,
so you can call it anything, fubar.xml if you wanted to,
as long as you reference it with that name.
Anyway, I have my beanScope-applicationContext.xml,
now let's go ahead and bean it up,
let's go ahead and open this file
and what I wanna do is, I just clean it up.
There's some lines in here that I want to delete.
I'll select lines 10 and 11, I'll highlight those
and I'll delete these lines because we're
not going to use any of the property placeholder stuff here.
I'm moving down a little bit further
and I'll also remove that bean for myCricketCoach,
so I'll just highlight the lines 24 through 34
and I'll actually delete those lines
and I'll just clean up some of this white space,
move up and let's do a little quick check point,
so in this config file that we just created,
beanScope-applicationContext.xml,
these are the only two entries that we should have
inside of here for beans, so we'll have our FortuneService
and we'll have our Coach, that points to our TrackCoach
and that's all we should have, at this point.
Now, by default, since we didn't specify
a scope for our track coach, well, what's the scope?
Well, it's singleton right?
Basic information we've learned so far,
so it'll simply be a single bean,
now, everyone will reference when we run our application.
Let's go ahead and create another main app,
I'll call this guy, BeanScopeDemoApp.java,
so I'll just do a right click, I'll say, new class
and the actual name of the class again, BeanScopeDemoApp
and I'll also go down and I'll check the box there
for the public static void main,
because I'll have a main method,
just a little separate demo app that I'll use for
testing out this scoping stuff.
Alright, okay with all that stuff, hit, finish.
Alright, so we have a very simple bean scope demo app.
I'll just move in here and I'll just remove the
auto-generated stuff and I'll write some quick comments
here, as well as what I need to do.
This is kinda, you're getting really used to this now,
the first thing we need to do is,
load the spring configuration file
and then, simply retrieve beans from the spring container.
Alright, that's kinda the game plan,
let's write the code right here
and you should probably know most of this now,
from memory because you've seen this a lot
so this is good practice, this is how you can really learn
the technology, just by repeating it
over and over again, just like a sport,
practice, practice, practice.
Let me go ahead and use that ClassPathXmlApplicationContext,
I'll just do a copy paste, I say, new
and I give the actual name, so this is gonna be
the actual name of my new configuration file
that we just created, so that's
the file that we created called,
beanScope-applicationContext.xml,
let me go ahead and fix up the imports right here.
I'll just hover over and say, import that given class,
looks good and there we go, so yeah,
that's our new config file that we're reading in here,
beanScope-applicationContext.xml
so again, you can have as many config files
up here as you like for your project,
simply load the appropriate one.
Also, if you have multiple, you simply give
a common denominated list, you can load in
multiple configs if you wanted to.
Alright, let's keep it simple for now.
Now, let's go ahead and get some white space
and let's go ahead and retrieve the bean from the container.
I'm actually gonna retrieve two beans,
so I'll start off with the first one here.
I'll say, Coach theCoach = context.getBean,
I give the name, which is, myCoach
and then I give the interface, Coach.class.
Looks good, and also you can just copy paste this line,
for the second reference, so I'll
just do a paste on that one, instead of the coach,
I'll call it alphaCoach and everything
else here stays the same, so basically,
this is the code here for retrieving
the bean from the spring container.
Right now, it's a singleton, so
we should get the same reference
and we'll actually write some code in a second
to show us the reference, but I'll kinda pause for now.
In the next video, we'll write more code
to print out the results of this reference.
I'll see you in the next video.