Alrighty, so let's go ahead
and pick up where we left off.
So, the previous video we simply retrieved those beans
from a container for theCoach and alphaCoach,
now let's go ahead and just do some more work here.
So, the first thing I wanna do is check
to see if these are the same beans.
So, I'll simply set up a boolean variable result
and I will actually compare these two,
I'll compare their object references.
So, I'll say theCoach equals equal alphaCoach
and I'll put that in parens
just to show you that I'm comparing
these two items, I'm comparing our object reference
to see if they are pointing to the same area of memory
or if they're pointing to the same object.
That's what we're doing here
with this boolean result equals.
Now let's go ahead and display the results here
and so we can see, you know,
exactly what's going on.
So, let me set up my quick comment here
to print out the results
and I'll use my sysop print line
and then inside of here
I'll actually say pointing to the same object
and then plus result
and I put a backslash in at the beginning
of that stream just to give me a character turn
just so I can have some extra white space
when I'm looking at the results here of my run.
Alright, so that's the first one here.
And then I also wanna actually print out
the memory location for each one of these.
So, I'll say the memory location for theCoach
and then I'm just doing a plus theCoach
and so by default,
the default version of this display here,
it'll call the two string method of this object,
and the default implementation of the two strings,
it'll simply be the class name
and the internal memory address
for that given object reference.
So, I'll do a similar thing here for alphaCoach.
Alright, that looks okay,
and I'll add an extra character turn
just to make the output look pretty.
And also I'll be nice, add a Spring container
and I'll close the context.
Alright, so that's kind of it.
So, you know, we already read in the config up top,
then we retrieved the bean from the container,
we moved down and we just checked the result
to see if they were the same,
and then we print out the result
and we also print out the memory location
for theCoach and alphaCoach.
Oh actually, let me fix that quick typo here.
So, pointing, I put a colon space right there
on line 22 just to make my output
look a little bit prettier.
Alright, so run as Java application
and good stuff here.
Alright, let's check out this output.
Okay, great, so first off
it says, you know, loading XML bean definitions
from this file, beanScope-applicationContext,
so that's our new file that we just created
and so we are reading that file which is good,
and then here's the print out of the results
pointing to the same object is true,
and also we have the memory location for theCoach
which is 5e85
and also the memory location for alphaCoach 5e85,
so basically those numbers are the same,
so it's actually printing to the same area of memory
for both of these objects.
So, that's great.
Now let's go ahead and switch this up.
Let's test this with scope equals prototype.
So, scope equals prototype means that it'll actually create
a new object every time we request it.
So, here I'll say scope equals prototype
in the config file.
Alright, so this looks good,
so let's go equals prototype,
so I'm gonna create a new object for each request.
Let's go ahead and save this file
and now all we need to do is go back
to the bean scope demo app
and then just run it.
No changes here, everything here stays the same.
Just right click and choose run as.
Alright, so looking at the output.
Okay, now, okay, reading from that config
beanScope-appContext,
now it says pointing to the same object is false.
Whoa, yeah, 'cause it's a prototype, right?
So that means that they create a new object
for each reference, alright?
So, theCoach has one memory address
and then alphaCoach has a different memory address,
so these are two separate objects,
two separate areas of memory
because again, right, we using the prototype scope.
Alright, so nice little example here
of making use of singleton scope
and prototype scope
and here you're able to see the output,
see the results and so on.
So, you should feel very comfortable now with bean scopes.
So again, the default is singleton
and it's only one instance
and then you can also specify prototype scope
which will create a new one for each request.
Alright, you're ready,
you're ready for a Spring job interview.
Alright, cool, good stuff.
So, I'll see you the next video.