In this video,
we're gonna discuss bean lifecycle methods.
So when the Spring container first starts
there are a couple of things that happens.
First off, the beans are instantiated,
and then the actual dependencies are injected,
next you have some internal Spring processing
that occurs with the bean factory,
and then you have the option
of adding your own custom initialization code,
and then at that point the bean is ready for use.
So you can call methods on it,
do work with the bean,
so on and so forth.
At a certain point the containers actually shutdown
meaning your application is shutdown
like what context.close,
then you also have a chance
to call your custom destroy method,
and that code'll execute before the actual application
is stopped or before the actual beans lifecycle is over.
The one thing you want to take a look
at are those two orange sections
here adding your own custom methods.
What you can do is you can add your own custom code
that happens during bean initialization.
So you can call custom business logic,
you can set up handles,
so like databases, or sockets, or whatever.
You can also do a similar thing
when a bean is actually being destroyed or destructed.
So again, you can call any custom business methods,
or you can clean up any handles
that you may have to resources
like databases, sockets, or files.
So basically what this provides here
is that during the bean lifecycle,
Spring allows you to call some of your custom code,
and these are what we call hooks,
where you can actually hook in codes
to execute during bean initialization or bean destruction.
All right, so now, how would you do this?
Well, you simply make configuration entry in your XML file.
So for bean initialization,
you make use of this attribute called init-method,
and then you give the actual method name
that you would like for Spring to call on your bean.
Now this method name can be any method name.
Here I called doMyStartupStuff.
It could be called fubar or whatever,
and we can also do a similar thing for the destroy method.
So again, you simply make
a configuration entry here in your XML file.
You simply give the method name
you want Spring to call for destroy,
and again, it can be any name.
All right, so this all looks kinda good.
What's the basic development process?
So again, I love my step-by-step.
So the first thing you do is you simply
define your methods for the init and destroy
in your bean class, then the next step
is you simply configure those method names
in the Spring configuration file,
and in the next video, we'll dive into Eclipse,
and we'll actually walk through this development process,
and we'll test out this feature.
So I'll see you in the next video.