Alrighty, so let's go ahead
and move into Eclipse.
Looking at our development process,
the first thing we want to do is define methods
for init and destroy.
So I'll go ahead and do this here.
I'll make use of my TrackCoach.java class.
So let's go ahead and move into this class.
And we are going to just open it up.
And we'll simply scroll down a bit
to the bottom, and we'll define those new methods.
So again, I always like to drop in
some quick comments here just so I keep myself on track.
So I want to add an init method,
and I want to add a destroy method.
So again, this is custom code that will execute
during the bean's lifecycle,
when the bean's being created
or the bean's being destroyed, our little custom hook.
And now what I want to do, just inside of this method here,
just print out a little message here
just so I know I'm actually inside the method.
So I'll say TrackCoach: inside method
do my startup stuff.
So just to make sure that spring's actually calling
my initialization method.
But that's basically it right there.
So this looks pretty good so far.
Alright, so let's move on down
and let's do a similar thing in here for our destroy method.
So again, this is a hook or a method that'll be called
when your bean's actually being destroyed
by the spring container.
So I'll call this doMyStartupStuff,
and I'll copy/paste the method down there.
And I'll just copy/paste that method name, and ew.
I notice this is the wrong method name.
I have a typo here, so let me change this.
So instead of doMyStartupStuff, doMyCleanupStuffYoYo.
Alright, doMyCleanupStuff.
So I'll copy/paste.
I'll fix that issue.
So again, that's different method names.
So this is our destroy method,
so I'll call it doMyCleanupStuffYoYo.
And I'm being funny here just to verify
that, hey, there's no special method naming convention.
You can give it any method name that you want.
Alright, so that looks good.
So that's our init method, and that's our destroy method.
Good job so far.
Now let's go ahead and make use of a configuration file.
And what I'm gonna do here is I'm gonna
just kind of copy/paste a previous config file
and simply make some changes to it.
So I'm gonna copy/paste the beanScope-applicationContext.xml
from the previous video.
Simply do just a right-click and choose Copy
and then a right-click and choose Paste.
And then for the new name that I'll give here,
I'll call it beanLifeCycle-applicationContext
and remove the two at the end, .xml.
So again, we can have multiple config files, right?
So I'm just giving a unique name here
for this demo project.
And if you didn't complete the previous video,
simply grab any one of your XML files and just rename it.
So anyway, let's take a look
at this beanLifeCycle-applicationContext.xml,
and let's kind of expand the window here.
And let's move down.
Now there's one thing that's a leftover
from the previous video as far as playing around
with bean scopes.
So on line 19, I'm gonna delete this entry,
scope="prototype".
I'm gonna remove that because I want to make use
of simply just the default scope, right?
And as a quiz question, the default scope is singleton.
Alright.
Now here, let's go ahead and add our init method.
So we need to give the actual method name
from our bean class.
So I need to kind of move back over
to my TrackCoach and find out which init method
I'll use here.
So I'll call it doMyStartupStuff.
I'll simply copy that name, and then
I'll simply paste it here.
I use the keyboard for that, copy/paste.
And there we go.
So that's my init method.
That's in place.
Now let's do a similar thing here
for the destroy method, so destroy-method equals.
And again, I need to get that actual method name.
So I'll kind of move back over to TrackCoach,
and I'll copy that name.
So it's doMyCleanupStuffYoYo.
And then move back to the config,
and then paste that in there.
So that's our destroy method that spring will call
when the bean is being destroyed.
Alright, this looks pretty good.
Now I need to have a main program to kind of run everything.
So again, I'm gonna kind of copy
one of my previous examples.
We've been doing a lot of stuff from scratch.
And here I'm just gonna copy this
and just make some quick updates to it.
So here, I'm gonna copy this BeanScopeDemoApp,
BeanScopeDemoApp.java, tongue twister.
I'll just copy that, and I will just paste it.
And I'll give it a new name, so I'll call this
BeanLifeCycleDemoApp, take off the two at the end.
And if everything's okay, then we can click the OK button.
Alright, so we should have this new file here,
BeanLifeCycleDemoApp.java.
So let's go ahead and double-click that one,
open it up, expand the window.
Cool, now the first thing I want to do here is on line 11
where we have the actual file name.
I want to change this file name
to use my LifeCycle example.
Right, so it has to say
beanLifeCycle-applicationContext.xml.
You want to make sure that it's calling
the right config file for your application.
Alright, and then we'll kind of scroll down a bit.
I'll delete a lot of that other stuff that was there.
So we should have just a very simple program right now.
So again, we did a little copy/paste
to kind of help us out, but just a real small program:
load the config, retrieve the bean,
and close the context.
So just a little checkpoint to make sure
we're on the same page here.
And now I'm just gonna use the bean
once I've retrieved it from the container.
I'll just print out getDailyWorkout
just to print something to the screen, nothing big there.
And that's pretty much it for this little demo here
for the LifeCycle.
So we simply load the config file.
We retrieve the bean from the container,
call methods on it, and finally we close the spring context.
Alright, so that's it.
It looks good.
BeanLifeCycleDemoApp, it's ready.
Let's save it, and let's run it.
Right-click, Run as Java Application.
And cool, here's our output.
So, a couple of things here.
Make sure that it's reading from the right config file,
beanLifeCycle-applicationContext.xml.
So that's the correct file that we just created.
We see that it's calling our method,
inside method doMyStartupStuff, which is good.
That's our init method.
We call our daily workout which is great.
And then we see when this container's closing,
at the end it'll actually call our destroy method.
So, inside method doMyCleanupStuffYoYo.
So this is great.
So spring's actually calling our init method as desired
and it's also calling our destroy method.
So this is great.
So we can add our own custom hooks here
into the spring bean lifecycle.