In this video, we're going to get an
overview of Spring MVC.
So what is Spring MVC?
Well, basically, it's a framework for building web
applications in Java.
As the name suggests, it's based on the
Model-View-Controller design pattern.
And also, the nice thing about it is that it leverages
the features of the Core Spring Framework, so you can
leverage all of your inversion of control,
and dependency of injection.
So everything that you've learned in the class so far
you'll be able to apply in Spring MVC.
Okay, so here's a big picture here of the MVC framework,
and the process flow and how it works.
So basically you have an incoming request coming from
the browser, it'll encounter the Spring MVC
front controller.
This person will actually delegate the request off to a
controller code.
This controller code is code that you create that contains
your business logic.
You basically create a model, and you send the model back
to the front controller, and then the front controller,
will pass that model over to your view template.
So your view template is basically like a html page,
or a JSP page that will take that data, and then render
a response to the browser.
So that's kind of the big picture of the MVC framework.
In following videos, I'll kind of break this down,
and I'll go into more details on each step of the process.
But anyway, this is a big picture here on how Spring MVC
will process a web request.
Alright, so what are the benefits of using Spring MVC?
Well it's basically Spring's way of building
web apps using Java.
So basically you can leverage a set of reusable UI
components, and these are available in the form of
Spring JSP custom tags.
You can also manage your application state for web requests
for session tracking, or application tracking,
and you can also process your form data, so you can also
perform validation on the form data, conversion,
so on and so forth.
And finally, Spring MVC has a very flexible configuration
for the view layers, so you're not limited to only using
JSP, you can use other view layers like Thymeleaf,
Velocity, or FreeMarker.
And I'll talk about this in some of the following videos.
Alright, now as far as documentation, there's a lot of
good documentation available.
Here's the official documentation from Spring.
You can go to this website I have here,
luv2code.com/spring-mvc-docs.
This will basically just redirect you to the official
documentation at the Spring website.
So they have a very good write up on how the framework
works, details, and pretty much everything you need to know
is available in that documentation.
That's the actually Spring reference manual.
And if you wanted to have more information about Spring,
well there's plenty of books online.
So you can simply go to Amazon, you can type in the word
Spring MVC and do a search, and you'll have a lot of good
hits out there, so a lot of good books out there.
Go ahead and read the reviews, see which ones work for you,
and you can proceed accordingly.
But a lot of information's available at Amazon, and also
there's a lot of free websites that have Spring MVC
tutorials, too.
Alright, so that was just a quick overview of Spring MVC.
In the following videos I'll go into some details,
I'll give you a quick behind-the-scenes tour of Spring MVC,
and then we'll set up our development environment,
and then we'll start writing some code.
So I'll see you in the next video.