In this video,
I'm gonna give you a behind the scenes tour
of Spring MVC.
What are the components of a Spring MVC application?
Basically it's a collection of web pages
to layout your UI components.
It's also a collection of Spring beans,
for controlling, handling services,
and so on.
And then finally you have your Spring configuration.
You can choose XML, Annotations, or pure Java.
And those are kinda the main components
of a Spring MVC application.
Now, how does Spring MVC work behind the scenes?
In a previous video I showed you this
little diagram here of the process model.
What I wanna do is actually take this
little process model and kind of break it down,
and kinda dig into it a little bit,
and kinda go step-by-step.
Do a little deep dive on how the
whole process flow works.
Everything starts off with that first
incoming request and it encounters something
called a front controller.
So the front controller is known as
the dispatcher servelet.
This front controller's actually part
of the Spring framework.
It's already developed by the Spring development team
so you don't have to create this.
This is part of the Spring jar files
that you download,
so it's given to you for free.
So out of the box you have his front controller.
What this front controller will do
is it will actually delegate the request
to some other objects or items
here in our system.
As a developer, you will create
the model, the view, and the controller MVC.
So the model objects are in orange.
The model objects contain data.
The view templates,
that are in dark green,
that's your actual JSP page,
or your view page to actually
render the data.
And then C,
the controller classes that's in yellow,
that's your actual business logic
or your processing logic.
Coming up next, I'll actually talk about
each one of these components in detail.
Let's start with controller.
So when the front controller has a request,
it delegates the request to the controller.
That's in yellow.
The controller is the code that you will actually create.
Basically in this controller,
this contains your business logic.
So this is where you'll handle the request
where you'll maybe read some form data
then you'll take this data
and store it or retrieve it.
You may store it into a database or
retrieve information from a web service.
Basically, once you have your data
and you're using it,
then you can take that data
and place it into the model.
So the model is just a container for your data
and then you pass it back to the appropriate
view template.
So again, your controller,
code that you create,
contains your business logic,
and it handles the web request.
So let's talk about the model.
As I mentioned earlier,
the model contains your data.
So when your controller goes off
and performs an operation to retrieve data
from a backend system, like a database or web service,
or a Spring Bean,
you can take that data and place it into the model.
So the model again is your container,
like your suitcase or your luggage,
for shipping data between various parts
of your Spring MVC application.
So that model data will actually get passed
over to the view template
and they can actually handle that
for displaying the data.
That's kinda where we're at right now.
So the view template.
The most common view template that you'll use
is JSP and JSTL.
Spring MVC is very flexible.
There's many different view template types.
I'll talk about that in a second.
But for now let's just think about JSP, JSTL.
This model data comes over to your view template
and then your JSP page can read that model data
and display it.
So, say for example,
you have a list of students,
or list of products,
then your JSP page can create a table
to display that product list
or that student list.
Or, say for example, somebody is signing
up for an airline flight,
or is signing up for a class,
then your view template,
or your page can give them a confirmation,
hey, you're registered for the class,
here's your confirmation number.
So that's the idea of the view template.
It's basically a JSP page
that will provide data to the user.
Now as I mentioned,
Spring MVC is very flexible on the view templates.
There's actually other view templates
that are supported,
so if you don't wanna use JSP,
you can make use of some other templates
like Thymeleaf, Groovy, Velocity, Freemarker,
the list goes on.
You can plug in all different types of view templates.
If you'd like to get details on this,
go to this link I have on the screen,
luv2code.com/spring-mvc-views.
This'll redirect you to the official Spring documentation
and you can get more information
on the various other templates
that are out there and available.
Alright, good.
This is a quick behind the scenes view
of Spring MVC.
You learned about the model, the view, the controller
and a conceptual theoretical level.
In the following videos we're gonna
start getting our hands dirty
and setting up our environment
and then starting to write some code.
So I'll see you there.