In this video, we're gonna
talk about our development environment setup.
So, as a checkpoint, these are three items
that you're gonna need for your development environment.
So, so far you should have already installed
Tomcat, Eclipse, and also Connected Eclipse to Tomcat.
You need to have this setup
and configured before you can proceed.
This is all covered in previous videos,
so if you haven't done this yet,
please go back to those videos
and get it configured accordingly.
Now, there's some additional things
that we're gonna need to do.
The first item is downloading Spring MVC source code
that's specific for this training class.
I have some sample files that you'll use
to kind of get started with some of the configuration.
And then also, what we're gonna do is,
we're gonna download the latest Spring JAR files
from the Spring websites.
There were some recent updates to Spring,
and I want to take advantage of those new features
and cover it here in the course.