In this video,
we're going to learn how to configure Spring MVC.
So, here's the big picture of Spring MVC.
Remember, we have a Front Controller.
They dispatch something to a Controller class,
and also make use of View Templates,
and I'll show you how to get this set up
and how to get it configured in Spring MVC,
and I must admit, up front,
this is probably the hardest part
of getting started with Spring MVC,
is getting the configuration right,
so I'll have a step-by-step process,
and I'll show you how to get all of this working.
So, here's the first part of doing the
Spring MVC Configuration Process.
What we'll have to do is make some modifications
to our web.xml file.
So, the first thing is,
configuring a Spring MVC dispatcher servlet, and then
setting up a URL mapping to this dispatcher servlet.
And then, part two of the configuration process
is that we'll add some entries into a
Spring configuration file,
so here, we'll add support for a component scanning.
We'll also add support for
conversion, formatting, and validation.
And then, finally, we'll configure
the Spring MVC view resolver, and don't worry.
In the following slides,
I'll go through each of these, step-by-step.
Alright, let's start off with step one,
Configure the Spring MVC DispatcherServlet.
So, in our web.xml file, we need to add an entry
for the Spring DispatcherServlet, or the Front Controller,
so you put in a servlet reference,
you give the name and class of the servlet,
and, again, the DispatcherServlet is part of
the core Spring framework,
so you get it for free, in the Spring .jar files.
There's nothing that you have to create.
Once you have the servlet reference,
then you set up initial parameter,
so you basically tell it where your
Spring context configuration file is located.
In this example, we'll make use of
/WEB-INF/spring-mvc-demo-servlet.xml.
You can give any name you want, here,
as long as you reference it accordingly.
So, the next thing we need to do is set up
the URL mappings for the Spring MVC DispatcherServlet.
So, basically, what we want to do is
tell the system, "Hey, for any URL pattern coming in,
I'd like for you to pass it off to the DispatcherServlet."
So, in this case, our URL pattern's going to be slash,
meaning all web requests, coming in,
should be handled by the DispatcherServlet.
If you want to have a different pattern, here,
you can simply say slash FUBAR, slash STAR, or whatever,
to have it work with a different pattern,
but, here, I'm going to keep it simple and make use of
the slash pattern for handling all the requests.
Now, one thing that's important, here, is to know here
that servlet name matches with the servlet reference
that you just set up, higher up in this file,
or at the top, that was set up in step one,
so those two items have to match up.
Okay, moving to the next step,
Add support for component scanning, so in our file,
this is our Spring file, spring-mvc-demo-servlet.xml,
we simply add context:component-scan.
And, again, this works just like we've learned so far,
that it'll basically scan this package
for any special Spring beans, and make them available,
so any @component items out there,
it'll make them available,
and put them into the Spring context.
Alright, step four, adding support for conversion,
formatting, and validation.
So, when you make use of spring-mvc,
it could perform conversions of form data.
It can also format form data, for you,
and you can also perform form validation,
so in order to get the support,
you make use of this mvc:annotation-driven.
And then the final step here,
is Configuring the Spring MVC View Resolver, so,
really, a fancy name for, "How do we display the pages?"
Or, "Where are the pages located?"
So, at the bottom, here, we make use of
this internal resource, ViewResolver, and then
we give a prefix, and then a suffix.
And you're probably wondering,
"What's up with the prefix and suffix?"
(laughs) Well, when your app provides a "view" name,
Spring MVC will automatically prepend the prefix
and append the suffix.
Alright, so it's basically telling it
where to look for files,
to actually render the view for your application.
So, let's take a look at an example, here.
So, say, for example, we returned a view name of
show-student-list.
Automatically, Spring will prepend /WEB-INF/view,
because that's the prefix,
and then we'll have the actual view name,
and they'll append the suffic, .jsp.
So, that's the actual path of the view page
that will actually show.
Alright, so a little funny, a little tricky,
but once you understand this configuration file,
and you understand that Spring will automatically
do this work for you, then it'll work out just fine.
Alright, so that's basically
the Spring configuration process,
so what we'll do in the next video
is that we'll actually move into Eclipse,
we'll create a new project,
and we'll get it all set up to use Spring,
so I'll see you there.