All right, so let's go ahead
and move into Eclipse.
What we're gonna focus on in this video
is setting up our Spring MVC configuration,
and in particular, adding the JAR files to a Spring project.
So the first thing I'll do is actually go through
and create a new project.
So I'll go to File &gt; New,
and I'll choose Dynamic Web Project.
And the actual name I'll give for the project,
I'll call it spring-mvc-demo.
And once you're happy with that name,
keep all of the other defaults and then hit Finish.
Okay, great.
So now we have this very basic project that's empty.
There's not much there right now.
So the next you want to do is actually
copy over the Spring JAR files from our previous download,
and we're actually gonna place them into this lib directory
in WEB-INF/lib.
So let me swing back over to my file system
into that Downloads directory, and this is where
we downloaded the Spring Framework JAR files earlier
in a previous video.
So we already have this ZIP file unzipped, or uncompressed.
I'll expand this directory here,
and I'll go into the libs directory,
and this is where we have all of the Spring JAR files.
So this is from the Spring Framework, the core JAR files.
And I'll go ahead and just select all of the .jar files
located in this directory, and I'll highlight all of them
and then I'm gonna simply copy them.
And then I'll move back over to Eclipse,
I'll move into this WEB-INF/lib directory,
and this is a special directory
where we place the JAR files.
I'll simply do a right-click and choose Paste,
and by putting them in the WEB-INF/lib directory,
they're automatically on our build path.
They're automatically on our class path.
So this looks good so far.
Now there's some additional files that we're gonna need.
Basically what we're gonna do now
is copy over some JAR files
from the Udemy source code download.
So in a previous lecture, I gave you a link to download
the Udemy source code for this class.
So you simply download that ZIP file
and unzip it, or uncompress it,
and then inside of this directory here,
we have some supporting files that we're gonna use,
and in particular, we're gonna make use
of some starter files.
So in this directory structure here,
go to spring/mvc/starter-files/spring-mvc-demo/lib.
So go ahead and grab those files.
Just do a right-click and choose Copy,
and we're gonna put those into our Eclipse project also.
And then we'll swing back over to Eclipse,
and in the lib directory, we'll hit Paste.
All right, so we're kind of good to go right now.
So at this point, we have the Spring Framework JAR files,
and the JSTL support JAR files.
So this is good so far.
We're in good shape.
In the next video, we'll start moving in
some of the Spring configuration files,
so I'll see you there.