Alrighty so let's go ahead and move forward,
so we're gonna go ahead and copy over some
of the starter config files for our Spring project.
So let's swing back over to our files system
where we have our classroom files or our starter files
and what I want to do now is look
into starter-files/Spring-mvc-demo/config
and inside of this directory there's
two starter files that we're gonna use.
Spring-mvc-demo-servlet.xml and web.xml
And then we'll move over to our Web-INF directory
and then we'll paste them directly here.
So you paste them into the WEB-INF directory.
Alright great so at this point we should
have Spring-mvc-servlet.xml and web.xml,
and the reason I like to use these as starter files,
is because this is normally a common source
of problems that folks will have, incorrect XML files
and they can never get Spring MVC working.
So even myself, whenever I start a new project,
I have starter files that I copy and paste
from just to get myself started
because you can waste a lot of
time trying to get this working.
Alright so here's step one,
configuring a dispatcher servlet upfront.
This is the same information that we had from our slides,
and then step two is setting up the URL mapping.
So we're basically gonna map the URL pattern of just
slash basically all the web requests coming in.
We're gonna map it to our dispatcher servlet,
or our front controller,
that's part of the Spring MVC frameworks.
Alright so that's the web XML part of it.
Now let's go ahead and look at
this spring-mvc-demo-servlet.xml.
So this is really just a Spring configuration file,
and a lot of this will look familiar to you,
especially this lines 14 and 15,
we're simply setting up components scanning,
so again, base package of com.luv2code.springdemo.
Step 4 we're adding support
for conversion formatting and validation.
We give the MVC:annotation-driven,
and then finally we set up this Spring MVC view resolver.
So again remember we can specify a prefix
and a suffix and this is where the view pages
will be located and Spring will automatically
add these values whenever you give a view name.
So this directory here or this folder,
we actually have to create this,
we have WEB-INF, but we don't have a /view/.
So this is something that we'll
actually have to create here in Eclipse.
Let's go ahead and do that now.
Alright so lets kind of swing back over.
So under WEB-INF we need to create a new folder here.
So I'll simply right click on WEB-INF
and I'll say New Folder,
and then the actual folder name it's very simple,
we just call it View,
and we'll keep all the other defaults
and then we'll hit Finish.
Alright cool so we have this view folder now.
So we have all the basic stuff in place
and set up for our Spring application.
Now we need to actually write some code (laughs)
and we'll do that the following videos.
So I'll give you a quick video
on how to create a controller class
and a view and then we'll actually write
our own controller class and views,
but anyways making sure we have
our Spring MVC project set up
and I dunno, we're good for now,
so I'll see you in the next video.