In this video,
we're gonna learn how to configure
a Spring container using Java code.
So instead of configuring our container using XML,
instead what we're gonna do is make use of Java source code
to configure the container.
When we use Java source code to configure the container,
there's actually no requirement for XML,
so this will be a pure Java configuration.
So just as a reminder,
there's three ways of configuring a Spring container,
and we've gone through the first two,
so the first one here is a full XML config
where you'll list each bean in the XML file.
The second approach was the XML component scan,
and we made use of annotations,
and it would simply scan and look for classes
with the at component annotation.
It made the XML a little bit smaller.
And this next one we're gonna take a look at here
is a Java configuration class.
So you simply write Java source code
to actually configure the container.
And the important thing here is that
there's actually no use of XML
when you make use of option three,
the Java configuration class.
Now here's the development process,
and we'll go through this step by step.
So the first step is that we create a Java class
and we annotate it as at configuration.
Step two is add component scanning support
with at component scan,
and this is an optional step.
Step three is reading the Java configuration class
in our main application.
And then finally with step four,
we retrieve the bean from the Spring container.
All right, so let's go look at each one of these steps
in detail.
So in step one, we simply create the Java class
and we annotate it as at configuration.
And so at this point,
I have a class called sport config at configuration.
It's an empty config right now.
There's not anything there.
We need to go through and add some steps as far as
adding some beans to this configuration.
Now this one leads us up to step two
of adding component scanning.
So we could manually add beans.
We'll talk about that later,
but for right now, we'll take the easy approach
and we simply say component scan.
So we'll make use of that same at component
that we used in previous examples,
and it would simply tell Spring to scan a given package,
and it works exactly like it worked in the XML,
we're simply scanning for classes
that support at component,
and it'll automatically register those with the container.
Now with step three,
we simply read the Spring configuration class
that we've just created.
So in our main program,
we make use of this new class
called annotation config application context.
Big word.
And we simply give a reference there
to the configuration class that we just created,
sport dot config.
So it'll actually create the Spring container
based on that Java source configuration,
and make the context available for us.
And then finally here,
just like we've seen before,
once your context is created,
you simply retrieve a bean.
So here I say context get bean,
you give the bean name, and there you go, that's it.
So this is very similar to what we've already seen
in all the other configuration methods.
So that's the basic process.
We're gonna move ahead into the next video.
We're gonna dive into Eclipse
and we'll actually build this out using some Java code.