Let's go ahead and move into Eclipse
and let's get our hands dirty writing some code.
So again, our development process,
we'll walk through this step-by-step.
We'll start off here with our first step
of creating a Java class
and then we'll annotate it as a configuration.
So here I'll simply create a new class
and I'll give the @Configuration annotation.
I'll simply right-click on my package.
I'll say New, Class.
And for the name of the class,
I'll do just like the slides.
I'll say SportConfig and that's it.
We can keep all the other defaults and hit Finish.
Okay, great, it gives me a very basic class.
I'm going go ahead and expand my window here for a second.
And the first thing I like to do
as far as my step one is that
I like to add the annotation here.
So I'll add the @Configuration annotation.
This basically will tell spring,
hey, this is a Java configuration
and follow the appropriate rules or directions here
in this configuration file.
Alright, now we have our very basic SportConfig.
But it's empty.
There's nothing in it.
There's no beans to find. Nothing.
So we need to somehow go by and fix that.
And we'll do that right now.
Step two is that we're going to
add component scanning support
by simply adding the @ComponentScan annotation.
And you simply give the actual package
that you want to use to have spring to start scanning.
And, again, this works exactly like XML component scanning.
They'll simply scan this package,
find all the classes that have the @Component annotation
and then register them in the spring container.
So, again, exactly the same as what you've learned so far.
Instead, here we're simply using
a Java class for setting this up.
But in the previous examples we used XML.
Again, exactly the same there.
Alright, so this looks pretty good.
We have our very basic Java configuration class set up.
We have the @Configuration annotation.
And we also tell it to do the component scanning
with the @ComponentScan annotation.
Now what we need to do is set up our main program.
What I'll do is I'll do some copy/paste programming
here for this.
I'll actually start with our AnnotationDemoApp.
So I'll simply just copy this AnnotationDemoApp.
With just a right-click, choose Copy.
And then I'll simply paste it
by doing a right-click and Paste.
And for the new name here I'll call it JavaConfigDemo.
I'll take off the 2 at the end and leave it at that.
So, JavaConfigDemoApp and once you're happy with all of that
then hit the Okay button.
We have this new file here JavaConfigDemoApp.
Open it up.
Expand the window.
And, again, pretty much everything like we've seen before.
We're only going to make one slight change here.
On lines 9 through 11, instead of reading the XML file,
we're going to instead make use of our
spring java configuration class that we just created.
I'll make use of that class here
called AnnotationConfigApplicationContext.
I'll simply copy that name because
that's one big name there.
Actually, I'll fix the imports first here.
I fixed the import, okay, so I have it.
Then I'll simply copy AnnotationConfigApplicationContext
and paste it right there.
So, no more XML.
No more XML!
We're going to make use of our
annotation configuration class.
So I'll say SportConfig.class.
That's the class that we just created.
And that's it.
That's how you read your spring config java class.
Let me even update my documentation here.
So read spring config java class.
Okay, that looks good.
So we're in good shape here.
Now the final step, step four.
Nothing new.
That step is basically retrieving the bean
from the container.
And it's the exact same process you've seen before.
We already have a application context created.
We simply say
context, get bean, tennis coach.
And that's it.
Everything else is the same.
So really lines 10 through 12,
those are the only changes here
that we made for this example.
So let's go ahead and run the application.
Right-click, Run As, Java App.
Then we open it up and oh, yeah!
So this app is going to work exactly the same.
The only difference here is
that instead of reading the configuration
from an XML file, we're actually reading it
from our Java class.
Our Java class that's configured,
it's handling all of the configuration
of the spring container.
At this point there's no XML being used.
We can verify that by looking here in the spring logs
where it says AnnotationConfigAppContext
so that we know that it's actually reading our
Java configuration class for handling or managing
this spring configuration.
So this is great.
We made some good progress here.
We were successful.
And, again, I'd like to say great job.