In this video,
we're gonna define beans with Java code.
Earlier in the course,
we learned how to define beans using XML,
so we would list each bean out separately
in the XML file.
Well, now we're making use of these
Java configuration classes.
Right now our classes are empty.
We're actually gonna add beans into this class,
and we're gonna do it with no XML.
Let's take a look at a new class.
We're gonna introduce here our new coach
called SwimCoach.
He's gonna implement the Coach interface,
and it's a plain old Java class
with no special annotations.
So we'll have a coach.
He'll also have a fortune service implementation,
and we'll learn how to inject that fortune service
using just raw Java code.
So here's the development process
kind of step by step.
So the first thing we're gonna do is
define methods to expose the bean,
then we'll inject the bean dependencies,
then we'll read this Spring configuration class
in our main program,
and then finally we'll retrieve the bean
from the Spring container.
So we have a lot of things here,
but we'll, of course, we'll go through it
step by step.
So let's start with the first step,
defining a method to expose the bean.
So in our configuration class, SportConfig,
we're gonna make use of a new annotation
called @Bean, so this basically defines a bean.
So here we'll provide a method called SwimCoach
that returns Coach.
Internally inside of this method,
we actually create a new instance of this bean.
So I say mySwimCoach = new SwimCoach,
return mySwimCoach.
So the method name here, SwimCoach,
that's the actual bean ID that will be registered
by the Spring container.
And in this example,
notice we're not using component scan.
In this configuration, we're actually gonna define
each bean individually within this configuration class.
The next question you may have is like,
well, what about our dependencies?
How will we inject our dependencies?
Because we know that a coach needs
a fortune service dependency.
So how will we do that,
or how will we pull it in?
And I'll show you how in this next slide.
In step two, to actually inject the bean dependencies,
we make use of this @Bean,
and we define the bean here for happyFortuneService.
So again, I'll create another method here
called happyFortuneService that returns
a new instance of happyFortuneService.
Now, the bean method name here, happyFortuneService,
that's the actual bean ID
that Spring will use when they register this bean
with the application context.
Then we simply use that later on
when we create the SwimCoach.
We say new SwimCoach,
and then we pass in happyFortuneService.
Note the parens here.
We're actually calling that bean reference up top,
and Spring will intercept that
and handle the quarterly based on the bean configuration.
Then the next step here is reading the
Spring Java configuration class.
So, same thing we saw before, the AnnotationConfig.
We simply give a reference to our SportConfig.class.
And then finally, just for completeness here,
retrieving the bean from the container.
So again, just like we've worked on before,
you simply say context.getBean,
and you simply give the bean ID.
And again, the bean ID's the actual method name
for that @Bean annotation,
so in this case, it's swimCoach.
And that's basically it.
So we went through the gory process
of actually using the Java source code
of the Java config approach
to actually define two beans
and then also inject the dependencies.
So this is really good stuff.
In the next video,
we'll dive into the clips,
and we'll start writing some code.
So I'll see you there.