Alright, I'm excited now.
It's time to write some code.
So we want to make use of our SwimCoach
and our SadFortuneService so we have
to do some prep work first.
The first thing we have to do is
create our SadFortuneService, then we'll go through
and actually build out our SwimCoach.
So that's what we'll start with.
So creating that SadFortuneService, I'll create a new class.
I'll do a right click, I'll say New Class.
And the actual name I'll give for the class is
SadFortuneService 'cause I'm so sad.
And this SadFortuneService is going to implement
an interface so we move down to the Interfaces section
and click on the Add button.
And we'll select FortuneService from that list.
And then we'll hit the okay button.
Okay, great, so we have the interfaces listed here
in the Interfaces section.
Keep all the defaults and hit Finish.
Alrighty, so here's our SadFortuneService.
I'm going to remove some of the auto-generated stuff,
and I'll return the sad fortune,
so Today is a sad day, oh my gosh.
And that's basically it, just a very simply
implementation here of this SadFortuneService.
I just want to mix it up a bit
and give us a different type of fortune service.
Alright, so now the next thing we need
to do for prep work is create the actual SwimCoach.
So I'll do a right click, I'll say New Class,
and the actual name of the class, I'll call it SwimCoach.
And then this SwimCoach also has to implement an interface
so down in the Interfaces section, I'll click
the Add button and I'll choose the Coach interface.
Alright, so here's our SwimCoach
with the Coach interface.
We can keep all the other defaults
and then hit Finish.
Alright, so I'll expand the window here.
And so here's our SwimCoach and we'll keep this
as a plain ole Java object, you know,
no special annotations here for component or anything.
We'll simply just write out a normal SwimCoach.
And remember a swim coach needs a fortune service.
So I'll simply define a field here for fortuneService
and then I'll also define a constructor
so we can make use of constructor injection.
So I'll create SwimCoach FortuneService
and then I'll say theFortuneService
as a parameter being passed in.
And then like any normal constructor, right,
we simply make an assignment.
So here I'll say fortuneService the field equals
theFortuneService the parameter being passed in.
And that will basically take care of it.
So we have our field defined and we also have a constructor
that Spring can use to actually inject
the data or the dependency.
Alright, so let's move on down here
and let's fix up some of our other methods,
remove the auto-generated stuff.
And for daily workout, let's see what
our swim coach will provide for us
as far as a daily workout.
So our swim coach will say, "Swim 1,000 meters
"as a warm up."
Whoa, as a warm up?
Okay, that's a pretty intense workout, coach.
Alrighty, but anyways, so that's our daily workout there.
And then for the fortune, let me get
some white space here at the bottom.
We simply make use of our fortuneService
and we simply say fortuneService.getFortune,
very simple, very straightforward.
So these two methods here getDailyWorkout
and getDailyFortune, we have a very basic
implementation for them here so this kind of follows
with everything that we've seen before
in some of our previous videos.
Alright, so then just kind of just recapping
everything here so our SwimCoach needs a fortune service
and so we set it up where the fortuneService will be
passed in, the SwimCoach constructor and setup.
So we're in good shape here.
This is all our prep work taken care of.
In the next video we'll get down and dirty
and start doing the bean definitions.
So I'll see ya there.