Okay, so let's go ahead
jump into our development process.
The first thing we're gonna do here
is define a method to expose the bean.
Then we'll add this to our Java configuration class.
So moving into our actual Java config,
our SportConfig.Java, defining a method to expose a bean.
So I'll just simply put in some comments
here just to kind of keep myself on track.
So here I'll say define bean
for our sad fortune service.
And then I'll also define our bean
for our swim coach.
And inject dependencies for the swim coach.
Ooh, a lot of good stuff here.
Alright, so let me get some white space here
at the bottom to kind of stretch out.
And up top I'll define a bean for our sad fortune service.
So I'll start with that at bean annotation.
And then I'll define a method here,
public FortuneService, sadFortuneService.
We can give any method name we want,
the method name is the actual bean ID
that's registered.
And then here I'll say return new
and then I'd create an instance
of that sad fortune service.
Let's just go through and fix the imports
here on the far left.
Import bean from the Spring framework.
And there we go, we've manually defined
our bean for our sadFortuneService.
And again, remember, the method name's
the actual bean ID that Spring will use
when they assign it to the container.
We have our first bean taken care of.
Now let's go ahead and take care of our swim coach.
So again, we say at-bean, and then we define a method,
public Coach and then I'll say swimCoach,
and then I simply say return new swim coach.
And I also inject the dependency here.
So here I'll say, I'll actually call that
sad fortune service bean method.
So, I'll put in a space here.
I'll say sadFortuneService.
Open paren, close paren.
Now it's really important here
to not that we're actually calling that bean method
up top on line 13.
So we're actually calling that method
and then it'll give us a reference to the actual bean.
And Spring will actually intercept that
and give us a reference to the object accordingly
based on the bean scope.
But anyway, there we go, so that's how
we inject the sadFortuneService
into our coach bean,
or our swim coach bean.
So that's our sad fortune service bean
that we've defined manually
and then also our swim coach
that we've defined manually.
So this looks pretty good.
So we've written a code in our configuration class
to actually define our beans manually.
Good job.
Now let's move back over.
We need a main program.
So I'm gonna do some more of my copy paste programming.
Please forgive me.
Don't judge me.
I'll go to this Java config demo app,
I'll right click and I'll choose copy.
And then I'll do a right click and I'll choose paste.
And the new name that I'll give,
I'll call it SwimJavaConfigDemo,
remove the two at the end.
So SwimJavaConfigDemoApp.
Ah, long name but we'll keep it,
we'll take it and we'll hit okay.
So let's go ahead and open up this SwimJavaConfigDemoApp.
So lines 10 through 13, or 10 through 12 actually,
takes care of our step three of reading
the Java config file.
We've seen that already.
And then line 15 is actually reading
or retrieving a bean from the container.
So we say get bean, swim coach.
So again, remember the actual bean method name
defined in our config file.
That's the actual bean id that we'll use here
for retrieving that bean reference.
So there we go.
So we have the bean.
We can call some methods on it,
getDailyWorkout, getDailyFortune, and so on.
So that's it.
One thing I want to do is go back to our configuration,
our SportConfig.Java.
I actually want to make one small enhancement
or one small change here.
So on line eight, I want to comment out the ComponentScan.
Here I don't want to do any component scanning
'cause I simply only want to make use
of the two beans that I've manually defined.
So just comment out line eight.
Alright, so now we're at a point
where we can actually go ahead and run the application.
So I'll simply do a right click,
and I'll choose Run As Java application.
Oh yeah!
So here we go, our swim coach says,
"Hey, swim 1000 meters as a warm up."
Really?
And then also Today is a sad day.
So the sad day portion, that's what we're getting
from our SadFortuneService.
So this works out as desired.
So instead of a sad day, it's actually a happy day
because we were successful here
in doing Java configuration of our Spring beans manually.
Woo hoo!
Good job.