In this video,
we're going to learn how to inject values
from a properties file.
So we'll make use of our Swim Coach
and we'll also use as properties file.
This properties file is going to have
the email address, and a team.
And we want to read information from this properties file
and inject it into our Swim Coach to make use of.
Again, I love doing everything step-by-step,
so here's our development process.
The first thing is creating the properties file,
then we'll actually load the properties file
into our Spring configuration.
And then next, we'll actually reference the values
from the properties file.
So starting with step one, creating the properties file.
Very simple.
You simply open up a text editor,
create a file that has name-value pairs,
so the name of the property is foo.email,
the value is myeasycoach, and we repeat the
same process for foo.team.
And that's it.
Save the properties file as sport.properties.
Then in step two, we actually need
to load the properties file into our Spring config.
So again, you make use of that Java-based configuration,
our public class SportConfig, we make use of this
new annotation up top called @PropertySource,
and then you simply give a reference to where
your properties file is located.
So in this example, were going to say that
our file is located on our class path,
and the actual name of the file is sport.properties.
So here's step three, referencing the values from
the properties file.
So here's our Swim Coach,
and basically what we need to do now
is actually inject, or reference those values
from the properties.
So here, the Swim Coach is going to have two fields here,
for email address and team.
And what we'll do is we'll actually make use
of field level injection.
So to inject those values,
I simply make use of this annotation called @Value,
and then I give the actual name of the property.
Now I placed the name of the property
inside of a dollar sign curly brace,
and then here, foo.email.
It'll inject that value into our field
and our class called email.
We simply repeat the process again
here for the next property, foo.team,
so @Value("$").
It injects it into the team field.
And then later on, the Swim Coach
can use those values to maybe display some information
so on and so forth.
So that's basically how you reference values
from properties files.
You simply make use of the @Value annotation.
What we'll do in the next video,
is that we'll move into Eclipse, and we'll actually
write all the code to make this happen.
So I'll see you in the next video.