Alright, so let's move into Eclipse
and let's get ready to write some code!
So here starting with our development process,
the first thing we need to do
is create our Properties File.
That's gonna hold our name value pairs
of the data that we want to inject.
So what I'll do is on my source directory,
I'll do a right click, and say new file
and make sure you select the source directory there,
new file.
The actual name of the file that I'll have
is sport.properties,
and again make sure that it's in the source directory,
cause that's our actual class path for our application,
and then go ahead and select the finish button.
Alright, so we have an empty file right now.
So now what we need to do is add some name value pairs here
to this file.
So the first property is foo.email
and the actual email address is myeasycoach@luv2code.com.
My second property name is foo.team
and then I give the actual team name of Awesome Java Coders,
that's us, yeah!
Alright, so that's our properties file.
Once you're happy with that, go ahead and save it.
So that pretty much takes care of step one.
Now we need to get ready for step two,
and that's actually loading the Properties File
into our Spring config.
So we go back to our Java class,
our SportConfig.Java, right?
We're doing this Java based configuration here.
And let's move down to line seven.
Just right after line seven,
we're gonna add a new entry here.
So line eight, will actually make a reference
to that annotation.
We'll make use of that annotation Add Property Source
and then we simply give the location
of that Properties File, classpath:sport.properties.
I'll go ahead and fix the imports.
And there we go, so this looks pretty good.