Alright, so we're making
really good progress here.
So in step three we're actually gonna reference
the values from the properties file.
So I'll move over to my SwimCoach class.
Expand the window here.
And basically what I wanna do is define two fields.
And inject them accordingly.
So here I'll set up my first field for email
and then my second field for team.
And then just like what we saw in the slides
we make use of that @value annotation to inject
the actual value from the properties file.
And we place that inside a dollar sign curly brace
and we give the property name of foo.email.
Let me go ahead and fix the imports here
for @value annotation.
So that looks good.
And so there you go so right here foo.email
that's the actual property name from the actual config file
or the properties file.
And it will basically inject that value into our field here
called email.
So this is field level injection.
Now let's do a similar process here for team.
So again make use of the property name
inside the dollar sign curly brace so foo.team.
And again it injects it into the actual field called team.
So there we are, so we're in good shape right now.
So this looks really, really good.
Now let's go ahead and modify this coach class
this swim coach class will actually make use of
those new fields here.
So what I'm gonna do here is actually generate some
getter methods.
So I'll simply do a right-click Source,
generate getter setters.
And I'll expand the options here.
I simply wanna expose or generate getter methods
so I wanna generate a get email and also a get team.
We could manually write it out if we wanted to
but here just making use of Eclipse to help me out.
Select those options, hit OK.
And then there we go, so good.
So lines 29 through 35 these are the new methods
that were just generated by Eclipse
to give us the values for email and team.
So this is great, I'm happy with this so far.
Alright so I'll go ahead and save this.
And let me scroll back just take a look at everything,
so this looks good.
Alright, so I think we're good to go here.
Alright so let's go ahead
and move into our SwimJavaConfigDemo App.
This is our main program.
We're gonna make some slight modifications
here in this file.
The first mod I wanna make is on line 14.
I wanna change the actual class here to SwimCoach.
Because I wanna make use of the special methods
that I just added to SwimCoach the get team
and the get email make the changes here accordingly
on the left hand side and also on the right hand side.
Because SwimCoach has new methods that are not available
in the normal Coach interface, and that's the get email
and get team method.
Alright so now down here at the bottom we simply
go ahead and make use of our new methods.
Take it for a test drive.
And these new methods is gonna make use
of those property values that were actually injected
into that SwimCoach class from the Props file.
Alright so system out print line.
I'll simply print out the email.
So theCoach.getEmail.
And I'll simply do a copy, paste here.
And I'll do a similar thing for the team.
So line 24 I simply say team
and then I say theCoach.getTeam.
So again we're making use of those new methods
that are available in the SwimCoach class.
So this looks pretty good so far.
So this is great, I'm kind of excited about this.
I'm anxious, I'm ready to run it.
Alright so we save everything.
We right-click and choose Run As, Java Application.
Let's run it.
Oh and this looks good.
I'm getting excited, I'm getting happy.
Look at that, email myeasycoach@luv2code.com.
And team Awesome Java Coders.
And it's reading all that information
from the properties file.
So we're actually injecting data from the Props file
into our Java class, love it.
This is awesome, I'm so happy.
So I'd like to say good job, congratulations and woohoo!