In this video,
we're gonna learn about bean scopes with annotations.
And we've already used bean scopes before
with XML declarations,
but here we'll actually make use of with annotations.
And again, remember the bean scope basically says
how long the bean lives,
how many instances are created,
and also how was the bean shared?
And as a quick refresher here,
the default scope for all beans in Spring is singleton.
And just to jog your memory,
singleton, it's basically a single instance of the bean.
It's cached in memory
and all requests for the bean
will return a shared reference to the same bean.
So here's a nice diagram
that's just gonna show you how it works.
So in this case, tennis coach is singleton,
so when you get a reference of the tennis coach,
saying coach that coach equals
context get bean tennis coach
you get one link,
and then you say coach alpha coach
equals context get bean tennis coach,
it gives you the same reference.
So basically these two variables here,
the coach and alpha coach,
they both point to the same area of memory.
So it's a singleton bean.
Now you can also explicitly specify the bean scope
and you can do that using annotations,
and it's really, really straightforward here,
basically have at scope,
and then you simply specify the scope and commence.
So in this case, we say the tennis coach
is a singleton scope.
Prototype scope basically says
it's gonna create a new object for each request.
And again, to specify the scope,
I simply give at scope,
and I give the actual scope in parens or quotes here.
So in this example, I'll set the scope to prototype.
Now again, if I make that modification,
then every time I reference that tennis coach bean,
it's gonna create a new object for each request.
So in this example,
coach a coach points to one area of memory,
and then when I say coach alpha coach get bean,
it'll create a new object,
so you have two different objects out there
pointing at two different areas of memory.
That's prototype scope.
All right, so this looks really good.
We'll move into Eclipse
and we'll actually write some code using scopes
with annotations.