Let's move into Eclipse and let's
get ready to write some code.
The first thing I wanna do here is create
a new main class for this demo.
So I'll simply select my package here
and I'll do a right click
and I'll say New Class.
And the actual name for this class
I'll call it AnnotationBeanScopeDemoApp.
I know that's a lot of words there but,
let's be very specific here.
AnnotationBeanScopeDemoApp.
We're also gonna make use of that main method
so check the box there for Main at the bottom.
And then keep all the other defaults
and hit Finish.
Okay, this looks really good here.
So we have our very basic app here.
Let's go ahead and clear out the auto generated comments
and let's go ahead and provide my own comments
just to kind of again,
keep myself on track as far as
the code I need to write for this application.
And this will really just be
the same old Bootstrap code that you saw before
as far as reading in the config file,
and then retrieving a bean from the Spring container.
So let's go ahead and do this first part
right now so we're gonna use that class
path xml application context.
We'll say context = new.
Again, my little copy paste trick here.
And in parens, I'll give the actual configuration
file name.
So applicationContext.xml
Alright, looks good.
Looks good.
Let me fix the imports actually.
Import, alright good.
So line three, we have our imports in here.
We're good to go.
Great.
Let me stretch out here,
give myself some white space at the bottom.
Now let's go ahead and retrieve the bean from the
container.
So I'll go ahead and save a Coach = context,
I get bean.
And I'll retrieve that TennisCoach.
Now is it Coach.class?
So that's for the Coach and let's do a similar thing
here, so I'm just gonna copy, paste
line 14.
So I copied it, I pasted it on Line 16
and then I'll have Alpha Coach.
So I'm basically making two requests
for that bean from the spring container.
Now what I wanna do is actually check to see
if they're the same object.
So here I'll say, boolean result =
and then I'll check to see if the Coach
is equal, equal, alphaCoach.
Basically are they pointing to the same area
of memory?
I have that assigned into a variable called Result.
Now let's go ahead and print out some information.
Let's print out the results
of our comparison.
Use my sysout print line.
Pointing to the same object and I'll simply
append that variable that we have, results.
So that's our boolean of true or false.
And now I'll go through and actually
print out the memory location
for our first object, the Coach.
Simply do an append
with the Coach.
There we go.
So that takes care of that.
Looks pretty good.
Just give me some white space.
And I'll do a similar thing here
for alphaCoach.
Memory location for alphaCoach.
And a similar thing here,
the append, alphaCoach.
So this will basically just print out
the two string method here.
Now the actual class name
and the memory location.
So that's it.
Just basic coding here,
just printing out results.
Alright, so this looks good so far.
And as usual, I'm always gonna be nice,
and I'll simply close the Spring application
context.
So that's our coding here.
We load the Spring config file,
retrieve the beans from the container,
check to see if they're the same,
and then finally we simply print out the results.
Alrighty, so let's go ahead and run this application,
do a right click, Run As Java application.
And let's check out the results here.
Alright, TennisCoach inside default constructor.
That looks okay.
And it says, Pointing to the same object: true.
Because the default scope is singleton.
We haven't changed the scope or anything.
And memory location for the Coach
is this 78 alpha and memory location
for alphaCoach is 78 alpha.
Great, so they're both pointing
to the same area of memory.
So it really is a singleton scope here
for that TennisCoach object.
And I just fix the little typo I had
in that print line.
So anyway, that's good.
Now let's go ahead and change the scope
on our TennisCoach.
And we're gonna use that annotation
@Scope.
And the scope I'll change it to
is Prototype.
I'll go ahead and fix the imports here.
And we'll save this.
Okay.
That looks good.
The imports are okay, great.
Happy with that.
So again, prototype scope
means that it's gonna create a new instance
every time.
So whenever they make a request for TennisCoach,
from the Spring container,
it's gonna create a new instance every time.
Alright, so I'm moving back to my
AnnotationBeanScopeDemoApp
and I'll just run it.
Right click, run it as Java application.
And our application's running.
Okay, now couple of things here.
Prototype scope.
It's gonna create a new instance every time
so we see two constructors being called.
So they're calling the constructor twice
meaning that they're creating two objects.
Alright, that looks pretty good.
That's kind of what I was expecting.
Pointing to the same object is false
because now, prototype scope
there's a new object for each request
and then also check the memory locations.
The memory locations here
are different for the Coach
and alphaCoach.
So it really is prototype scope.
It's creating a new object every time.
This is great.
I'm happy.
We made use of that @Scope annotation
to give us the desire output
for singleton and also for prototype.
So I'll say good job,
congratulations and you are rockin' and rollin' baby.