In this video, we're gonna learn
about bean lifecycle methods with annotations.
So remember in Spring, you can actually add some custom code
that will execute during bean initialization,
but you can also add code to run during bean destruction.
And the very basic development process here
that you simply define your methods
for initialization and destroy
and then all you do is you add annotations to those method
and the annotation that you'll use
is @PostConstruct and @PreDestroy.
So, for initialization, you can choose
any method that you want, give it any method name,
and you simply annotate it with @PostConstruct.
So, as the annotation says, this code will execute
after the bean has been constructed.
So, this is where you can place your own
custom initialization work.
And likewise, you can actually write
some custom code here for destroy.
So, before your bean is destroyed
you can annotate a method with @PreDestroy
and then you can write your own
custom clean-up code to execute.
And that's pretty much it.
Very simple, very straightforward.