Alright, let's go ahead and write some code.
So we're gonna follow our development process here.
Define init and destroy methods and add the annotations.
Alright, so the first thing we need to do is
change the scope on tennis coach.
In the previous videos, we were playing around
with the scope and then we had scopes at the prototype.
I actually wanna remove the prototype scope.
I wanna just go back to using our default scope
which is singleton scope.
Alright, so I remove that, save this file.
And now what I'd like to do is go through
and actually define our init and destroy methods,
and actually set up the annotations for them.
So first off I'll just go ahead
and write some comments to myself
just so I can keep myself on track.
Alright, so my comments are in place.
Alright, so let's go ahead and dig in
and let's start writing some code.
I'll start right here with my init method
and I'll call it do my start up stuff
and inside I'll simply just do a print line
just so I know that Spring's actually
call init's method and doing something.
So here I'll just put tennis coach,
and then I'll say inside, do my start up stuff.
(writing some code...)
And that's the method and add my annotation,
whoops I almost forgot.
So here I'll say @postconstruct.
Just to let Spring know that
hey call this one once you construct the object.
I'll go ahead and fix the imports here.
And that looks OK, so let me just step back
and admire my beautiful work and yeah, looks good.
Looks good to me.
Well, let's go ahead and move on down and let's just
repeat the process here for our destroy method.
So again, we can give it any method name
so I'll call it do my clean up stuff.
And again, I'll do my system out print line,
and I'll simply print out what's happening inside of my
do clean up stuff method.
Make sure I add the annotation here.
So I'll say @predestroy,
and again you'll be able to fix the imports.
And basically there's my destroy method
along with the appropriate annotation.
Looks pretty good.
Well, I think my work is done here
right now on tennis coach.
Let's go ahead and move back over to
our main program annotation demo app.
So I'm in annotation demo app.
Again, this is our same main program that we've used before.
No changes here.
And I'll simply just do a right click and run it.
Run this baby. Run this program.
So our program's running now.
We can go take a look at some of the output.
So here inside default constructor, that's good.
And, oh yeah! Inside of do my start up stuff.
Yeah, that's the @postconstruct word, I like that.
Very good, very good.
And then finally here,
inside of do my clean up stuff, so that's @predestroy,
so our custom hooks are in place.
They're executing as desired and I think we're good to go.
So we add some annotations here
to handle bean life-cycle methods.
Congratulations. Good job!