In this video,
we're going to learn how to read HTML form data
using the @RequestParam annotation.
So we'll actually work through a code example
similar what we've already worked on,
where were going to read the form data,
covert the name to uppercase,
and add the uppercase version to the model.
And you saw some of the coding for this already
with the Let's Shout Dude,
where we would read the student's name,
by saying request.getParameter("studentName"),
assigning it and then doing some work with it later on.
Now what we're going to do is use a different technique
for reading in the form data.
So Spring has a special annotation called @RequestParam.
This will allow you to read form data,
and automatically bind it to a parameter
coming into your method.
So here in this example, I make use of @RequestParam,
and I give studentName.
So behind the scenes, Spring will actually read that data
from the request parameters,
and then it will take that data and bind it
to this variable that I have here called theName.
All right, so Spring will read the request parameter,
and bind it to variable theName, and at that point
we have the variable and we can use it
in our application.
But the key here is that Spring
has that special annotation here called
@RequestParam for reading form data for you.
All right, this looks really good.
Let's go ahead and move into the next video,
and let's jump into Eclipse, and let's write some code,
and let's try this out.
So, I'll see you there.