All righty, so let's go ahead
and move into Eclipse and what we're gonna do here
is make use of that @RequestParam annotation binding
for our controller methods.
So, what I'll do is I'll actually move
into my Hello World controller and I'm gonna make use
of a little copy/paste example here.
I'm basically gonna copy everything I had
from processFormVersionTwo and then I'll just make
some small changes to it.
So, let me go ahead and highlight everything here
for this processFormVersionTwo.
All right, so I have everything in highlight
and let's just go ahead and just do a copy on this.
So, I'll simply do a right click and choose copy.
And, then I'll move a little further down here
in this Hello World controller
and I'm gonna paste this information
and again make some small changes here.
So, I'll right do a click and choose paste.
So, a couple things here.
First off, I'll actually change the actual RequestMapping
so instead of processFormVersionTwo,
we'll call it processFormVersionThree.
And, then I'll also change the actual method name here
to make the method name different.
So, I'll call it processFormVersionThree.
I don't know, I'm just making it up there, okay?
All right, so those are the basic mods I wanted to make here
for this one.
So, again, a new RequestMapping processFormVersionThree
with a new method name of processFormVersionThree.
So, what I'm gonna do here is change the actual parameters
coming into this actual method.
So, instead of passing in the HttpServletRequest,
I'm actually gonna make use
of that Request binding annotation parameter.
So, I'll use @RequestParam and then give studentName.
So, I'm basically saying I wanna read in the HTML form field
coming into request studentName
and I'm gonna assign it a binder to theName.
So, let me go ahead and fix some of the imports here
for RequestParam.
I'm just highlight over it for one second.
Do an import on RequestParam
from the Spring framework for binding.
I'll take it.
All right, so again, we're basically gonna make use
of this Spring annotation.
So, it's gonna read the http server request
and read that form parameter studentName
and bind it to this Param we have coming into this method
called String theName.
So, now lines 53 through 54, we no longer need this code.
Spring will automatically do this code for us.
So, by effectively adding that @RequestParam
behind the scenes, Spring is doing everything on line 54.
So, I can go ahead, right click this code
and just cut it or delete it.
All right, so we don't need that.
So, that's good to go.
So, we already have this theName coming in already
as a parameter.
So, we're good to go, so there we go String theName.
Now, here we make use of it a little bit later on
and we simply take it and convert it to all caps.
That's all good.
And, I'm simply gonna change the method,
I'm sorry, I'm gonna actually change the message here.
So, instead of saying Yo, then I don't know,
make something else up, Hey My Friend.
And I don't know from v3 or something.
All right, so I simply wanted to create a new message here
just to make it unique and distinct from the previous one
that we worked on for version two.
All right so here's our v3 message.
And then everything else stays the same here.
We simply added to the model and we return helloworld.
So, that's basically it.
So, I have a new handler method here
in my Hello World controller called processFormVersionThree.
We make use of the @RequestParam
for annotation parameter binding.
And, I don't know, this looks pretty good.
So, I need to take this actual path here
and I need to update my HTML form.
So, processFormVersionThree, I'll simply right click,
I'll choose copy, and then I'll go back to the form,
helloworldform.jsp and I update this.
So, instead of versionTwo, then I'll simply right click
and choose and do a paste for versionThree.
All right, so I just wanna make sure that my form
is pointing to the right code that I wanna execute here
for this video.
All right, so this looks good.
So, let's go ahead and save our form.
And let's go ahead and run our application.
So, just right click, Spring-MVC-demo.
Choose Run As and then choose Run On Server.
And I'll go ahead and just choose the link here
to take a look at the form.
And, now this form's been updated to point to VersionThree
so I'll just enter some student name here.
Just enter the name of Mary, hit submit.
And, now the message Hey My Friend from v3
and then Mary in all caps.
So, this is great.
So, we know that it really is reading our new code
for VersionThree and it's making use
of that @RequestParam binding.
So, anyways, just wanted to show you an example
of using that @RequestParam and how it works out
for reading form data.
Nice little shortcut for you.
So, good job and I'll see you in the next video.