In this video,
we're going to learn how to add controller request mappings.
So you can actually define a request mapping
at the controller level, so it basically
serves as like the parent mapping for the controller.
All of the request mappings on the methods
are actually relative to the controller's path.
And this is very similar to setting up
a folder directory structure where you have
a parent directory, and you have subdirectories
underneath it.
A similar thing here with using request mappings.
All right, so let's look at a coding example.
So here we have our funny controller.
We're going to add a controller mapping for it.
@RequestMapping/controller,
so that's the parent mapping,
then all other mappings on methods within this controller
are actually relative to it.
So for show form, we'd have /funny/showForm,
so all of the method mappings are relative to
the actual controller mapping.
And this is just a very nice way
for you to group your request mappings together,
and also a great technique
for resolving any problems or conflicts that you may have
with other request mappings.
All right, so that's the basic layout here.
In the next video, I'll actually show you a problem.
I'll show you a conflict where we have
two request mappings that have the same name,
and then I'll show you how we can resolve it
by making use of controller request mappings.
Alrighty, so I'll see you on the next video.