All right.
So let's go ahead and move into Eclipse here,
and let's actually kind of walk through
this scenario where we have conflicts in request paths.
So what I'll do is I'll actually create
a new controller,
and I'll try and break things on purpose.
We already have this helloworld controller
that already has a request mapping for showForm,
and I'll create a new controller
that has the exact same request mapping.
And again, let's just try and break this thing,
and let's see what Spring gives us.
And then also, we'll learn how to kind of
resolve this or how to fix it.
All right, so let's go ahead and add
a new controller class here,
so I'll do a right click,
I'll say New Class.
And the actual name, I'll call it SillyController.
(chuckles)
SillyController, get outta here.
And I'll keep all the defaults and hit Finish.
All right, so here's our SillyController.
Up top, we'll give the @Controller annotation
like we always do for our Spring MVC
controllers XD imports.
And now I'll go down here,
and I'll set up a method.
I'll call it displayTheForm.
That just returns silly,
just kind of making this up.
There is no silly view template yet,
but anyway, let's only just check this stuff out.
And again, I'm gonna copy the actual mapping
from the helloworld controller.
So helloworld controller has a mapping of /showForm.
I'm gonna copy this,
and then use that same mapping for silly.
So I'll just do a right click, choose Copy,
move over to sillycontroller,
and do a paste over here.
All right, great.
So different method names,
but the same request mapping, all right?
So the key here is that Spring handles everything
based on a request mapping.
So here, hellworld has show form,
and sillycontroller has show form.
All right, so let's go ahead and save everything,
and let's go ahead and run this application.
Right click, Run As, Run on the Server,
and I will take a look at the console window here.
Ooh, I saw some bad stuff there in the stack trace,
and ugh, see some ugly stuff here in the browser.
Wah! The dreaded 500 error.
And I'm pretty sure you're gonna run into this
during your lifetime as a Spring MVC developer, okay?
So the good thing here is,
let's kind of dig through this
and find out what's happening here.
So error creating a bean,
request mapping,
and it says here that there's already
a helloworld controller,
bean mothod, okay.
All right.
And it says ambiguous mapping, okay?
So could not map sillycontroller method,
because there's already a helloworld controller
bean method ... Ah!
Okay, so it's giving us some information here.
It's saying, hey, you can't use this dude,
because someone else is using it,
the helloworld controller is using it.
So you can see the information here
in this browser window,
but you can also take a look at it
in the console window,
so let's did into that one.
So this is our stack trace of all the stuff.
And a similar thing here, ambiguous mapping,
cannot map sillycontroller.
There's already a helloworld controller bean method.
All right, okay, gotcha, gotcha.
All right, so that's the idea,
so we know that there's a conflict,
and we know that it's ambiguous,
and we somehow need to resolve it.
So let's go ahead and take a look at how we can resolve it.