Well one way to resolve is simply tell
the silly controller, hey go change your mapping.
(chuckle) Go change your stuff.
But for some reason,
for political reason or I don't know,
they don't wanna change it or they don't see fit,
and then you say fine, go ahead and keep your mapping
the way you want it and on the Hello World controller,
we'll give our own path
and then we'll have relative sub-paths
or relative sub-directives
and that's how we'll resolve it here on our side.
So we'll make some changes here
to the Hello World controller to resolve this ambiguity.
So just kinda moving back to the actual...
We're gonna close this window here and
moving back to my Hello World controller,
what I'll do is I'll actually put a parent mapping
up at the top.
So let me expand my window here,
and so I'll set a parent mapping at the top, so I'll say
at request mapping,
and then I give the parent mapping of /hello.
So this is the high-level mapping
or the main directory,
and then you're gonna have sub-mappings off of it,
and so now, all these others show form and process form,
these are all relative to Hello.
So the full path for show form will be hello/showform.
The full path of process form will be hello/processform.
And that will remove that ambiguity.
Now, the one thing I need to do is here is kinda
set up one of the links here that I have
for my initial show form, so in my main menu,
I need to modify that to make use of this /Hello.
So let's go ahead and do that now.
So in my main menu, instead of saying showform directly,
I'm gonna say hello/showform,
so it's gonna call the show form mapping
that's in my Hello World controller,
because I set the parent mapping
for that Hello World controller to be hello.
So that's how we can kinda resolve that issue there,
so now there's no longer a conflict between the two
because now show form is relative to Hello.
So I save everything, go right-click, choose Run As,
run server,
and we see our main menu, which is great,
so that's nice.
And we can also go check out our console,
kinda scroll through.
There's no errors,
and we can see now that we have hello/showform,
hello/processformVersionThree,
processform, process form version two,
so on and so forth.
So it's relative to Hello,
the Hello parent path so far, which is great,
and it maps all of the Hello World controller so far,
so we kinda resolved all the ambiguity,
everything is happy in the Spring World now,
and now we're ready to go, so this is good so far.
So now we simply run back to our application
and now everything is gonna work
just as we had before, so we can enter a student name,
and hit submit,
and everything processes A-okay.
Then note the URL is a little different up top here,
so it has /hello
and then process form version three, blah blah blah.
So we've kinda clarified or
removed that ambiguity that we had a little bit earlier,
and that's by making use of parent request mapping.
So anyway, good stuff here.
You'll probably run into this in the real world, so
I wanted to show you a good example of how to resolve it,
and how to fix it.
Alright, congrats.
Good job.