In this video we're gonna learn
about Spring Dependency Injection with Annotations
and Autowiring.
So we'll continue with the Coach example
where our Coach already provides daily workouts.
Now we'll also provide daily fortunes
and will make use of the FortuneService
and this is a dependency.
We've seen this in previous videos,
but now we're gonna inject this dependency
using annotations and autowiring.
Now what exactly is Spring AutoWiring?
Well, for dependency injection,
Spring can automatically wire up your objects together,
so basically what'll happen is that Spring
will look for a class that matches a given property.
And it'll actually match by type,
so the type could be either the class or the interface.
Once Spring finds a match,
then it'll automatically inject it.
Hence it's called autowired.
So let's take a look at this using an example
and we'll actually make use
of that Coach and FortuneService.
So we need to inject a FortuneService
into a Coach implementation.
So how does it work behind the scenes?
Well, Spring will actually scan all of the components
and it'll say hey, I need to satisfy a dependency.
I need to inject a FortuneService,
so Spring will basically ask,
say hey, is there anyone out there
that implements the FortuneService interface?
If so, Spring will grab that component or bean
and actually inject it.
In our examples that we're gonna work through,
we're gonna actually have a happy FortuneService
which is an implementation of the FortuneService interface
and Spring will find that implementation
and automatically inject it into our class
and that's called Autowiring.
And we'll actually walk through this
with a full code example so if the theory
and the concepts are a little funny to you right now,
don't worry we'll see all the code for it.
Now with this Autowiring,
they actually have three different types of injections.
They have Constructor Injection.
Setter Injection and Field Injection
and we'll cover all of these in this video series,
but we'll simply start off with Constructor Injection.
Now here's the development process
for constructor injection.
And again, I love doing things step-by-step,
so the first thing is that we'll define
the dependency interface and class,
we'll also create a constructor on our class for injections
and then the main point here is that
we'll configure the dependency injection using
that Autowired Annotation
and we'll see all of this step-by-step.
All right, so let's start with step one.
Define the dependency interface and class.
So here we'll have this dependency called FortuneService,
it's simply an interface.
Has a simple method called getFortune, returns a string.
And then we'll actually have
an implementation of this interface
called HappyFortuneService
and they simply provide a very basic implementation.
And we've seen a lot of this before.
The only thing that's new here with the HappyFortuneService
is that we have the @Component annotation there,
so Spring can auto-scan and find this implementation
for the Spring container.
All right, so that's step one.
Now step two is that we need to create
a constructor in our class for injections.
So for our TennisCoach we'll simply add a constructor
and again, the constructor has the same name as the class,
TennisCoach, and then we pass in our dependency,
FortuneService
and we'll make a basic assignment.
But now the real work happens here in step three
where we configure the dependency injection
using that Autowired Annotation.
So this is where you have the real magic here.
So note on our constructor for TennisCoach,
we have Autowired.
So we're basically saying,
the parameter being passed in FortuneService,
we want Spring to automatically wire up this component,
so instead of doing it long-hand, using XML configs,
we're making use of this Autowired annotation.
So again, what happens in the background
is that Spring will say hey,
I need to satisfy this dependency.
So Spring will again, it'll scan all the components there,
it'll find the component that implements
this FortuneService interface,
which in our case is HappyFortuneService.
And it'll take that bean, actually inject it,
or Autowire it here into this TennisCoach.
So that's how they handle the dependency injection
using that Autowired annotation.
So that's the whole idea there.
Now again, stepping back here,
let's kinda look at the big picture again.
Again, we're simply gonna retrieve a Coach object
from our Object Factory.
So now this Object Factory
all the dependencies of the helper objects
are being handled or injected by making use
of annotations and Autowiring.
So all that work is happening
behind the scenes by Spring.
So when we simply retrieve the Coach
we get it fully assembled.
So here there's no assembly required,
we get the Coach object and it's FortuneService
already wired together,
thanks to Spring.
And in the next video,
we'll actually move into clips
and we'll enhance our demo
to make use of annotations and Autowiring.
So I'll see you there.