Let's go ahead and move into Eclipse
and let's get our hands dirty.
Let's write some code.
So looking at our to-do list here,
or our step-by-step,
the first thing we need to do is
define the dependency interface and the class.
And we'll make use of that same dependency from earlier,
fortune service and happy fortune service,
but we'll go ahead and cut the code again from scratch
just so we're all on track
and everything is sinked up.
I'll simply do a right click,
I'll say new interface.
And the name of this interface is FortuneService.
Another name there,
I keep all the other defaults
and I hit finish.
So at this point I have a very basic fortune service.
There's nothing inside of it.
I'm gonna define just one method here,
this method will be called
getFortune.
And open paren, close paren, and a semicolon,
and that's it.
Somethin' very simple.
Not much coding.
We like to keep it short
and we like to keep it sweet.
So there's our fortune service,
now what we wanna do is actually create a class
that'll actually implement this interface.
So I'll move back over here to my package,
I'll do a right click, I'll say new, class.
Now the name of this class will be HappyFortuneService.
So that's the name and then this class
will actually implement an interface.
So down in the interfaces section,
let's click on that button to the right called add.
And the name of the interface that we're looking for
here is called FortuneService.
So I just type in fortune up top,
you'll get this FortuneService listing there
as a matching item.
Then go ahead and hit on the okay button.
So our interfaces section should be updated
with FortuneService.
Looks good.
Let's keep all the other defaults
and let's hit the finish button.
Okay, good.
Here we go.
So we have our HappyFortuneService implements
FortuneService,
we're simply gonna give a very basic
implementation here.
On line seven, I'll simply say return,
and I will say today is your lucky day.
And I'll add the double quote there
and that's it.
So that's a basic implementation here of this
HappyFortuneService.
This looks good.
Now the one thing that we're gonna do different
that we didn't do earlier in the videos
is that we're gonna add this @Component annotation.
Remember Spring will scan our package
and it'll register all components.
So we want this HappyFortuneService
to be a component that's registered.
That looks good and I think we're in good shape so far.
Now the next thing we wanna do is we wanna enhance
our coach interface.
We actually wanna add a method to the coach interface.
Right now the coach can give us daily workouts
but we also want the coach to be able to give us
our daily fortune.
So in coach dot java,
I'm gonna add a new method here called
GetDailyFortune that returns a string.
And that's it.
We keep it very simple for right now.
Okay, great.
This looks good so far.
Good job.