Well, one thing that I just noticed
is that we actually broke the TennisCoach class
that implements Coach,
because we added a new method in Coach,
but we didn't add that new method to TennisCoach.
So let's go ahead and fix this now.
So I'll move into my TennisCoach class,
I'll kinda hover over the error,
and Eclipse can actually help us out.
So we can choose that option there
to Add unimplemented methods,
and that's the method for getDailyFortune.
So down on lines 13 through 17,
this is where Eclipse just added that new method for us.
Just a stub, just a skeleton.
We'll fix it up later.
But at least it resolved that compilation issue that we had.
Now one thing I wanna do right now is just
set up a little private field for the FortuneService,
and we'll actually set it, or inject it, later.
But for now, simply list it out here, FortuneService.
And then, down in my getDailyFortune method,
I'll actually use this FortuneService.
So here I'll say FortuneService.getFortune.
All right, this is great, but now you may have noticed
that we haven't actually initialized the FortuneService yet,
that's not really taken care of.
And we'll take care of that part of it in the next step,
when we cover our constructor injection.
All right, so in Step 2 we need to create a constructor
in our class for injections,
and also we'll need to add in the Autowired annotation,
but we'll kinda do this step by step.
All right, so Step 2, creating a constructor.
So again,
the constructor is always the same name as the class,
so our class is called TennisCoach,
so our constructor will be called TennisCoach.
And I'll just kinda write it out longhand.
I'll say FortuneService theFortuneService,
and internally I'll simply assign it.
So I'll assign fortuneService = theFortuneService;
All right, so we basically just assigned
the parameter being passed in to a field
that we have here in our TennisCoach class.
So this looks good so far.
So now we need to do Step 3,
configure dependency injection
with the Autowired annotation.
Then we can simply go through
and fix the imports here for that.
And up top, on line 3,
we should have the proper import pulled in,
so this looks good.
Okay great, so now we have this constructor injection
with the Autowired annotation,
so for our Coach, they're gonna inject a FortuneService.
So remember, Spring is gonna scan for a component
that implements the FortuneService interface.
So in our example, that's the HappyFortuneService,
it'll actually meet that requirement.
Spring will create an instance of it,
and then inject it here into our TennisCoach.
All right, now let's move over to our main program here,
our AnnotationDemoApp.java.
Take a quick look at that one.
So this is where we actually read in the config file,
we get the container,
we actually get the bean from the container,
and then we call methods on it.
Now what I wanna do
is actually make use of some of those new methods,
or that new method that I added, to get the daily fortune.
So here I'll simply say sysout.println,
and I'll say theCoach.getDailyFortune.
So this is great.
So now we're using that new method,
and that new implementation,
and the fortune is actually being supported
by the FortuneService dependency, our helper,
that's giving us all of our happy fortunes.
So again, just a quick recap here on this AnnotationDemoApp.
Again, our main driver,
we simply read the spring config file,
we get the bean from the container,
call a method,
and then call the daily fortune method,
finally cleanup.
So that's just a recap
of what we had from some of the previous videos here.
All right, so we can save everything,
and then we can right click,
and we can choose Run As a Java Application.
And here's the output, and yeah!
Today's my lucky day.
So we read the config file,
applicationContext.xml does the auto-scanning,
we print out our daily workout,
"Practice your backhand volley".
And then this new item here, which is really cool:
"Today is your lucky day!"
That's our fortune.
Yeah! I'm lucky today.
So that's being actually handled by the dependency,
so they're actually injecting
our FortuneService implementation, HappyFortuneService,
and now our Coach, or our TennisCoach,
can actually use that to provide the desired output.
So this is great.
I'm excited.
I'm fired up.
And you should be happy too,
'cause now you're doing dependency of injection
with Spring Annotations.
You can check that box off,
and you can go brag to your friends
of all this great stuff that you're learning.
All right, I'm having too much fun.
But anyways, good job and congratulations.