In this video, we're going to discuss
setter injection with annotations and autowiring.
So we've covered different injection types so far.
We've covered constructor injection.
Here we're going to focus on setter injection.
Alright, so with this type of injection,
we basically inject dependencies by calling
setter methods on your class.
Now we'll continue to use that same example
that we've worked on so far.
We're basically going to inject a FortuneService
into a Coach implementation.
And again, Spring's going to scan all components
and it'll see if there's anyone
that implements the FortuneService interface,
and if so, then it will inject it.
Here's the development process.
Again, step by the step.
The first step is we're going to create
setter methods in our class for injections
and then in step two, we'll configure
the dependency injection with the Autowired Annotation.
Alright, so here's step one, creating the setter methods
in your class.
So here we have our tennis coach
and then we're going to define a setter method
for the fortuneService.
So we have setFortuneService and they pass in a param
and them we simply assign it.
Again, a very basic setter method here, nothing new.
But now with step two is that we're going
to configure the dependency injection
with the Autowired Annotation.
So in this scenario, in this example,
we're going to add the at-Autowired annotation
right on that method setFortuneService.
Alright, now previously in the previous videos,
we would set the annotation on the actual constructor,
but here instead we're going to place
the Autowired annotation on the setter method.
So when Spring goes to resolve this
or to inject the dependency, it'll say hey,
I have a method here called setFortuneService.
I need a component that implements
the fortuneService interface.
And if it finds it, then it'll actually inject it
and make it available here for the dependency injection.
Alright, this looks good.
In the next video, we're going to dive
into the clips and write some of the code.