Alright, so let's
go ahead and write some code.
So with our development process the first step
is actually creating the setter methods in our class,
and then the second step is to configure
the dependency injection using that @Autowired Annotation.
Alright, so for this example we're gonna make use of
our tennis coach, the same one we've been working on so far.
We're very familiar with this class now.
Let's go ahead and open up TennisCoach
and expand my window here.
Now in the previous videos online, 11-14,
we actually made use of the @Autowired Annotation
for constructors, but in this video we're actually
going to just comment that out.
We're not gonna use constructor injection here,
we're actually gonna use setter injection.
Now what I want to do is actually
first set up a default constructor.
So a default constructor is simply
a no-argument constructor, just
an open paren, closed paren.
And I want to do this mainly just
so I can keep track of Spring when they
create my objects, and also add a little diagnostic message.
So this is not really required in this example,
but I'm just adding it here just to give us more insight
as far as what Spring's doing in the background.
Alright, so here's my constructor TennisCoach.
And I'll do a simple sys out printline,
and I'll just do, again, a little diagnostic message
saying hey inside default constructor
so when I run the app, I can see that Spring is
actually calling the default constructor.
Again, mainly just for debugging here.
Mainly just for my own benefit and for tracing.
Alright, so that's my basic default constructor right now.
This looks pretty good.
Now for the real stuff.
The step one, so this is actually creating
a setter method in our class for injections.
So it's just a normal setter method
that will define for injecting this FortuneService.
So here I'll call it public void, setFortuneService,
I'll pass on the params here, theFortuneService,
typing it all out longhand and I simply make
an assignment inside so I'll say fortuneService, the field,
equals theFortuneService, which is
the actual parameter being passed into this method.
Again, very simple setter method
just making an assignment for theFortuneService.
And that's it. Looks good so far.
Now the next step, step two is actually
configuring the dependency injection
with @Autowired, so we need to actually tell Spring
hey I want you to autowire this dependency
and we'll autowire it using this setter method.
So basically when Spring sees this @Autowired,
it'll say hey I need to resolve a dependency,
I need to inject a dependency, and they'll look
for any class of implements FortuneService.
And that's how we have that set up.
So instead of doing constructor injection,
we're going to do setter injection.
And we basically put that
@Autowired on the actual method name.
And again on line 19, again, I'm just adding
some diagnostic messages here
just so I can see what's happening with Spring
behind the scenes when our application
actually executes.
So again, just more debugging for myself.
So there we go. We've set our injection.
Put the @Autowired annotation on a setter method.
Alright, so our work's all done here in the TennisCoach.
Let's go back to our main program, AnnotationDemoApp.java.
Again, this is our main program, it goes through,
it reads the Spring config file, you know,
it gets the bean from the container,
call methods on the bean to get the daily workout,
to get the daily fortune and so on.
So no changes over here I'll just kind of keep this as-is.
Clean up an extra white space, but that's basically it.
And what I'll do is I'll go ahead
and actually run the application now.
Just do a right-click, I'll choose Run as, java application.
So it's up and running, and oh yeah,
I see some good stuff out here.
So here is our one message inside the default constructor.
So they're calling that person correctly,
and they're also calling our inside setFortuneService
so that dependency injection for that method
is actually working out just fine.
So that @Autowired is working for us for our setter methods,
and all of our other messages print out just fine:
backhand volley, your lucky day, and so on.
So this is awesome. So we've accomplished the process
of using setter injections with annotations.
And that's by simply adding that @Autowired annotation
to our setter method. So this is great. Congratulations!