All right, so one other thing
I wanna talk to you about is that we can actually
inject our dependencies by calling any method on our class.
So, instead of using setter methods,
we can actually use any method.
All we have to do is simply give the @Autowired
annotation on net method.
This is really cool and let's check it out.
In the code example I have here, for my TennisCoach,
note here at the bottom I have
this method called doSomeCrazyStuff.
Okay, so just any method name that I'm making up,
the only thing here is that I have @Autowired on it.
So, Spring will actually use this for dependency
injection and Autowiring the actual FortuneService.
So again, any method name simply listed as being Autowired.
Really, really cool feature.
Okay, let's dive into Eclipse and let's test
this out real quick.
I'll go ahead and modify my TennisCoach.java.
And instead of using a regular setter method,
I'm gonna use any old method name.
Let me go ahead and scroll down to the area
where I had the setter method before,
and I'm gonna make a small change here.
So, instead of using setFortuneService,
I'm gonna give my own custom method name.
I'll change the method name, so instead of calling it
setFortuneService, I'll call it doSomeCrazyStuff.
Being really silly here.
I'll also update the method name inside
of my little print line statement,
so it'll say inside, doSomeCrazyStuff.
And that's it.
So, as long as its method is listed as being Autowired,
then Spring will use this for dependency of injection
when it needs to resolve a dependency.
All right, so this looks good, so I'll save this file
and I'll move back over to
my main program, AnnotationDemoApp.
This is the same main program that we've had before,
no changes to it.
I'll simply Run this application.
Do a right-click, choose Run As&gt;Java App.
Here's our output.
Oh, this looks kinda good.
So, I'm inside of my default constructor, check.
And inside doSomeCrazyStuff, yeah, I like it!
All right, that's it!
That's it.
(laughs)
So, we had the Autowired method, doSomeCrazyStuff,
and so they're actually using it for dependency injection.
This is great and all of our other messages
print out just fine.
Backhand volley and lucky day.
This is great, so we're successful.
The key takeaway here is that you can use
any method for injection, you simply list
it as being @Autowired.
All right, so we can check the box there.
We've made use of some very fancy techniques here
with annotation dependency injection with Spring.
Buzzwords, buzzwords, buzzwords.