In this video, we're gonna learn
about field injection with annotations and autowiring.
So, we've covered two injection types so far.
We've covered constructor injection
and we've already covered setter injection.
Now, this video will focus on doing field injection.
Now, with field injection, you can actually
inject the dependencies by setting the field values
on your class directly, even for private fields,
and the nice thing about it is
that this happens behind the scenes
using some Java technology called Reflection.
So, the development process for field injection
is that you simply configure the dependency injection
using the Autowired annotation.
You place this annotation directly on the field
and with this annotation,
there's no need for setter methods.
Hmm, interesting.
So, let's take a look at it.
So, step one.
We have our TennisCoach for our FortuneService
we know that we need a fortuneService as a dependency,
so what we do is we simply place Autowired
directly on the field,
directly on the field.
So, instead of making you supply constructor injection
or setter injection, we place it directly on the field.
So, what happens is behind the scenes,
when Spring creates your object,
then they'll automatically set this field behind the scenes,
so they won't have to go through
any setter methods or anything.
They'll just actually set it directly
by making use of Java technology called Reflection,
and they'll set it directly
without you having to do any additional work.