All right, let's go ahead
and dive into Eclipse and write some code.
So with our development process,
what we're gonna do is we're gonna configure
dependency injection with the Autowired annotation
and we're gonna apply it directly to the field,
no need for setter methods.
So, let's go ahead and modify our TennisCoach.java.
In the previous videos we made use of method injection,
so our doCrazyStuff, we're simply
gonna comment out that for now.
We're not gonna use it, we're gonna actually
make use of field injection instead.
So, I just put a comment on this section here.
Go ahead save the file.
Great, so now step one is configure
the dependency injection with the Autowired annotation,
and I want to apply it directly to the field.
So I have this field here called fortuneService
and I say Autowired.
Now, what Spring will do with that,
it will say hey, I need to resolve a dependency.
Even though this field is listed as private,
Spring will still set this value behind the scenes.
So, the first thing Spring will do
is it will actually construct the class
by calling the default constructor
and then it will actually inject
a fortuneService implementation directly into this class
making use of some Java technology called Reflection.
And it happens all behind the scenes for you.
There's no additional work you have to do.
There's no special constructor injection,
no setter injection,
simply make use of this field injection,
which is really, really cool.
And everything else in the file is the same,
so we make use of all of our normal methods.
So, that's it for TennisCoach.
So, we're good to go right now.
All right, so let's go ahead and move back over
to our main program AnnotationDemoApp.
That's the one that we've been using so far.
Actually there's no changes here to this file.
We keep everything the same.
Spring's gonna do some injection work in the background
but everything else here stays the same.
And then we'll go ahead and run the application
and we'll look at our beautiful output, oh yeah.
So here we're inside the default constructor
which is great.
So behind the scenes Spring will actually inject
that FortuneService, so we can print out
our daily workout and then we'll get the actual fortune,
today is your lucky day, we're getting that
from the FortuneService that was wired up by Spring.
And it was wired up by Spring automatically
using that field level injection.
So, this is awesome.
I'm really, really excited about this.
We've covered all the bases here
on doing the different types of injection with Spring.
So, I'd like to say congrats, and you rock dude.