Hey, so I wanna give you a quick video
regarding the different injection types.
So, we covered constructor injection.
We also looked at how to do setter injection
and finally, we discussed field injection.
You may wonder well, which one should I use?
So, I always say, choose a style and stay consistent
within your project, alright.
And, that'll make things easy for you, but also make
it easy for other team members on your project
if it's one consistent approach throughout.
Now, you may wonder, is one injection type better
than the other?
Well, you get the same functionality regardless
of either injection type that you use.
So, constructor, setter, field you get
the same functionality.
So, again, choose one injection type that you
feel comfortable with you like to use
and then make use of that in your application.
So, full disclosure, I'll go ahead and tell you now
that you'll see certain blog posts out there
written by certain Spring fans boys or fan girls
where they will taut a specific injection type
as being superior to all.
Now, this is a very debatable topic.
I always joke, it's kinda like a religious argument.
There's no right or wrong answer,
even in the Spring documentation they state
that with the injection types you pretty much
get the same functionality across the board.
So again, just choose the type that works best
for your team or what your team is more comfortable with
seeing and then simply stay consistent
throughout your project.
Alright, just a quick video.
I know you may have had questions about that
and I wanted to give you just a quick answer
to help you out.
Alright, I'll see you in the next video.