In this video, we're gonna discuss
annotation autowiring and qualifiers.
So far, we've been using autowiring
where Spring was basically scanned for components
and it'll ask, hey does anyone implement a given
FortuneService interface?
But I bet you are probably wondering. (laughs)
What happens if there's multiple implementations out there?
I mean, which one will Spring pick?
Will it pick the first one it finds?
Will it pick the last one?
I mean, what's the strategy?
Basically, what's up with that?
So, if we had multiple FortuneService implementations
like the HappyFortuneService, and then what if we had like
maybe a RandomFortuneService?
We get real fancy with a DatabaseFortuneService.
And then maybe a RESTFortuneService.
Well, I mean, which one?
I mean, there's so many out here.
How will Spring know which one to pick?
Well, if you actually had all those implementations
out there, you'd actually have a problem.
And this is the error message that Spring will give you.
Spring will say, hey, there was an error creating
a bean named tennisCoach.
The injection of the autowired dependencies failed.
And this was caused by NoUniqueBeanDefinitionException.
Ugh, sounds ugly.
So basically, it says that we expected a single match
of the bean, but we found four implementations.
And then Spring will even be nice.
It'll give you a list of all four that it found.
So basically, in order to resolve this,
you need to be able to give Spring a unique bean, all right.
So Spring can't figure it out on it's own
because there's more than one.
So you have to kind of be very specific,
and you have to qualify or tell Spring
which specific bean you want them to use.
So what you'll do is actually make use
of this annotation called Qualifier.
So here, we're gonna be specific.
So in this example for TennisCoach, I'll use @Qualifier,
and then I'll actually give the bean ID
of the bean that I wanted to use.
Now, remember in this example, we're using our @Components,
and we're actually just using the default name
for the component, so the default name will simply be
the class name with the lower case.
So our happyFortuneService class?
Well, the actual bean ID for it
is lower case happyFortuneService.
Right?
And we've covered all this before.
So that's how you use the qualifier.
You simply specify the bean ID of the component
or the bean that you want Spring to inject.
And this'll help resolve that problem
of too many implementations.
All right, so that's the @Qualifier.
You simply be specific, and you give the actual bean name.
Now, you can actually use this @Qualifier annotation
on all your different injection types.
So you can use it for constructor injection.
You can also use it for setter injection
and finally, for field injection.
And you simply apply it just like a normal annotation.
In the following video, we'll dive into Eclipse,
and we'll actually write some code
using this @Qualifier annotation.