Let's go ahead and move into Eclipse
and let's actually build out those Multiple Fortune
Service Implementations.
So we'll create all these other services
like Random, Database, and RESTFortune
and we'll stub them out
and then we'll test it out and see our error message.
So here's our interface FortuneService
and we already have HappyFortuneService.
We've been using that so far in the video series.
Let's go ahead and create another Fortune Service.
So let me right click and say New Class.
And this will actually be the class
for my RandomService.
So I'll just give the name of RandomService.
And then down that interface, I'll click
on the Add button and I'll choose FortuneService.
I'll just type it in the top.
Fortune, and select FortuneService.
That's the interface that we're gonna implement.
Again, we're creating multiple
FortuneService implementations.
Hit Okay, I'll keep all the other defaults here.
And I'll hit Finish.
Okay, so here's our RandomService
and let's go ahead and add the Add Component there,
so spring will handle the component scanning for us.
And just hover over it and fix the import there.
And there we go.
So line three, we should have the import
for Spring component.
Okay, great.
So now this RandomService is set up
for auto scanning with our spring application.
Good job.
Now we're kind of gonna, we're gonna go through
and actually repeat the process for the other
service implementations.
So do right click,
I say New Class.
And for this one, this will be our database
FortuneService and again,
we'll just stub it out.
We're not gonna do any real database stuff now.
We'll just stub it out for now.
Move down to interfaces and I'll click on Add.
And again, I'll choose my FortuneService
there from the list
as far as my interface.
And then I'll hit Okay.
Keep all the other defaults
and hit Finish.
Alright, so there's my DatabaseFortuneService.
I'll go ahead and keep that stub.
Now let's create one more service.
So I'll just do a right click.
I'll say New.
And I'll say Class.
And this will be my RESTFortune Service.
Again, we're just stubbing this out.
Move down to interfaces.
And choose Add.
And again, choose a FortuneService interface.
Hit Okay.
All the other defaults, hit Finish.
Okay, great.
So now I have four FortuneService implementations
right now in my application.
So this kind of matches with the diagram
that we had a little bit earlier.
So good job.
So now let's move back over to our TennisCoach.
Our TennisCoach is set up
for auto wire and they'll auto wire a FortuneService.
For right now, I'm gonna leave it plain vanilla.
I'm not gonna make any changes.
I actually wanna run it and see the error message
first and then we'll actually come back and fix it later.
So let's go ahead and move back over to our main
application, our AnnotationDemoApp.
And we'll keep this app exactly the same.
We won't make any changes here.
It'll simply read the configs, get the container,
and now I'll just simply run this application.
Just a right click and run as a Java app.
And let's expand the console window
and oh, yucky, yucky, yucky.
We see the exception.
The same one we saw from the slides.
Ugh.
Just all this ugly statuary stuff.
So the auto,
the injection of the auto wire failed.
Okay, all this stuff.
All this stuff.
Ugh.
So, cannot auto wire field blah, blah, blah.
Blah, blah, blah.
It's all bad news, right?
(laughs)
So here it said,
Expecting a single matching bean
but found two.
Wait, wait, two?
Happy for rent,
wait, what's up with that?
Two?
We had four.
Ugh.
Now I'm really sad.
Actually, I'm mad.
What's going on?
Let's see, oh!
Duh.
Okay, great.
You see the problem, the mistake I made?
You probably caught this earlier, right?
I forgot to add the @Component annotation.
So Spring wouldn't auto-scan these guys.
So it never saw these guys.
That's why DatabaseFortuneService
was never there.
Ooh, okay.
My mistake.
So that's fixed and I think I made the same mistake
over here.
Yeah.
RESTFortune.
Ugh.
Okay, so need to add @Component.
Ayay-yah.
But I'm glad you caught that.
You probably caught that during the video
and you sat there and you waited for me
to make this mistake.
So good eagle eye on your part
for catching that.
But we went through,
we solved it.
Let's save all those files and now let's go back to our
main app and run it one more time.
So back in our main application.
And right click and run it as.
Alright, so it's running.
We got our console output.
Okay, good.
So all the ugly stuff before,
all the blah, blah, blah,
blah, blah, blah.
But at least we get the error message
we were looking for.
(laughs)
We're actually happy to get this error message down.
It said that single matching bean but found
four.
Okay, good.
Alright, so now we broke it the way I
planned on breaking it.
(laughs)
Okay, good.
Database, happy, random, Rest.
Alright, so basically Spring says,
"Hey, I don't know which one of these beans
"to use.
"Which one of these implementations to use
"because they're all perfect candidates here
"for this auto wiring."
So again, write the solution and be specific.
Alright?
So we need to go back into our Tenniscoach
and we need to use that @Qualifier
and I need to give the actual bean ID
of the bean that I want spring to use.
I'll say, "Hey, I want you to use
"the HappyFortuneService."
And so I use the bean ID
which is the same name as the class,
first letter, lower case
because we're using the default naming image.
Alright, this looks good.
This looks really, really good.
Alright, so let's go ahead and run this now.
Back into our main application,
Annotation Demo App.
And now just right click and run it.
And we're up and running
and booyah!
Back to normal.
Okay?
Practice your back hand volley
and today is your lucky day.
That's the fortune that we get from our
HappyFortuneService.
All those other implementations are stub out
right now.
They simply return null,
but this guy gives us our desired output.
So it's using our HappyFortuneService.
So yay!
Good job.
We resolved it and how do we resolve it?
By being specific with our @Qualifier Annotation.
Yoo-hoo!