All right, so what I'd like to do right now
is actually add code for the Random Fortune Service.
So far in the video series,
we've used the HappyFortuneService and it worked fine,
but it was hard-coded with just one fortune every time
and we'd like to kind of mix it up a little bit.
So let's make use of our Random Fortune Service,
and I actually noticed a mistake from the previous videos
that it's simply called RandomService.
I want to rename it to Random Fortune Service.
So I simply select this class here,
do a right-click and choose Refactor,
and then I choose Rename.
So I'm gonna rename this RandomService
to RandomFortuneService.
Just being a little specific here, being a little bit anal.
I want everything to kind of match up just right.
So I give it that name and I go ahead and hit Finish.
RandomFortuneService.
Okay, great.
So at this point, Eclipse has updated everything
and we have the basic outline here
for this RandomFortuneService.
I'll go ahead and add some comments here
as far as exactly what we need to do during this coding.
So first thing is that we need to create an array of strings
and then down in the get Fortune part of it,
I'll actually pick a random fortune out of that array.
So those are the basic comments to myself,
just to kind of keep me on track,
as far as what I need to do.
And then I'll go ahead and start writing
some of the Java code to make this happen.
All right, so we'll start here
with setting up an array of strings.
And I'll just keep it simple.
I'll just add like three or four strings here,
so it's just an array with comma-delimited strings.
All right, so here are my three fortunes here.
Beware, diligence, and the journey is the reward.
So again, just keeping it simple.
You can get creative and do anything that you'd like here.
Just a basic array of strings.
So this is good for part one, so far, so good job.
Now I need to have some type of random number generator.
Java provides a built-in random number generator
and so it's called class Random.
So I'll call it myRandom equals new Random.
And Random is part of the Java JDK,
so it's in the java.util package.
Simply hover over, do an import on this one.
And up top,
you should see the import for,
on line 3, java.util.Random,
so that's part of the standard Java API,
which is really cool,
and I'll show you how to use it, too.
Now with this fortune service,
they're gonna call getFortune
when they actually wanna give a fortune.
So we're gonna give them a random fortune from our array.
So the first thing we need to do is, first off,
get a random number based on the size of that array.
So I'll call this random number here index
and I'll say, index equals random.nextInt,
and it's gonna be based on the size of the array.
And again, we can always find out the size of the array
by simply saying dot length, so in my case, data.length,
that's, data's the array name, dot length is the attribute
that gives you the size of the array.
And I have a small little typo here.
I should call this, myRandom
because I defined myRandom on line 18.
All right, so basically line 24 gives you a random number
based on the size of the array.
So now I can use that random number
to then index into the array and grab a fortune.
So here I'll say, data sub index.
So then, once I have the fortune, then I return the fortune,
and that's it.
So that's the basic implementation here for getFortune.
We basically get a random string from the array,
using our random number generator, simple and plain.
All right, so this class is pretty much ready to go.
So this is our RandomFortuneService.
So let's go ahead and Save this,
and then we can go back and use it
in our TennisCoach application.
All righty, so moving back over to TennisCoach,
and my qualifier here, instead of using happyFortuneService,
I'm gonna tell TennisCoach to now use
my RandomFortuneService.
So I just write out RandomFortuneService and again,
we're using the actual default naming conventions,
so it's the same name as the class,
first letter is lowercase.
All right, that looks good.
So now Spring is actually gonna inject
the RandomFortuneService here for the TennisCoach.
Hm, I'm getting excited, getting excited.
All right, so moving back over to our main application,
AnnotationDemoApp, again, this app stays the same,
no changes here.
We simply fire this app up by running it.
Say, Run As a Java Application.
And booyah!
I love it, look at that!
Diligence is the mother of good luck.
That's one of our random fortunes, this is great.
So, our TennisCoach was injected
with our RandomFortuneService, and now that looks good.
But let's try it one more time, let's run it one more time.
So I'll hit the green button here on the toolbar
to run it again, and take a look at my console,
and oh yeah!
Beware of the wolf in sheep's clothing.
So we're getting random fortunes.
All right, so when you run it over and over again,
you're gonna get a different fortune every time
because that random number generator
is giving us random items.
All right, I'm excited.
Doesn't take much for me to get excited.
I don't know, random numbers, I don't know.
They just kind of do something for me.
All right, so we're good.
So the key here is that
we created another implementation here
of that fortune service and then we put in
a very simple random number implementation,
and then we injected that by using that at qualifier
into our Tennis Coach, and we ran it, and everything worked.
This is fun, I love it.
All right, good job and congratulations.