In this video, we're gonna learn about
Spring MVC form validation.
So what's the need for validation?
Well, you may have a form, and you may wanna validate
the fields to make sure you have required fields.
You also may wanna validate numbers in a given range.
You may wanna validate the format, for example,
for a postal code.
Or you may wanna add your own custom business rule
for validation.
So we can make use of Java's standard Bean Validation API.
This API's defined in JSR-303 and 309.
And it defines a meta model and API for entity validation.
So this Bean Validation API is available for server-side
applications and also client-side applications using
like JavaFX or Swing.
This is all defined at this one website here,
beanvalidation.org.
It has all the documentation along with sample code.
Now let's talk about Spring support for validation.
So Spring version four and higher supports
the Bean Validation API, which is a good thing.
So it's actually the preferred method for validation
when building Spring apps.
You simply add the Validation JARs to our project,
use the appropriate annotations, and you're ready to go.
So the Bean Validation features, you can check to see
if a field is required, you can validate a length,
you can validate numbers, validate with regular expressions,
custom validation, and so on.
All right, so let's take a look at some validation
annotations, and these are all fairly self-explanatory,
but I'll go through them.
@NotNull makes sure that the given value is not null.
@Min and @Max, those basically apply to a number
to make sure it falls within a given range.
You also have @Size to make sure that the value
matches a given size as far as the number of characters
or the number of digits.
You can also apply regular expression patterns
using @Pattern.
And then you have @Future and @Past.
These apply to dates, so the date must be in the future,
or it must be in the past.
And there are also some others.
All right, so let's go ahead and take a look
at our road map here as far as what we're gonna do.
First thing we're gonna do is set up our
development environment, then we'll write code
to check for a required field.
Next we'll validate a number range with min and max.
Next we'll move forward and we'll apply regular expressions.
And then we'll do custom validation, this is kind of like
the big grand finale.
We'll actually create our own custom validation rule
along with our own custom Java annotation.
Really great stuff, so stay tuned.
We'll walk through each of these step by step
in the following videos.
So I'll see you there in the next video, yo, yo.