In this video, we're gonna learn
how to set up our development environment
for Spring MVC form validation.
Now we've already discussed the Java standard
Bean Validation API, but the important thing here
is to know that this is only a specification.
It's vendor independent, it's portable.
However, we still need an implementation.
We need something that implements the spec.
So this is where Hibernate comes in the play.
Hibernate to the rescue!
So Hibernate originally started as an ORM project,
or object to relational mapping project.
However, in recent years, they've expanded
into other areas.
So now they have a fully compliant
JSR-303/309 implementation.
So they have an implementation of the validation framework,
which is really, really cool.
And also it's not tied to the ORM or database work.
It's actually a separate project just for doing validation.
So here's the actual website,
hibernate.org/validator.
Again, it's its own separate project for doing validation,
and it's fully compliant with the Java Beans
Validation API, so they implement the spec
to the T, and it works out really, really nice.
Here's the actual development process.
Basically what you'll do is you'll download
the Validation JAR files from the Hibernate website,
and then you'll add those JAR files to your project.
So in the following videos, we'll actually go through this
step by step, and I'll show you how to get your project
set up to make use of Spring MVC form validation
with the Hibernate Validation JAR files.