All right, so let's go ahead and move
into our development environment here
and let's kind of get things set up.
So what I'll do is I'll actually open up a web browser
and I'll go ahead and download the hibernate validation
jar files.
So I go to hibernate.org and this is the main website.
Now I'll make use of the validation framework
that's over on the far right side.
So just move over there and click on the blue button
there for more.
So now we're at the Hibernate validation website here.
I'll go ahead and click on the green button
to start the download process.
Depending on your internet speed this can happen
very fast or it can happen very slow.
But eventually you'll get the actual zipfile
downloaded to your computer.
Now let me swing over to my file system here.
I'll go look at my downloads directory and I have a file
here called hibernate-validator.zip.
I'll go ahead and double click this file to unzip it.
Okay great so now it's unzipped and has a lot
of good things in here.
I'll go ahead and expand my folder here.
So I have a dist directory and it has jar files
and also a supporting lib directory.
This looks really good so far.
What I want to do is kind of swing back over to eclipse,
get that window back up because I want to add
some of these jar files to my eclipse project.
I'll kind of resize the windows here so I can see them
both at the same time.
I'll go ahead and highlight the first three
hibernate-validator files here.
Then I'll copy those.
Then I'll move over to eclipse and I'll paste those
into my Web-INF lib directory, right?
That's where we place all of our third-party jar files.
All right great, so I've added those.
Now there are some additional files that are required.
So under lib, slash, required go ahead and select
all of the files in lib, slash, required.
Select those items.
Then I'll move back over to eclipse and my WEB-INF
directory and I'll paste those files.
So there we go, we've added those hibernate-validation files
to our projects.
All of those jar files that are in there now,
so we're good to go.
In the following videos we'll actually start coding
with these and applying the validation rules accordingly.
But at least at this point we're all set up
and we are ready to go, yo yo.