In this video, we're gonna learn about
Spring MVC form validation for required fields.
So what we'll do is we'll have this example.
We'll have this form for a customer where we can ask
for the customer's first name and last name.
And what we'll do is we'll make last name required.
So if they hit the submit with simply an empty form,
then we'll give them an error message saying,
hey, last name is required.
I'll show you how to code all this together in this video.
We'll pull it all together looking
at the really big picture here.
So we'll have our customer form, the user enters their data.
They hit submit, pass over a customer
object to our customer controller.
In the customer controller,
we'll actually perform the validation.
If the validation is successful,
we'll send them to the confirmation page.
If the validation fails, we'll actually send them back
to the customer form for them to fix
up the form and resubmit again.
All right, so let's look at
the development process step by step.
So the first thing we're going to do is add
the validation rule to the customer class,
then we'll display the error message on the HTML form.
Next, we'll perform validation in the controller class.
And then finally, we'll update our confirmation page.
All right, a lot of good stuff.
Let's go ahead and dive in.
So the first step is adding the validation
rule to the customer class.
So remember in our example, we want to add a validation
rule to the last name field to make it required.
So what I'll do is I'll make use of these
two annotations here: @Null and @Size.
So for @Null, I give the error message is required
that'll be displayed if the value is null.
Also, I have @Size min equals one,
meaning that I need to have a minimum of one character here
to make sure that this value is not empty.
That's basically the process there.
So I'm checking @Null, @Size on the given last name.
So those are the validation rules that
I've just added to this customer class.
And note for first name, nothing's there because
we're not adding any rules to the first name field.
OK, so moving ahead to step three,
displaying the error messages on the HTML form.
All right, so here's our customer-form.jsp.
Down in the section where we list the last name,
we have the normal work here,
form:input path of last name.
But then I add this new entry here
just to display the error message.
So I say form:errors.
All right, a new entry.
Form:errors path of last name.
That maps to the last name field,
or error messages for the last name field.
Then I also apply a CSS class.
The actual name of that class is error.
I'll show you the coding for the CSS in the next video,
but for now just assume that there's
a CSS class definer there called error.
That's basically what we do here.
So we just give form:errors and that'll display the error
message for that last name field if that's the case.
All right, so now getting down to
the nitty gritty here, step three.
This is where we actually perform
the validation in the controller class.
All right, so here's our method here
for this request mapping of process form.
Now, two new items that'll appear here
in this process form as far as parameters.
So we have this one new attribute called @Valid.
So basically, you're saying perform
validation rules on this customer object.
Also, the results of that validation test
will be placed in BindingResult.
So BindingResult will be the result
of the actual validation rule.
So behind the scenes when Spring calls its method,
Spring will perform the validation rules
using that hibernate validator API,
and then the results will be placed
in this object BindingResult.
In your code, you can check the value of the BindingResult.
So I can say if theBindingResult.hasErrors,
then we're gonna return them back to the customer form.
Else, that means there were no errors
and we'll simply send them to the confirmation page.
All right, so the basic approach here,
you simply check the BindingResult.
If there are errors, you send them back to the form,
else, you send them over to the confirmation page
or whatever your success page is for your application.
So the key item here, two new entries, @Valid
is an annotation and BindingResult
that'll hold the actual results of the validation test.
And that's basically it.
And then finally, step four.
Very simple, we just update our confirmation page.
We say, hey, the customer's confirmed,
and we yield the customer's first name
and the customer's last name.
So nothing really big here.
Just simple Spring MVC coding.
All right, that's it.
So in the next video, we'll actually dive in.
We'll get into Eclipse.
We'll actually start writing some code
and we'll see how all this works out real time
while we're going through the development effort.
Alrighty, so I'll see you in the next video.