All right.
So let's go ahead and dive in here.
Just a quick review of our development process.
So the first thing that we wanna do in this video
is add the validation rule to our customer class.
Moving into Eclipse, first thing I need to do
is write the code for the Customer class,
'cause I don't have a Customer class yet.
So let's go ahead and create this new class.
So I'll just do a right click.
I'll say New, Class.
And the name that I'll give for the class is Customer
I'll keep all the other defaults, and then I'll hit Finish.
Excellent.
So we have this empty class right now.
I'll expand my window here.
Now, this is gonna be really simple.
We're simply gonna have two fields,
first name and last name.
And I also wanna add
some getter and setter methods here for these properties.
So I'll simply just do a right click,
and I'll say Source, Generate Getters and Setters.
And you've seen all this before, right?
You're accustomed to all of my tips, tricks, and techniques.
All right.
Zoom in here.
We'll go ahead and select both of those
for firstName and lastName
Or if you wanted to get really fancy,
you could hit the Select All button
in the top right, but it's up to you.
Anyways, we're here and we hit the OK button.
All right. Great.
So there's the code that Eclipse just generated for us,
the getters and setters for firstName and lastName
All right.
So now for the real work here,
that's actually adding the validation rules.
So we're gonna add a validation rule for lastName
So we're gonna say @NotNull
and then we give the actual message for this error.
And I actually misspoke in my previous video.
I called it @Null, but it's really @NotNull
But you already knew that, right?
And then we'll also give the annotation here
for @Size(min=1)
So those are the validation rules
that we'll have here for this field.
I'll go through and just fix the imports for @NotNull
And I'll also fix the import for @Size
And then I'll just scroll up to the top
and just make sure that my imports are correct.
So make sure you have
the javax.validation.constraints.NotNull and Size.
So this looks pretty good so far,
so we have the basic validation rules added
to this Customer class.