All righty, so let's do a check point
on our development process.
We've already covered step one of adding
the validation rule to our customer class.
Now we'll move to step two,
displaying the error message on the HTML form.
All righty, so moving into Eclipse,
we actually need to create the HTML form.
So let's go ahead and move down
to our WEB-INF view directory.
We're gonna create a new file.
And the actual name of the file,
we'll call it customer-form.jsp.
And once you're happy with that,
go ahead and click on the finish button.
All righty, so here's our empty file right now.
Let's go ahead and expand the window here for a second.
And the first thing I wanna do is add
the reference for the spring form tag library.
So make sure you enter your information
the same way I have it here on this screen.
So you may wanna pause the video,
type in exactly as I have it here.
And now I'll go through and start
just putting up my basic HTML page.
So I'll do HTML head, and then body.
I'll go ahead and add a title here for this page,
and I'll call it Customer Registration Form.
Real fancy, oooh.
And here's a little screenshot to the right
as far as what I want the form to look like,
basically the first name and last name.
So I'll go ahead and lay out the basic HTML
form here using the spring form tags.
So I'll have form action equals process form
and then the model attribute will be customer,
and that's the same customer class that
we just created in the previous video.
And one other thing I wanna do is I wanna stretch out here,
give myself some, give myself some white space.
I love white space.
So, kind of just moving things around a bit,
and now let's go ahead and lay out the fields
here for first name and also for last name.
These are the input fields that the user
will see on the HTML form.
So I have form colon input,
then I'll set path equals first name,
and I'll keep it simple for that one.
I'll add some line breaks here after this entry.
And I'll do a similar thing here for the last name field.
So form input, path equals last name.
Now, the only thing that's different here is that
I'm actually gonna add a field to display the errors.
So in the event that there is an error message
I wanna display it here.
So I'll say form colon errors path last name,
and then I give a reference to a CSS class.
But basically here on line 18 where I'm saying hey,
display an error message if an error message has been set.
Now the first time we show the form
we won't see any error messages.
You'll only see that if validation
fails after a form submission.
So a good segue here for this next item.
We actually need to add our submit button,
to submit the data.
So I'll set up input type equals submit
and value equals submit.
Value's the actual label that'll
show up on the submit button.
All righty, so just kind of stepping back for a second.
This looks pretty good.
So this is my basic HTML form for reading the users,
I'm sorry, for reading the customer's first name
and last name along with the submit button.
All right, and I'll just do some little cosmetic stuff here.
I'll put an asterisk here to let the user know
that it's required, and I'll also just add this text
up at the top on the form, just so the user can read that.
Now this is mainly just cosmetic stuff.
I could use any type of symbol
to say that a field is required.
This is simply for display purposes only.
The real validation part happens
because of the validation rules that we have set up
in our customer class that we did in the previous video.
All right, so just adding my little
cosmetic labels here at the top.
Make sure I could spell asterisk properly.
(laughing)
It's such a weird word to actually write out and try
and spell it yourself, but I think I got it right.
If not, please correct me.
I'll just put it in italics.
All right, so that looks pretty good.
Looks pretty good.
All right so the main thing here was adding
that form errors, and we have the CSS style.
Remember I said I'll cover that later,
and this is where we're covering it right now.
So, I'm referencing a CSS style called error.
So that means in my GSP page I need to either define
that style or I could import it.
Right now I'm just gonna keep it simple.
I'll just define the CSS style in line,
but you could also create this
on a separate file for pulling that in.
But now I'll just keep it simple.
So I'll say .error color red,
and again, this is really simple.
I'm, I'm not a CSS guru.
I know the very basics of CSS.
But this will give us the result of displaying the color,
displaying the text in the red.
So that's my style.
Let me kind of clean up, tighten up the screen
here a little bit, just so we can get
everything on one page, and there we go.
So here we go.
We have our style up top, error,
and then we reference that CSS class on line 24.
So that's kind of how things map up,
and that will apply the appropriate red font
for the error message if an error message is there.
Now you may wonder well, where is the is required?
Where, where does that text come from?
Well remember in our class customer that we created
in the previous video when we set up our validation rule,
we had at not null, and then here we actually
listed the message of is required.
So if the validation fails for that field,
then that's the error message that will
be displayed on the actual screen.
So that's how those two things
kind of map together and tie up.
All right, so that kind of pulls it all together for us.
Okay, good stuff, good stuff.
All right, so I'll see you in the next video
as we continue with our development process.