All right, so we're making good progress
with our development process here.
We've already covered step one,
of adding the validation rule to Customer class.
And we also finished with step two,
of displaying the error message on the HTML form.
Now we actually need to move to step three,
and that's performing the validation
in the Controller class.
Now what I actually need to do,
is I actually need to create the Controller class.
Because I don't have it yet.
So I need to move on to my source directory.
And to our package here, and I'll create a new class.
And the name that I'll give for this class
is customer controller.
I'll keep all the other defaults here.
And I'll hit finish.
All righty, so let me go ahead and, kind of,
expand the window here.
For this customer controller, I'm gonna set up
a request mapping, up top for this controller.
And this is work that we've all seen before.
We already know how to do all of this stuff.
Let me go ahead and fix the imports, real quick.
Okay, great, so the basics are set up for right now.
What I'd like to do is actually set up a request mapping,
just to show the actual form.
And also to add the model attribute for the form.
So I'll define this method here.
Show form, that takes the model.
And inside of this method here,
I basically, just wanna add a model attribute here.
So I'll say, the model dot add attribute.
I'll give the name comma value pair
for that model attribute.
From our form, we know that the model attribute
name is customer.
And then we simply give it a new customer object.
Just a blank customer object.
Just to start out with.
For the actual form data binding.
And then I go, return on customer form
I'll actually return it back to customer form dot jsp.
Based on our configuration.
Oh yeah, one more thing
I forgot up here.
I actually need to put in request mapping
the actual path to show this form.
So I'll say, show form.
And that's basically it here for this first method here.
Our request mapping for actually showing the form.
And we've seen this work before
of simply adding an attribute for the model attribute.
Giving it a new customer object.
All right, this looks good so far.
So now, I actually wanna move to my
main menu dot jsp and set up a link
for the customer form.
Just so we can access it,
directly from our main menu.
So we don't have to do any manual pecking
on the URL location bar.
So let me just do a little copy paste here.
I'll just copy this section here for student form.
Then I'll just paste it real quick.
Then I'll simply just do an update here.
So I'll call it, customer form.
And for the link.
I'll make use of the href customer slash show form.
All righty, so this looks pretty good here.
Well now what I want to do is actually
test this out to make sure that we can
actually show the customer form.
All right, so let's go over to our
application here and let's run it.
Just do a right click, say run as
and run on server.
And here's our main menu, our home page.
And we have a new link here, customer form.
It looks really good.
Let's try it out.
And all right, good job.
So here's our form.
Kind of like the stuff we put in the previous video.
It's there but we don't really have
any processing code yet.
We haven't really done that part of it yet.
So if I hit the submit button,
Whahhhh!
404, but we know about that, right?
We don't have the mapping yet, for process form.
We'll actually add that in the next video.
So we still have some work to do.
So I'll see you in the next video.