Well, we know that we're doing a validation
in a controller class, but we still have
some work to do, right?
So we still need to add that processForm RequestMapping
to kind of get rid of that 404 error that we've encountered
in the previous video.
So we'll take care of that now.
So let's go ahead and move into our customer controller.
And let's kind of stretch out here,
give myself some white space.
I love white space.
And I'm gonna add this processForm RequestMapping.
So I'll set up my RequestMapping, slash processForm.
And I'll go ahead and write the method for it here.
ProcessForm, and right now I'm not gonna put any arguments
or params in there, I'm just gonna keep it simple
for right now.
And I'll just do the open curly brace, close curly.
And I'll simply return the actual confirmation page.
So I'll return customer-confirmation, quotes, semi.
So that's kind of the basic layout.
I just wanted to kind of stud this method out.
We have the basics in place right now
for our request map.
So this looks good so far.
Now I'm happy with this.
Alright, well now it's time to kind of get down
and dirty and do some real validation.
'Cause we haven't really done that yet,
so this is where we start writing the code,
so I'm gonna tell Spring to validate the Customer object
that's being passed in.
And I do that by making use of at Valid annotation.
So at Valid, at ModelAttribute, customer.
Then I have a customer, space, the customer.
So this is the whole data binding that we saw earlier,
In previous videos.
The only new thing here is the at Valid, at the moment.
And then also we know, based on previous slides,
that spring will actually store the results
of the validation in this BindingResult object.
And we can kind of query that result object
to get more details on it.
That's kind of the basic layout here
for the validation.
Let me go ahead and fix some of the inputs here,
for at Valid, ModelAttribute, and also fix the
import for BindingResult.
Alright, so again, just pointing out here.
At Valid performs the validation rules
on the Customer object, and then BindingResult,
Spring will place the results in the BindingResult.
And all this happens behind the scenes
with some Spring magic.
Ooh, I like it.
Alrighty, now at this point, I basically wanna check
the binding result and see if it has errors.
If it has errors, I wanna return the user
back to the actual form.
Else, if everything went fine, I wanna send 'em
to the confirmation page, so that's just what
the coding here does.
So, again, if the BindingResult has errors,
we're gonna return customer-form, so we're gonna
send 'em back to the form.
Else will return customer-confirmation,
meaning that's our success page.
And that's kind of the basic coding object
that you'll have here for validation
using Spring MVC.
So kind of stepping back, again,
just kind of highlight everything and so
our process form, we have those parameters coming in
for at Valid, and BindingResult happens behind the scenes.
And then we simply check the BindingResult.
If it fails, send 'em to the form,
if everything's successful, we send 'em to the
confimation page.
So this looks really, really good so far.