All right, so we're making
really good progress here.
We've covered the first three steps.
Our last step here is updating the confirmation page.
Or in fact, we actually have to create
the confirmation page so we can send them
to our success page.
And we'll do that here in this video.
So I'm just going to move over to my View folder
here on the WEB-INF view.
And I'll create a new file for customer confirmation.
For the file name, I'll give it customer-confirmation.jsp.
And once you're happy with that,
go ahead and click on the finish button.
All right, so here we go.
Let me go and maximize my screen for a second.
I'm gonna add in the taglib reference.
We're not using it immediately yet,
but we will use it in some later videos,
so I'll just go ahead and put it in now for safe keepings.
Again, you can pause the video and type it in exactly
like I have it here.
And let's go ahead and set up some work here
for our HTML page.
So I'll set up HTML, set my head,
and also kinda spell out the body here for a second.
Drop in a quick title here for "Customer Confirmation."
This is my success page, yeah.
And this confirmation page is gonna be really simple.
All I'm doing is I'm simply echoing
the customer's first name and the customer's last name.
And I'm making use of the JSP expression language
to display the information for the first and last name.
And we've all seen this before,
so this is nothing new here right now.
But I have to at least create the page
just so with our validation we're actually sending it
to a confirmation page that has been created.
So that's kinda why we're going through this process.
Fun, fun, fun.
Now, let's go ahead and let's run the application
because we've covered all four steps here
of our validation process here.
So let's go ahead and run it.
So right-click "Run As," and choose "Run On Server."
And here's our main menu.
Let's go ahead and click the link here for "Customer form."
And let's just test it real quick,
let's just go ahead and hit submit
without providing any data.
And, okay, not what I was expecting.
What the what?
Okay, this is fun.
So I think I know what happened.
So let me go and dig back into the source code
and try to identify what happened.
So let's move back over to our customer.java class.
Ah, I see the problem in customer.java.
I didn't follow my own slides.
So in the slides I actually have the message
for the size, but I didn't have it there.
So I'm just getting the default error message.
So here I'm going to give my own custom message,
of message="is required".
That's what I should really have here.
Now, note for @NotNull I kind of left that empty,
I'm not matching my slides exactly.
But I will come back to that later.
So let's just cover one thing at a time here.
So let me refresh the form.
And then do a submit, and great.
So now I'm getting the "is required" as desired.
So that is working and I'm getting
the proper error message for that.
So let me go ahead and enter some data here
for a Bob Smith, and then go ahead and hit submit.
And ooh, good, so that passes.
So our validation logic is working.
If there were errors, it sent me back to the form.
If everything was okay,
then it sent us the confirmation page.
So that's good, we're making some good steps here.
But there are some other things I'm gonna show you
in some of the following videos,
so don't go anywhere, stay tuned.