Well, we have our validation up and running
and I wanna do some experiments here.
And I'll try and break it.
I wanna try and find some edge cases that'll mess it up.
Alright, so the one thing I wanna do, though,
before I get into that part is I wanna add
some logging messages or some debug messages here
to my controller.
And I actually just wanna print out the last name
that's coming in for the customer,
just so I can see it at the console and I don't know,
just do some quick diagnostics for it.
So I'll print out the last name for debugging.
So I'll just move down into my customer controller
and I'll keep it very simple here.
I'll just do a system.out.println.
And I'll just print out last name.
I'll actually put a vertical bar here,
right before the end quote
and then I'll print out theCustomer.getLastName
and then I'll append another vertical bar,
just so I can see if there's any white spaces
or any funny business going on here.
So that'll just give me a visual representation
of what's actually being passed in
for the customer's last name.
A little coding trick that I use
or that I've learned from over the years.
So it's debugging output, 'cause it's really hard
to figure out if you really have any leading
or trailing white space.
Alright, so we have that in place
and we're good to go with that.
Now let's go ahead and run it.
And we'll see how this works out to my customer form.
And now I'll just hit Submit.
I won't enter any data, just hit Submit
and see what I get on the console.
So we kinda pull up a window here at the bottom.
And last name, so two vertical bars,
nothing in the middle, that's fine.
Okay, so it says is required.
Let me go ahead and enter a value there for last name
and hit Submit.
Okay, that looks good, too, last name Smith.
That's cool, happy with that.
Now, let's break the system.
Let's simply enter whitespace.
Really, just whitespace and hit submit.
What, that passed?
Whitespace passes the validation rules
and look at the bottom.
It's just whitespace, how?
How does whitespace pass validation?
We have @NotNull, we have @size.
So this is a common problem that new developers encounter
when they use Spring MVC validation.
It's not intuitive, it doesn't really make sense.
But don't worry, I'm gonna give you a solution for this.
And it's a proven technique.
It's a best practice that's using a Spring industry.
And it makes you some advanced features
and we see how it'll all play together.
And I'll cover that in the next set of videos.
So I have a solution, so stay tuned for next videos,
and we'll get it all worked out.