In this video we're going to learn
about Spring MVC Validation along
with the @InitBinder annotation.
So you remember we had a problem with white space
in our previous example.
If our last name field was added with all white space
it passed, yikes.
And it shouldn't, it should have failed.
So what we need to do is actually trim the white space
from the input fields to make sure that the white space
doesn't pass.
So what we'll do is we'll make use of this annotation
called @InitBinder.
This annotation works as a pre-processor.
So what it will do for every web request that comes
through our controller this code will execute first.
So what we'll do is we'll actually create a method
and we'll annotate it with the @Binder annotation.
So all requests coming in are pre-processed.
Now this is actually an advanced annotation.
Not many Spring developers know about it
so you're kind of getting the inside scoop.
You're getting some good advanced coverage here
of the Spring MVC framework.
Ooh, good stuff.
All right so what are we going to do in our InitBinder?
All right, remember it's going to pre-process
so we're going to use it to trim our strings.
We're going to remove the leading and trailing white space
from our strings.
Also if the string only has white space then we're going
to trim it all the way down to a no object.
This will actually resolve our validation problem.
Ah, sigh of relief because I was really upset
about white spaces passing.
So this will actually give us a solution to that issue.
All righty, so let's look at some code here.
So what we're going to do is actually register
a custom editor in our controller.
We do that by making use of this @InitBinder.
Remember @InitBinder will basically pre-process
all web requests coming into our controller.
So here's the method signature, public void initBinder.
Has a parameter coming in called WebDataBinder.
I'll talk about that in a second.
What I'll do on the next line here is I'll actually
create this StringTrimmerEditor.
This is actually a class that's defined
in the Spring API.
Its purpose is to trim strings.
So it will basically trim or remove the leading white space
and also the trailing white space.
Also in the constructor I have the value of true.
That means that it will actually trim the string
down to null if it's entirely all white space.
All right, so it will trim it down to null.
So that's the StringTrimmerEditor.
Once I have this object created then I'll use
that dataBinder and I'll register this as a custom editor.
So what I'm doing here is I'm saying for every string class,
apply the StringTrimmerEditor.
So in a nutshell what this does is it will pre-process
every string as far as its form data.
It will remove the leading and trailing white space.
And again if the string only had white space
it will trim it down to null.
This is basically what this method will do.
I'll take a quick pause and just a recap.
So @InitBinder will pre-process every web request
coming in and the coding here will handle the special work
that we added for trimming strings.
All righty, so a lot of good stuff here.
Don't let it overwhelm you.
This is all advanced Spring information.
But what we'll do is we'll actually use this
in the next video.
So we'll move into clips, we'll actually write this code.
We'll add it to our controller and we'll make sure
that this solves our problem of having white space
for validations.
All right, so hold tight, I'll see ya in the next video.