So let's go ahead and move and see the clips.
We're going to go ahead and add support for Init Binder
and also that String Trimmer Editor.
Alright, so let's go ahead and move
into our customer controller class, expand the window here,
and let's go ahead and first off I'm just going to add
some comments here, just to kind of keep myself on track
just so I know what I'm doing here (laughs).
So basically, what I want to do is add Init Binder
to convert or trim the input strings.
I want to remove the leading or trailing white space
and also resolve this issue for our validation.
Alright, so I'm going to make use
of this at InitBinder annotation
that we've discussed in the previous set of slides
and then I'll simply give a method.
The method signature will always have Web Data Binder
being passed in.
And I'll just set up my curly braces, open and closed.
And now I'll do the similar thing as what I had
in the slides earlier, so I'll create this new
String Trimmer Editor, remember,
it's part of the new spring API.
I pass in the constructor value of true,
meaning that if it's all white space, trim it down to null.
And then what I'll do is I'll basically register
this custom editor on the data binder,
I'll say for the string class,
then make use of this string trimmer editor
that I just created.
And, uh, let me just kinda go through here
and fix my imports here for Init Binder
and a similar thing here for Web Data Binder
that's also from the spring API.
And finally String Trimmer Editor from the spring API.
Alrighty, that looks good and oh, have a little typo here.
Oh, yeah, I got it. Have to fix the variable name.
It's data binder coming in as a param,
I need it to say data binder here on line 27.
Alrighty, got that taken care of,
and let's see, register, customer, ah,
this should be register custom editor,
not customer but custom, so I'll fix this little typo.
I'm thinking about too many customers here.
Alright, so register custom editor.
Alright, take care of that, and we're good.
Alright, so that takes care of all of the errors
that I had here on the actual code, good job.
Alright, so again, just kinda stepping back here.
So this is our Init Binder, this method will be called
for every web request coming into our controller
and then we simply use this to trim the strings,
the leading and trailing space
and help us resolve that issue.
Alright, so let's go ahead and test this out.
Let's go ahead and do a run as and do run on server.
And then we'll bring it, we'll go to our customer form
again, we'll try and break it, we'll enter all white space
here for the name, so enter all white spaces and hit submit.
And, hm, it's working but that's not the error message
that I was expecting.
Here it says "may not be null," I was actually expecting
the one using the words "is required."
Hm, we're almost there,
let's think about this for one second.
Oh yeah, that's right, okay, remember my customer dot java
I said I was going to come back to if there was something
that I didn't really follow totally?
That's the at null.
Remember that from the previous videos?
So we actually need to give a message here.
Message is required, 'cuz what we saw on the screen
previously, that was the, on the form output,
that was the default message and here I'm giving my own
custom message of "is required."
So save that, my server did a reload on that
application of that context, now if I go back to this form
again, and just do a refresh on it,
and again let's try to break it by entering all white space.
Then, oh yeah, so this is great,
so we're getting our desired error message,
and also note here in the bottom, last name of null
it's trimming it all to null, so validation is working.
As desired.
All right, let's try one more thing.
Let's go ahead and enter a name and let's add a whole lot
of white space to the end and see if it actually trims it.
So I'll do a submit, and nice, now all that extra
white space has been trimmed from the end of that last name.
So this is great, so our string trimmer editor
is working as desired
and I'm really, really happy that it helped us to resolve
that crazy issue so I'd like to say congratulations
and good job!